{"version": 1.1, "data": [{"title": "ropes", "paragraphs": [{"background": "Another obvious change that occurs during puberty is rapid growth. This is called the adolescent growth spurt . In boys, it is controlled by testosterone. The rate of growth usually starts to increase relatively early in puberty. At its peak rate, growth in height is about 10 centimeters (almost 4 inches) per year in the average male. Growth generally remains rapid for several years. Growth and development of muscles occur toward the end of the growth spurt in height. Muscles may continue to develop and gain strength after growth in height is finished.", "situation": "Jim and Bob were brothers. Their mom had just bought them both new cloths at the beginning of the school year. This had always last both brothers for the school year but Jim needed new clothes again. He had grown several inches. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is older?", "id": "3440976510", "answers": [{"text": "Jim"}]}]}, {"background": "Another obvious change that occurs during puberty is rapid growth. This is called the adolescent growth spurt . In boys, it is controlled by testosterone. The rate of growth usually starts to increase relatively early in puberty. At its peak rate, growth in height is about 10 centimeters (almost 4 inches) per year in the average male. Growth generally remains rapid for several years. Growth and development of muscles occur toward the end of the growth spurt in height. Muscles may continue to develop and gain strength after growth in height is finished.", "situation": "Jim and Bob were brothers. Their mom had just bought them both new cloths at the beginning of the school year. This had always last both brothers for the school year but Jim needed new clothes again. He had grown several inches. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is younger?", "id": "344269681", "answers": [{"text": "Bob"}]}]}, {"background": "Another obvious change that occurs during puberty is rapid growth. This is called the adolescent growth spurt . In boys, it is controlled by testosterone. The rate of growth usually starts to increase relatively early in puberty. At its peak rate, growth in height is about 10 centimeters (almost 4 inches) per year in the average male. Growth generally remains rapid for several years. Growth and development of muscles occur toward the end of the growth spurt in height. Muscles may continue to develop and gain strength after growth in height is finished.", "situation": "Jim and Bob were brothers. Their mom had just bought them both new cloths at the beginning of the school year. This had always last both brothers for the school year but Jim needed new clothes again. He had grown several inches. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is going through puberty?", "id": "713828552", "answers": [{"text": "Jim"}]}]}, {"background": "Another obvious change that occurs during puberty is rapid growth. This is called the adolescent growth spurt . In boys, it is controlled by testosterone. The rate of growth usually starts to increase relatively early in puberty. At its peak rate, growth in height is about 10 centimeters (almost 4 inches) per year in the average male. Growth generally remains rapid for several years. Growth and development of muscles occur toward the end of the growth spurt in height. Muscles may continue to develop and gain strength after growth in height is finished.", "situation": "Jim and Bob were brothers. Their mom had just bought them both new cloths at the beginning of the school year. This had always last both brothers for the school year but Jim needed new clothes again. He had grown several inches. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is not going through puberty?", "id": "3472042553", "answers": [{"text": "Bob"}]}]}, {"background": "Another obvious change that occurs during puberty is rapid growth. This is called the adolescent growth spurt . In boys, it is controlled by testosterone. The rate of growth usually starts to increase relatively early in puberty. At its peak rate, growth in height is about 10 centimeters (almost 4 inches) per year in the average male. Growth generally remains rapid for several years. Growth and development of muscles occur toward the end of the growth spurt in height. Muscles may continue to develop and gain strength after growth in height is finished.", "situation": "Jim and Bob were brothers. Their mom had just bought them both new cloths at the beginning of the school year. This had always last both brothers for the school year but Jim needed new clothes again. He had grown several inches. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who has a lower testosterone level?", "id": "610020089", "answers": [{"text": "Bob"}]}]}, {"background": "Another obvious change that occurs during puberty is rapid growth. This is called the adolescent growth spurt . In boys, it is controlled by testosterone. The rate of growth usually starts to increase relatively early in puberty. At its peak rate, growth in height is about 10 centimeters (almost 4 inches) per year in the average male. Growth generally remains rapid for several years. Growth and development of muscles occur toward the end of the growth spurt in height. Muscles may continue to develop and gain strength after growth in height is finished.", "situation": "Jim and Bob were brothers. Their mom had just bought them both new cloths at the beginning of the school year. This had always last both brothers for the school year but Jim needed new clothes again. He had grown several inches. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who has a higher testosterone level?", "id": "1301424967", "answers": [{"text": "Jim"}]}]}, {"background": "In deep water, particles of water just move in circles. They don\u2019t actually move closer to shore with the energy of the waves. However, near the shore where the water is shallow, the waves behave differently. Look at the Figure below . You can see how the waves start to drag on the bottom in shallow water. This creates friction that slows down the bottoms of the waves, while the tops of the waves keep moving at the same speed. The difference in speed causes the waves to get steeper until they topple over and break. The crashing waves carry water onto the shore as surf.", "situation": "Bob had seen the ocean before but only from the shore. He had always associated the ocean with waves moving towards him. Now he was on a boat for the first time he was awed by how still the water appeared to be. His friend told him that the water moved in circles here.", "qas": [{"question": "Was Bob in deep or shallow water?", "id": "1979268300", "answers": [{"text": "deep"}]}]}, {"background": "In deep water, particles of water just move in circles. They don\u2019t actually move closer to shore with the energy of the waves. However, near the shore where the water is shallow, the waves behave differently. Look at the Figure below . You can see how the waves start to drag on the bottom in shallow water. This creates friction that slows down the bottoms of the waves, while the tops of the waves keep moving at the same speed. The difference in speed causes the waves to get steeper until they topple over and break. The crashing waves carry water onto the shore as surf.", "situation": "Bob had seen the ocean before but only from the shore. He had always associated the ocean with waves moving towards him. Now he was on a boat for the first time he was awed by how still the water appeared to be. His friend told him that the water moved in circles here.", "qas": [{"question": "What will start to drag as they move basck towards the shore??", "id": "224675748", "answers": [{"text": "waves"}]}]}, {"background": "In deep water, particles of water just move in circles. They don\u2019t actually move closer to shore with the energy of the waves. However, near the shore where the water is shallow, the waves behave differently. Look at the Figure below . You can see how the waves start to drag on the bottom in shallow water. This creates friction that slows down the bottoms of the waves, while the tops of the waves keep moving at the same speed. The difference in speed causes the waves to get steeper until they topple over and break. The crashing waves carry water onto the shore as surf.", "situation": "Bob had seen the ocean before but only from the shore. He had always associated the ocean with waves moving towards him. Now he was on a boat for the first time he was awed by how still the water appeared to be. His friend told him that the water moved in circles here.", "qas": [{"question": "Do waves get steeper or morre shallow before they break?", "id": "1767327166", "answers": [{"text": "steeper"}]}]}, {"background": "In deep water, particles of water just move in circles. They don\u2019t actually move closer to shore with the energy of the waves. However, near the shore where the water is shallow, the waves behave differently. Look at the Figure below . You can see how the waves start to drag on the bottom in shallow water. This creates friction that slows down the bottoms of the waves, while the tops of the waves keep moving at the same speed. The difference in speed causes the waves to get steeper until they topple over and break. The crashing waves carry water onto the shore as surf.", "situation": "Bob had seen the ocean before but only from the shore. He had always associated the ocean with waves moving towards him. Now he was on a boat for the first time he was awed by how still the water appeared to be. His friend told him that the water moved in circles here.", "qas": [{"question": "What do waves carry onto the shore?", "id": "4255464939", "answers": [{"text": "water"}]}]}, {"background": "Sometimes muscles and tendons get injured when a person starts doing an activity before they have warmed up properly. A warm up is a slow increase in the intensity of a physical activity that prepares muscles for an activity. Warming up increases the blood flow to the muscles and increases the heart rate. Warmed-up muscles and tendons are less likely to get injured. For example, before running or playing soccer, a person might jog slowly to warm muscles and increase their heart rate. Even elite athletes need to warm up ( Figure below ).", "situation": "Jim and Mark both raced in the track event today. Jim got to the field early so he could stretch and do some light jogging before the race. Mark was running late and did not have time to warm up. Besides he reasoned it was best to save his energy for the actual race.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is more likely to get injured?", "id": "1833119851", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Sometimes muscles and tendons get injured when a person starts doing an activity before they have warmed up properly. A warm up is a slow increase in the intensity of a physical activity that prepares muscles for an activity. Warming up increases the blood flow to the muscles and increases the heart rate. Warmed-up muscles and tendons are less likely to get injured. For example, before running or playing soccer, a person might jog slowly to warm muscles and increase their heart rate. Even elite athletes need to warm up ( Figure below ).", "situation": "Jim and Mark both raced in the track event today. Jim got to the field early so he could stretch and do some light jogging before the race. Mark was running late and did not have time to warm up. Besides he reasoned it was best to save his energy for the actual race.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is less likely to get injured?", "id": "1837969519", "answers": [{"text": "Jim"}]}]}, {"background": "Sometimes muscles and tendons get injured when a person starts doing an activity before they have warmed up properly. A warm up is a slow increase in the intensity of a physical activity that prepares muscles for an activity. Warming up increases the blood flow to the muscles and increases the heart rate. Warmed-up muscles and tendons are less likely to get injured. For example, before running or playing soccer, a person might jog slowly to warm muscles and increase their heart rate. Even elite athletes need to warm up ( Figure below ).", "situation": "Jim and Mark both raced in the track event today. Jim got to the field early so he could stretch and do some light jogging before the race. Mark was running late and did not have time to warm up. Besides he reasoned it was best to save his energy for the actual race.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's heart rate was highest at the begining of the race?", "id": "594163801", "answers": [{"text": "Jim"}]}]}, {"background": "Sometimes muscles and tendons get injured when a person starts doing an activity before they have warmed up properly. A warm up is a slow increase in the intensity of a physical activity that prepares muscles for an activity. Warming up increases the blood flow to the muscles and increases the heart rate. Warmed-up muscles and tendons are less likely to get injured. For example, before running or playing soccer, a person might jog slowly to warm muscles and increase their heart rate. Even elite athletes need to warm up ( Figure below ).", "situation": "Jim and Mark both raced in the track event today. Jim got to the field early so he could stretch and do some light jogging before the race. Mark was running late and did not have time to warm up. Besides he reasoned it was best to save his energy for the actual race.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's heart rate was lowest at the begining of the race?", "id": "3971954699", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Sometimes muscles and tendons get injured when a person starts doing an activity before they have warmed up properly. A warm up is a slow increase in the intensity of a physical activity that prepares muscles for an activity. Warming up increases the blood flow to the muscles and increases the heart rate. Warmed-up muscles and tendons are less likely to get injured. For example, before running or playing soccer, a person might jog slowly to warm muscles and increase their heart rate. Even elite athletes need to warm up ( Figure below ).", "situation": "Jim and Mark both raced in the track event today. Jim got to the field early so he could stretch and do some light jogging before the race. Mark was running late and did not have time to warm up. Besides he reasoned it was best to save his energy for the actual race.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's muscles are getting the most blood at the begining of the race?", "id": "4059708636", "answers": [{"text": "Jim"}]}]}, {"background": "Sometimes muscles and tendons get injured when a person starts doing an activity before they have warmed up properly. A warm up is a slow increase in the intensity of a physical activity that prepares muscles for an activity. Warming up increases the blood flow to the muscles and increases the heart rate. Warmed-up muscles and tendons are less likely to get injured. For example, before running or playing soccer, a person might jog slowly to warm muscles and increase their heart rate. Even elite athletes need to warm up ( Figure below ).", "situation": "Jim and Mark both raced in the track event today. Jim got to the field early so he could stretch and do some light jogging before the race. Mark was running late and did not have time to warm up. Besides he reasoned it was best to save his energy for the actual race.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's muscles are getting the least blood at the begining of the race?", "id": "779959602", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Sometimes muscles and tendons get injured when a person starts doing an activity before they have warmed up properly. A warm up is a slow increase in the intensity of a physical activity that prepares muscles for an activity. Warming up increases the blood flow to the muscles and increases the heart rate. Warmed-up muscles and tendons are less likely to get injured. For example, before running or playing soccer, a person might jog slowly to warm muscles and increase their heart rate. Even elite athletes need to warm up ( Figure below ).", "situation": "John liked to run 5 miles each day. Before he starts running he makes sure he stretches and does jumping jacks to warm up.", "qas": [{"question": "Is John preventing or causing injury by warming up?", "id": "3825730574", "answers": [{"text": "preventing"}]}]}, {"background": "Sometimes muscles and tendons get injured when a person starts doing an activity before they have warmed up properly. A warm up is a slow increase in the intensity of a physical activity that prepares muscles for an activity. Warming up increases the blood flow to the muscles and increases the heart rate. Warmed-up muscles and tendons are less likely to get injured. For example, before running or playing soccer, a person might jog slowly to warm muscles and increase their heart rate. Even elite athletes need to warm up ( Figure below ).", "situation": "John liked to run 5 miles each day. Before he starts running he makes sure he stretches and does jumping jacks to warm up.", "qas": [{"question": "Is John increasing or decreasing his heart rate by warming up?", "id": "490342333", "answers": [{"text": "increasing"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Jane and his friends Sue and Jim decided to have a picnic. Sue was sneezing and her eyes were itching but her friends were fine and enjoyed their meal. As they were packing up a bee stung Jim and his throat started to swell and he was having trouble breathing.", "qas": [{"question": "Who was having an allergic reaction ", "id": "2715363240", "answers": [{"text": "Sue and Jim"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Jane and his friends Sue and Jim decided to have a picnic. Sue was sneezing and her eyes were itching but her friends were fine and enjoyed their meal. As they were packing up a bee stung Jim and his throat started to swell and he was having trouble breathing.", "qas": [{"question": "Who was not having an allergic reaction?", "id": "1132472632", "answers": [{"text": "Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Jane and his friends Sue and Jim decided to have a picnic. Sue was sneezing and her eyes were itching but her friends were fine and enjoyed their meal. As they were packing up a bee stung Jim and his throat started to swell and he was having trouble breathing.", "qas": [{"question": "Who would benefit from an antihistamine?", "id": "1264593297", "answers": [{"text": "Sue"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Jane and his friends Sue and Jim decided to have a picnic. Sue was sneezing and her eyes were itching but her friends were fine and enjoyed their meal. As they were packing up a bee stung Jim and his throat started to swell and he was having trouble breathing.", "qas": [{"question": "Who would benefit from epinephrine?", "id": "2180655051", "answers": [{"text": "Jim"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Ann's class was going on a picnic. The teacher had made sure all the other children new not to bring anything that had nut in it because If Beth even touch nuts she would start to swell and her throat would close so that she could not breath. But at least she could play outside and run through the grass without sneezing and coughing like her friend Ann.", "qas": [{"question": "Who has allergies?", "id": "107300798", "answers": [{"text": "Beth and Ann"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Ann's class was going on a picnic. The teacher had made sure all the other children new not to bring anything that had nut in it because If Beth even touch nuts she would start to swell and her throat would close so that she could not breath. But at least she could play outside and run through the grass without sneezing and coughing like her friend Ann.", "qas": [{"question": "Who probably uses antihistamines?", "id": "1875987942", "answers": [{"text": "Ann"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Ann's class was going on a picnic. The teacher had made sure all the other children new not to bring anything that had nut in it because If Beth even touch nuts she would start to swell and her throat would close so that she could not breath. But at least she could play outside and run through the grass without sneezing and coughing like her friend Ann.", "qas": [{"question": "Who probably uses epinephrine?", "id": "2260683932", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Ann's class was going on a picnic. The teacher had made sure all the other children new not to bring anything that had nut in it because If Beth even touch nuts she would start to swell and her throat would close so that she could not breath. But at least she could play outside and run through the grass without sneezing and coughing like her friend Ann.", "qas": [{"question": "Who has more severe allergies?", "id": "2135903291", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Ann's class was going on a picnic. The teacher had made sure all the other children new not to bring anything that had nut in it because If Beth even touch nuts she would start to swell and her throat would close so that she could not breath. But at least she could play outside and run through the grass without sneezing and coughing like her friend Ann.", "qas": [{"question": "Who has less severe allergies?", "id": "2139442239", "answers": [{"text": "Ann"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Ann's class was going on a picnic. The teacher had made sure all the other children new not to bring anything that had nut in it because If Beth even touch nuts she would start to swell and her throat would close so that she could not breath. But at least she could play outside and run through the grass without sneezing and coughing like her friend Ann.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose immune system is responding to things in the air?", "id": "2055296395", "answers": [{"text": "Ann"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Ann's class was going on a picnic. The teacher had made sure all the other children new not to bring anything that had nut in it because If Beth even touch nuts she would start to swell and her throat would close so that she could not breath. But at least she could play outside and run through the grass without sneezing and coughing like her friend Ann.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose immune system is responding to things in food?", "id": "2065388694", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Ann's class was going on a picnic. The teacher had made sure all the other children new not to bring anything that had nut in it because If Beth even touch nuts she would start to swell and her throat would close so that she could not breath. But at least she could play outside and run through the grass without sneezing and coughing like her friend Ann.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose immune system causing a life threatening response?", "id": "3488503397", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Ann's class was going on a picnic. The teacher had made sure all the other children new not to bring anything that had nut in it because If Beth even touch nuts she would start to swell and her throat would close so that she could not breath. But at least she could play outside and run through the grass without sneezing and coughing like her friend Ann.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose symptoms can be treated?", "id": "2269596752", "answers": [{"text": "Beth and Ann's"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Mark where hiking. Mike was not having a good time. The pollen count was very high today and his eyes and throat were itching and he couldn't stop sneezing. When they sat down to rest Beth felt a sting on her arm and saw a be fly away. Her throat started to close and she was struggling to breath. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who had allergies?", "id": "2738172217", "answers": [{"text": "Beth and Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Mark where hiking. Mike was not having a good time. The pollen count was very high today and his eyes and throat were itching and he couldn't stop sneezing. When they sat down to rest Beth felt a sting on her arm and saw a be fly away. Her throat started to close and she was struggling to breath. ", "qas": [{"question": "Whose allergies were more severe?", "id": "3131389716", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Mark where hiking. Mike was not having a good time. The pollen count was very high today and his eyes and throat were itching and he couldn't stop sneezing. When they sat down to rest Beth felt a sting on her arm and saw a be fly away. Her throat started to close and she was struggling to breath. ", "qas": [{"question": "Whose allergies were less severe?", "id": "3132307224", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Mark where hiking. Mike was not having a good time. The pollen count was very high today and his eyes and throat were itching and he couldn't stop sneezing. When they sat down to rest Beth felt a sting on her arm and saw a be fly away. Her throat started to close and she was struggling to breath. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who would be helped by an antihistamine?", "id": "940325200", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Mark where hiking. Mike was not having a good time. The pollen count was very high today and his eyes and throat were itching and he couldn't stop sneezing. When they sat down to rest Beth felt a sting on her arm and saw a be fly away. Her throat started to close and she was struggling to breath. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who would be helped by epinephrine?", "id": "535508874", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Mark where hiking. Mike was not having a good time. The pollen count was very high today and his eyes and throat were itching and he couldn't stop sneezing. When they sat down to rest Beth felt a sting on her arm and saw a be fly away. Her throat started to close and she was struggling to breath. ", "qas": [{"question": "Whose allergies are life threatening?", "id": "2561357973", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Jane were enjoying the outdoors. But the pollen levels were high today and so Jane's eyes were itching and she was sneezing  a lot. Beth was about to suggest they go inside and get Jane an antihistamine when she felt a sharp sting on her arm as she saw a bee fly away. Suddenly she felt her throat swelling and she could not breath, Beth reached in her pocket for her epinephrine.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is having an allergic reaction?", "id": "1011307880", "answers": [{"text": "Beth and Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Jane were enjoying the outdoors. But the pollen levels were high today and so Jane's eyes were itching and she was sneezing  a lot. Beth was about to suggest they go inside and get Jane an antihistamine when she felt a sharp sting on her arm as she saw a bee fly away. Suddenly she felt her throat swelling and she could not breath, Beth reached in her pocket for her epinephrine.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is having an less severe allergic reaction?", "id": "1500928489", "answers": [{"text": "Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Jane were enjoying the outdoors. But the pollen levels were high today and so Jane's eyes were itching and she was sneezing  a lot. Beth was about to suggest they go inside and get Jane an antihistamine when she felt a sharp sting on her arm as she saw a bee fly away. Suddenly she felt her throat swelling and she could not breath, Beth reached in her pocket for her epinephrine.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is having an more severe allergic reaction?", "id": "1495292389", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Jane were enjoying the outdoors. But the pollen levels were high today and so Jane's eyes were itching and she was sneezing  a lot. Beth was about to suggest they go inside and get Jane an antihistamine when she felt a sharp sting on her arm as she saw a bee fly away. Suddenly she felt her throat swelling and she could not breath, Beth reached in her pocket for her epinephrine.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose Janes immune system or the pollen causing her symptoms??", "id": "3638714305", "answers": [{"text": "immune system"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Jane were enjoying the outdoors. But the pollen levels were high today and so Jane's eyes were itching and she was sneezing  a lot. Beth was about to suggest they go inside and get Jane an antihistamine when she felt a sharp sting on her arm as she saw a bee fly away. Suddenly she felt her throat swelling and she could not breath, Beth reached in her pocket for her epinephrine.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose Beth's immune system or the bee causing her symptoms??", "id": "162815631", "answers": [{"text": "immune system"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Jane were enjoying the outdoors. But the pollen levels were high today and so Jane's eyes were itching and she was sneezing  a lot. Beth was about to suggest they go inside and get Jane an antihistamine when she felt a sharp sting on her arm as she saw a bee fly away. Suddenly she felt her throat swelling and she could not breath, Beth reached in her pocket for her epinephrine.", "qas": [{"question": "What is Jane allergic to?", "id": "4125315438", "answers": [{"text": "pollen"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Jane were enjoying the outdoors. But the pollen levels were high today and so Jane's eyes were itching and she was sneezing  a lot. Beth was about to suggest they go inside and get Jane an antihistamine when she felt a sharp sting on her arm as she saw a bee fly away. Suddenly she felt her throat swelling and she could not breath, Beth reached in her pocket for her epinephrine.", "qas": [{"question": "What is Beth allergic to?", "id": "4129247603", "answers": [{"text": "bee"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Jane were enjoying the outdoors. But the pollen levels were high today and so Jane's eyes were itching and she was sneezing  a lot. Beth was about to suggest they go inside and get Jane an antihistamine when she felt a sharp sting on her arm as she saw a bee fly away. Suddenly she felt her throat swelling and she could not breath, Beth reached in her pocket for her epinephrine.", "qas": [{"question": "Will an antihistamine make Jane better or worse?", "id": "3145685570", "answers": [{"text": "better"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Jane were enjoying the outdoors. But the pollen levels were high today and so Jane's eyes were itching and she was sneezing  a lot. Beth was about to suggest they go inside and get Jane an antihistamine when she felt a sharp sting on her arm as she saw a bee fly away. Suddenly she felt her throat swelling and she could not breath, Beth reached in her pocket for her epinephrine.", "qas": [{"question": "Will epinephrane make Beth better or worse?", "id": "4269299833", "answers": [{"text": "better"}]}]}, {"background": "Allergy symptoms can range from mild to severe. Mild symptoms might include itchy eyes, sneezing, and a runny nose. Severe symptoms can cause difficulty breathing, which may be life threatening. Keep in mind that it is the immune system and not the allergen that causes the allergy symptoms. Allergy symptoms can be treated with medications such as antihistamines. Severe allergic reactions may require an injection of the hormone epinephrine. These treatments lessen or counter the immune system\u2019s response.", "situation": "Beth and Jane were enjoying the outdoors. But the pollen levels were high today and so Jane's eyes were itching and she was sneezing  a lot. Beth was about to suggest they go inside and get Jane an antihistamine when she felt a sharp sting on her arm as she saw a bee fly away. Suddenly she felt her throat swelling and she could not breath, Beth reached in her pocket for her epinephrine.", "qas": [{"question": "Does Jane need epinephrine or anihistamines?", "id": "1320179972", "answers": [{"text": "anihistamines"}]}]}, {"background": "Some fungi take on different shapes, depending on their environmental conditions. These fungi are called dimorphic fungi, because they have \u201ctwo forms.\u201d For example, the fungus Histoplasma capsulatum , which causes the disease histoplasmosis, is thermally dimorphic; it has two forms that are dependent on temperature. In temperatures of about 25\u00b0C, it grows as a brownish mycelium, and looks like a mass of threads. At body temperature (37\u00b0C in humans), it grows as single, round yeast cells.", "situation": "Mark had two samples of the same fungus, Histoplasma capsulatum. One sample had been grown at 25 degrees Celsius and the other at 37 degrees Celsius.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the two samples look the same or different?", "id": "1719402074", "answers": [{"text": "different"}]}]}, {"background": "Some fungi take on different shapes, depending on their environmental conditions. These fungi are called dimorphic fungi, because they have \u201ctwo forms.\u201d For example, the fungus Histoplasma capsulatum , which causes the disease histoplasmosis, is thermally dimorphic; it has two forms that are dependent on temperature. In temperatures of about 25\u00b0C, it grows as a brownish mycelium, and looks like a mass of threads. At body temperature (37\u00b0C in humans), it grows as single, round yeast cells.", "situation": "Mark had two samples of the same fungus, Histoplasma capsulatum. One sample had been grown at 25 degrees Celsius and the other at 37 degrees Celsius.", "qas": [{"question": "What made the two samples grow diffrently the location they were grown in or the temperature.", "id": "3378319343", "answers": [{"text": "the temperature"}]}]}, {"background": "Some fungi take on different shapes, depending on their environmental conditions. These fungi are called dimorphic fungi, because they have \u201ctwo forms.\u201d For example, the fungus Histoplasma capsulatum , which causes the disease histoplasmosis, is thermally dimorphic; it has two forms that are dependent on temperature. In temperatures of about 25\u00b0C, it grows as a brownish mycelium, and looks like a mass of threads. At body temperature (37\u00b0C in humans), it grows as single, round yeast cells.", "situation": "Mark had two samples of the same fungus, Histoplasma capsulatum. One sample had been grown at 25 degrees Celsius and the other at 37 degrees Celsius.", "qas": [{"question": "What temperature was sample that looks like threads grown at?", "id": "2468545478", "answers": [{"text": "25 degrees"}]}]}, {"background": "Some fungi take on different shapes, depending on their environmental conditions. These fungi are called dimorphic fungi, because they have \u201ctwo forms.\u201d For example, the fungus Histoplasma capsulatum , which causes the disease histoplasmosis, is thermally dimorphic; it has two forms that are dependent on temperature. In temperatures of about 25\u00b0C, it grows as a brownish mycelium, and looks like a mass of threads. At body temperature (37\u00b0C in humans), it grows as single, round yeast cells.", "situation": "Mark had two samples of the same fungus, Histoplasma capsulatum. One sample had been grown at 25 degrees Celsius and the other at 37 degrees Celsius.", "qas": [{"question": "What temperature was sample that looks like single round yeast cell grown at?", "id": "251070995", "answers": [{"text": "37 degrees"}]}]}, {"background": "Some fungi take on different shapes, depending on their environmental conditions. These fungi are called dimorphic fungi, because they have \u201ctwo forms.\u201d For example, the fungus Histoplasma capsulatum , which causes the disease histoplasmosis, is thermally dimorphic; it has two forms that are dependent on temperature. In temperatures of about 25\u00b0C, it grows as a brownish mycelium, and looks like a mass of threads. At body temperature (37\u00b0C in humans), it grows as single, round yeast cells.", "situation": "Mark had two samples of the same fungus, Histoplasma capsulatum. One sample had been grown at 25 degrees Celsius and the other at 37 degrees Celsius.", "qas": [{"question": "What had different shapes?", "id": "3643930337", "answers": [{"text": "samples"}]}]}, {"background": "The Coriolis effect describes how Earth\u2019s rotation steers winds and surface ocean currents. Unlike land, air and water move freely (in the absence of obstacles). The Coriolis effect causes the path of a freely moving object to appear to curve. This is because Earth is rotating beneath the object. So even though the object's path is straight, it appears to curve. The curve appears to be to the right in the Northern Hemisphere. It appears to be to the left in the Southern Hemisphere.", "situation": "Mark liked photography and spent his spare time taking pictures of his home town and the surrounding areas. Mark was hoping to get some nice areal images to add to his collection . He attached a camera to a weather balloon and released it above his small New England town. Mark watched as the balloon floated higher and began to drift away.", "qas": [{"question": "Did Mark see the balloon traveling on a straight or curved path?", "id": "3920708047", "answers": [{"text": "curved"}]}]}, {"background": "The Coriolis effect describes how Earth\u2019s rotation steers winds and surface ocean currents. Unlike land, air and water move freely (in the absence of obstacles). The Coriolis effect causes the path of a freely moving object to appear to curve. This is because Earth is rotating beneath the object. So even though the object's path is straight, it appears to curve. The curve appears to be to the right in the Northern Hemisphere. It appears to be to the left in the Southern Hemisphere.", "situation": "Mark liked photography and spent his spare time taking pictures of his home town and the surrounding areas. Mark was hoping to get some nice areal images to add to his collection . He attached a camera to a weather balloon and released it above his small town. Mark watched as the balloon floated higher and began to drift away.", "qas": [{"question": "If the balloons path appeared to curve right was Mark in the Northern or Southern Hemisphere?", "id": "2891270276", "answers": [{"text": "Northern"}]}]}, {"background": "The Coriolis effect describes how Earth\u2019s rotation steers winds and surface ocean currents. Unlike land, air and water move freely (in the absence of obstacles). The Coriolis effect causes the path of a freely moving object to appear to curve. This is because Earth is rotating beneath the object. So even though the object's path is straight, it appears to curve. The curve appears to be to the right in the Northern Hemisphere. It appears to be to the left in the Southern Hemisphere.", "situation": "Mark liked photography and spent his spare time taking pictures of his home town and the surrounding areas. Mark was hoping to get some nice areal images to add to his collection . He attached a camera to a weather balloon and released it above his small town. Mark watched as the balloon floated higher and began to drift away.", "qas": [{"question": "If the balloons path appeared to curve left was Mark in the Northern or Southern Hemisphere?", "id": "1601456145", "answers": [{"text": "Southern"}]}]}, {"background": "When humans dig up and use fossil fuels, we have an impact on the carbon cycle ( Figure below ). This carbon is not recycled until it is used by humans. The burning of fossil fuels releases more carbon dioxide into the atmosphere than is used by photosynthesis. So, there is more carbon dioxide entering the atmosphere than is coming out of it. Carbon dioxide is known as a greenhouse gas , since it lets in light energy but does not let heat escape, much like the panes of a greenhouse. The increase of greenhouse gasses in the atmosphere is contributing to a global rise in Earth\u2019s temperature, known as global warming or global climate change.", "situation": "Jane parked her car in the sun but did not cover her widows. Her neighbor John parked his car in the sun but he covered his windows with a sun screen.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's car is hotter inside?", "id": "605039054", "answers": [{"text": "Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "When humans dig up and use fossil fuels, we have an impact on the carbon cycle ( Figure below ). This carbon is not recycled until it is used by humans. The burning of fossil fuels releases more carbon dioxide into the atmosphere than is used by photosynthesis. So, there is more carbon dioxide entering the atmosphere than is coming out of it. Carbon dioxide is known as a greenhouse gas , since it lets in light energy but does not let heat escape, much like the panes of a greenhouse. The increase of greenhouse gasses in the atmosphere is contributing to a global rise in Earth\u2019s temperature, known as global warming or global climate change.", "situation": "Jane parked her car in the sun but did not cover her widows. Her neighbor John parked his car in the sun but he covered his windows with a sun screen.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's car is cooler inside?", "id": "590752188", "answers": [{"text": "John"}]}]}, {"background": "When humans dig up and use fossil fuels, we have an impact on the carbon cycle ( Figure below ). This carbon is not recycled until it is used by humans. The burning of fossil fuels releases more carbon dioxide into the atmosphere than is used by photosynthesis. So, there is more carbon dioxide entering the atmosphere than is coming out of it. Carbon dioxide is known as a greenhouse gas , since it lets in light energy but does not let heat escape, much like the panes of a greenhouse. The increase of greenhouse gasses in the atmosphere is contributing to a global rise in Earth\u2019s temperature, known as global warming or global climate change.", "situation": "Jane parked her car in the sun but did not cover her widows. Her neighbor John parked his car in the sun but he covered his windows with a sun screen.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's car is trapping more heat?", "id": "4209912726", "answers": [{"text": "Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "When humans dig up and use fossil fuels, we have an impact on the carbon cycle ( Figure below ). This carbon is not recycled until it is used by humans. The burning of fossil fuels releases more carbon dioxide into the atmosphere than is used by photosynthesis. So, there is more carbon dioxide entering the atmosphere than is coming out of it. Carbon dioxide is known as a greenhouse gas , since it lets in light energy but does not let heat escape, much like the panes of a greenhouse. The increase of greenhouse gasses in the atmosphere is contributing to a global rise in Earth\u2019s temperature, known as global warming or global climate change.", "situation": "Jane parked her car in the sun but did not cover her widows. Her neighbor John parked his car in the sun but he covered his windows with a sun screen.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's car is trapping less heat?", "id": "4210305946", "answers": [{"text": "John"}]}]}, {"background": "When humans dig up and use fossil fuels, we have an impact on the carbon cycle ( Figure below ). This carbon is not recycled until it is used by humans. The burning of fossil fuels releases more carbon dioxide into the atmosphere than is used by photosynthesis. So, there is more carbon dioxide entering the atmosphere than is coming out of it. Carbon dioxide is known as a greenhouse gas , since it lets in light energy but does not let heat escape, much like the panes of a greenhouse. The increase of greenhouse gasses in the atmosphere is contributing to a global rise in Earth\u2019s temperature, known as global warming or global climate change.", "situation": "Jane parked her car in the sun but did not cover her widows. Her neighbor John parked his car in the sun but he covered his windows with a sun screen.", "qas": [{"question": "who's car is more dangerouse to sit in?", "id": "966471206", "answers": [{"text": "Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "When humans dig up and use fossil fuels, we have an impact on the carbon cycle ( Figure below ). This carbon is not recycled until it is used by humans. The burning of fossil fuels releases more carbon dioxide into the atmosphere than is used by photosynthesis. So, there is more carbon dioxide entering the atmosphere than is coming out of it. Carbon dioxide is known as a greenhouse gas , since it lets in light energy but does not let heat escape, much like the panes of a greenhouse. The increase of greenhouse gasses in the atmosphere is contributing to a global rise in Earth\u2019s temperature, known as global warming or global climate change.", "situation": "Jane parked her car in the sun but did not cover her widows. Her neighbor John parked his car in the sun but he covered his windows with a sun screen.", "qas": [{"question": "who's car is less dangerouse to sit in?", "id": "971058730", "answers": [{"text": "John"}]}]}, {"background": "You don\u2019t have to suffer through an infection to gain immunity to some diseases. Immunity can also come about by vaccination. Vaccination is the process of exposing a person to pathogens on purpose so the person will develop immunity to them. In vaccination, the pathogens are usually injected under the skin. Only part of the pathogens are injected, or else weakened or dead pathogens are used. This causes an immune response without causing the disease. Diseases you are likely to have been vaccinated against include measles, mumps, and chicken pox.", "situation": "Jane took her young son Ethan to the doctors for a check-up. While they were there her son got vaccines for measles and mumps. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Ethan more or less likely to get measles?", "id": "3095595343", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "You don\u2019t have to suffer through an infection to gain immunity to some diseases. Immunity can also come about by vaccination. Vaccination is the process of exposing a person to pathogens on purpose so the person will develop immunity to them. In vaccination, the pathogens are usually injected under the skin. Only part of the pathogens are injected, or else weakened or dead pathogens are used. This causes an immune response without causing the disease. Diseases you are likely to have been vaccinated against include measles, mumps, and chicken pox.", "situation": "Jane took her young son Ethan to the doctors for a check-up. While they were there her son got vaccines for measles and mumps. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Ethan be immune or not to measles?", "id": "2543781817", "answers": [{"text": "immune"}]}]}, {"background": "A prism, like the one in the Figure below , can be used to separate visible light into its different colors. A prism is a pyramid-shaped object made of transparent matter, usually clear glass or plastic. Matter that is transparent allows light to pass through it. A prism transmits light but slows it down. When light passes from air to the glass of the prism, the change in speed causes the light to change direction and bend. Different wavelengths of light bend at different angles. This makes the beam of light separate into light of different wavelengths. What we see is a rainbow of colors. For an animated version of the prism below, go to this URL: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Light_dispersion_conceptual_waves.gif", "situation": "Marks science teacher gave each student something that looked like a thick pyramid of glass he called a prism. He asked them to hold it up to the light and look through it. He wanted them to look at the light in the air and as it passed through the prism. When Mark did he saw several different colored beams of light. ", "qas": [{"question": "When was the light moving faster?", "id": "3473048854", "answers": [{"text": "in the air"}]}]}, {"background": "A prism, like the one in the Figure below , can be used to separate visible light into its different colors. A prism is a pyramid-shaped object made of transparent matter, usually clear glass or plastic. Matter that is transparent allows light to pass through it. A prism transmits light but slows it down. When light passes from air to the glass of the prism, the change in speed causes the light to change direction and bend. Different wavelengths of light bend at different angles. This makes the beam of light separate into light of different wavelengths. What we see is a rainbow of colors. For an animated version of the prism below, go to this URL: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Light_dispersion_conceptual_waves.gif", "situation": "Marks science teacher gave each student something that looked like a thick pyramid of glass he called a prism. He asked them to hold it up to the light and look through it. He wanted them to look at the light in the air and as it passed through the prism. When Mark did he saw several different colored beams of light. ", "qas": [{"question": "When was the light moving slower?", "id": "3482813741", "answers": [{"text": "as it passed through the prism"}]}]}, {"background": "A prism, like the one in the Figure below , can be used to separate visible light into its different colors. A prism is a pyramid-shaped object made of transparent matter, usually clear glass or plastic. Matter that is transparent allows light to pass through it. A prism transmits light but slows it down. When light passes from air to the glass of the prism, the change in speed causes the light to change direction and bend. Different wavelengths of light bend at different angles. This makes the beam of light separate into light of different wavelengths. What we see is a rainbow of colors. For an animated version of the prism below, go to this URL: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Light_dispersion_conceptual_waves.gif", "situation": "Marks science teacher gave each student something that looked like a thick pyramid of glass he called a prism. He asked them to hold it up to the light and look through it. He wanted them to look at the light in the air and as it passed through the prism. When Mark did he saw several different colored beams of light. ", "qas": [{"question": "Did the light stay straight or bend as it went through the prism?", "id": "656969874", "answers": [{"text": "bend"}]}]}, {"background": "A prism, like the one in the Figure below , can be used to separate visible light into its different colors. A prism is a pyramid-shaped object made of transparent matter, usually clear glass or plastic. Matter that is transparent allows light to pass through it. A prism transmits light but slows it down. When light passes from air to the glass of the prism, the change in speed causes the light to change direction and bend. Different wavelengths of light bend at different angles. This makes the beam of light separate into light of different wavelengths. What we see is a rainbow of colors. For an animated version of the prism below, go to this URL: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Light_dispersion_conceptual_waves.gif", "situation": "Marks science teacher gave each student something that looked like a thick pyramid of glass he called a prism. He asked them to hold it up to the light and look through it. He wanted them to look at the light in the air and as it passed through the prism. When Mark did he saw several different colored beams of light. ", "qas": [{"question": "Was the light all bending at the same or different angles?", "id": "859475405", "answers": [{"text": "different"}]}]}, {"background": "A prism, like the one in the Figure below , can be used to separate visible light into its different colors. A prism is a pyramid-shaped object made of transparent matter, usually clear glass or plastic. Matter that is transparent allows light to pass through it. A prism transmits light but slows it down. When light passes from air to the glass of the prism, the change in speed causes the light to change direction and bend. Different wavelengths of light bend at different angles. This makes the beam of light separate into light of different wavelengths. What we see is a rainbow of colors. For an animated version of the prism below, go to this URL: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Light_dispersion_conceptual_waves.gif", "situation": "Marks science teacher gave each student something that looked like a thick pyramid of glass he called a prism. He asked them to hold it up to the light and look through it. He wanted them to look at the light in the air and as it passed through the prism. When Mark did he saw several different colored beams of light. ", "qas": [{"question": "Was the colored light all one wavelength or different?", "id": "217353439", "answers": [{"text": "different"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solution has a higher concentration of hydronium ions than pure water, it has a pH lower than 7. A solution with a pH lower than 7 is called an acid . As the hydronium ion concentration increases, the pH value decreases. Therefore, the more acidic a solution is, the lower its pH value is. Did you ever taste vinegar? Like other acids, it tastes sour. Stronger acids can be harmful to organisms. For example, stomach acid would eat through the stomach if it were not lined with a layer of mucus. Strong acids can also damage materials, even hard materials such as glass.", "situation": "Beth preferred to use natural cleaners. She had been using vinegar alone and mixed with water to clean her home for year and really liked the results. She was careful to were gloves when using it because if she had cuts on her hands it would burn and she also knew she should keep it away from her eyes. When she moved to her knew home however she was surprised to find that the vinegar was damaging her granite counter tops. She noticed that it was causing pitting in the granite.", "qas": [{"question": "What has a higher pH water or lemon?", "id": "1675986798", "answers": [{"text": "water"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solution has a higher concentration of hydronium ions than pure water, it has a pH lower than 7. A solution with a pH lower than 7 is called an acid . As the hydronium ion concentration increases, the pH value decreases. Therefore, the more acidic a solution is, the lower its pH value is. Did you ever taste vinegar? Like other acids, it tastes sour. Stronger acids can be harmful to organisms. For example, stomach acid would eat through the stomach if it were not lined with a layer of mucus. Strong acids can also damage materials, even hard materials such as glass.", "situation": "Beth preferred to use natural cleaners. She had been using vinegar alone and mixed with water to clean her home for year and really liked the results. She was careful to were gloves when using it because if she had cuts on her hands it would burn and she also knew she should keep it away from her eyes. When she moved to her knew home however she was surprised to find that the vinegar was damaging her granite counter tops. She noticed that it was causing pitting in the granite.", "qas": [{"question": "What has a lower pH water or lemon?", "id": "3717695264", "answers": [{"text": "lemon"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solution has a higher concentration of hydronium ions than pure water, it has a pH lower than 7. A solution with a pH lower than 7 is called an acid . As the hydronium ion concentration increases, the pH value decreases. Therefore, the more acidic a solution is, the lower its pH value is. Did you ever taste vinegar? Like other acids, it tastes sour. Stronger acids can be harmful to organisms. For example, stomach acid would eat through the stomach if it were not lined with a layer of mucus. Strong acids can also damage materials, even hard materials such as glass.", "situation": "Beth preferred to use natural cleaners. She had been using vinegar alone and mixed with water to clean her home for year and really liked the results. She was careful to were gloves when using it because if she had cuts on her hands it would burn and she also knew she should keep it away from her eyes. When she moved to her knew home however she was surprised to find that the vinegar was damaging her granite counter tops. She noticed that it was causing pitting in the granite.", "qas": [{"question": "Would lemon taste sour or sweet?", "id": "1486456520", "answers": [{"text": "sour"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solution has a higher concentration of hydronium ions than pure water, it has a pH lower than 7. A solution with a pH lower than 7 is called an acid . As the hydronium ion concentration increases, the pH value decreases. Therefore, the more acidic a solution is, the lower its pH value is. Did you ever taste vinegar? Like other acids, it tastes sour. Stronger acids can be harmful to organisms. For example, stomach acid would eat through the stomach if it were not lined with a layer of mucus. Strong acids can also damage materials, even hard materials such as glass.", "situation": "Beth preferred to use natural cleaners. She had been using vinegar alone and mixed with water to clean her home for year and really liked the results. She was careful to were gloves when using it because if she had cuts on her hands it would burn and she also knew she should keep it away from her eyes. When she moved to her knew home however she was surprised to find that the vinegar was damaging her granite counter tops. She noticed that it was causing pitting in the granite.", "qas": [{"question": "Is lemon's pH above or below 7", "id": "984646903", "answers": [{"text": "below"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solution has a higher concentration of hydronium ions than pure water, it has a pH lower than 7. A solution with a pH lower than 7 is called an acid . As the hydronium ion concentration increases, the pH value decreases. Therefore, the more acidic a solution is, the lower its pH value is. Did you ever taste vinegar? Like other acids, it tastes sour. Stronger acids can be harmful to organisms. For example, stomach acid would eat through the stomach if it were not lined with a layer of mucus. Strong acids can also damage materials, even hard materials such as glass.", "situation": "Beth preferred to use natural cleaners. She had been using vinegar alone and mixed with water to clean her home for year and really liked the results. She was careful to were gloves when using it because if she had cuts on her hands it would burn and she also knew she should keep it away from her eyes. When she moved to her knew home however she was surprised to find that the vinegar was damaging her granite counter tops. She noticed that it was causing pitting in the granite.", "qas": [{"question": "What has a higher hydronium ion concentration water or lemon?", "id": "893489554", "answers": [{"text": "lemon"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solution has a higher concentration of hydronium ions than pure water, it has a pH lower than 7. A solution with a pH lower than 7 is called an acid . As the hydronium ion concentration increases, the pH value decreases. Therefore, the more acidic a solution is, the lower its pH value is. Did you ever taste vinegar? Like other acids, it tastes sour. Stronger acids can be harmful to organisms. For example, stomach acid would eat through the stomach if it were not lined with a layer of mucus. Strong acids can also damage materials, even hard materials such as glass.", "situation": "Beth preferred to use natural cleaners. She had been using vinegar alone and mixed with water to clean her home for year and really liked the results. She was careful to were gloves when using it because if she had cuts on her hands it would burn and she also knew she should keep it away from her eyes. When she moved to her knew home however she was surprised to find that the vinegar was damaging her granite counter tops. She noticed that it was causing pitting in the granite.", "qas": [{"question": "What has a lower hydronium ion concentration water or lemon?", "id": "2807402820", "answers": [{"text": "water"}]}]}, {"background": "Newton was the first one to suggest that gravity is universal and affects all objects in the universe. That\u2019s why his law of gravity is called the law of universal gravitation . Universal gravitation means that the force that causes an apple to fall from a tree to the ground is the same force that causes the moon to keep moving around Earth. Universal gravitation also means that while Earth exerts a pull on you, you exert a pull on Earth. In fact, there is gravity between you and every mass around you \u2014 your desk, your book, your pen. Even tiny molecules of gas are attracted to one another by the force of gravity.", "situation": "Joe was bored and really didn't want to do homework. He could not think of anything to write about gravity. Instead he kept leaning back on his chair and tossing his pencil in the air. He through the pencil up and every time it fell back towards him and he caught it.Once he leaned back to far and his chair went crashing to the floor. Startled he decided he should get to work.", "qas": [{"question": "what was pulling on the chair?", "id": "1552119297", "answers": [{"text": "gravity"}]}]}, {"background": "Newton was the first one to suggest that gravity is universal and affects all objects in the universe. That\u2019s why his law of gravity is called the law of universal gravitation . Universal gravitation means that the force that causes an apple to fall from a tree to the ground is the same force that causes the moon to keep moving around Earth. Universal gravitation also means that while Earth exerts a pull on you, you exert a pull on Earth. In fact, there is gravity between you and every mass around you \u2014 your desk, your book, your pen. Even tiny molecules of gas are attracted to one another by the force of gravity.", "situation": "Joe was bored and really didn't want to do homework. He could not think of anything to write about gravity. Instead he kept leaning back on his chair and tossing his pencil in the air. He through the pencil up and every time it fell back towards him and he caught it.Once he leaned back to far and his chair went crashing to the floor. Startled he decided he should get to work.", "qas": [{"question": "What made the pencil fall?", "id": "2142008392", "answers": [{"text": "gravity"}]}]}, {"background": "Newton was the first one to suggest that gravity is universal and affects all objects in the universe. That\u2019s why his law of gravity is called the law of universal gravitation . Universal gravitation means that the force that causes an apple to fall from a tree to the ground is the same force that causes the moon to keep moving around Earth. Universal gravitation also means that while Earth exerts a pull on you, you exert a pull on Earth. In fact, there is gravity between you and every mass around you \u2014 your desk, your book, your pen. Even tiny molecules of gas are attracted to one another by the force of gravity.", "situation": "Joe was bored and really didn't want to do homework. He could not think of anything to write about gravity. Instead he kept leaning back on his chair and tossing his pencil in the air. He through the pencil up and every time it fell back towards him and he caught it.Once he leaned back to far and his chair went crashing to the floor. Startled he decided he should get to work.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the pencil always fall bsck to earth or only sometimes?", "id": "3568468249", "answers": [{"text": "always"}]}]}, {"background": "When you add sugar to a cold drink, you may stir it to help the sugar dissolve. If you don\u2019t stir, the sugar may eventually dissolve, but it will take much longer. Stirring is one of several factors that affect how fast a solute dissolves in a solvent. Temperature is another factor. A solid solute dissolves faster at a higher temperature. For example, sugar dissolves faster in hot tea than in ice tea. A third factor that affects the rate of dissolving is the surface area of the solute. For example, if you put granulated sugar in a glass of ice tea, it will dissolve more quickly than the same amount of sugar in a cube. That\u2019s because granulated sugar has much more surface area than a cube of sugar. You can see videos of all three factors at these URLs", "situation": "Melissa and her friends were enjoying different beverages while making plans for an upcoming trip. Melisa and Barb had a cup of coffee but Barb used sugar cubes while Melisa preferred granulated sugar. Kelly and Lisa were both having tea but Kelly was having iced tea while Lisa was having hot tea but the both added a scoop of sugar to their tea.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's sugar will disolve faster Melisa's or Barb's?", "id": "1035510652", "answers": [{"text": "Melisa's "}]}]}, {"background": "When you add sugar to a cold drink, you may stir it to help the sugar dissolve. If you don\u2019t stir, the sugar may eventually dissolve, but it will take much longer. Stirring is one of several factors that affect how fast a solute dissolves in a solvent. Temperature is another factor. A solid solute dissolves faster at a higher temperature. For example, sugar dissolves faster in hot tea than in ice tea. A third factor that affects the rate of dissolving is the surface area of the solute. For example, if you put granulated sugar in a glass of ice tea, it will dissolve more quickly than the same amount of sugar in a cube. That\u2019s because granulated sugar has much more surface area than a cube of sugar. You can see videos of all three factors at these URLs", "situation": "Melissa and her friends were enjoying different beverages while making plans for an upcoming trip. Melisa and Barb had a cup of coffee but Barb used sugar cubes while Melisa preferred granulated sugar. Kelly and Lisa were both having tea but Kelly was having iced tea while Lisa was having hot tea but the both added a scoop of sugar to their tea.", "qas": [{"question": "Would Lisa's sugar melt faster or slower if she stirred it?", "id": "1763944133", "answers": [{"text": "faster"}]}]}, {"background": "When you add sugar to a cold drink, you may stir it to help the sugar dissolve. If you don\u2019t stir, the sugar may eventually dissolve, but it will take much longer. Stirring is one of several factors that affect how fast a solute dissolves in a solvent. Temperature is another factor. A solid solute dissolves faster at a higher temperature. For example, sugar dissolves faster in hot tea than in ice tea. A third factor that affects the rate of dissolving is the surface area of the solute. For example, if you put granulated sugar in a glass of ice tea, it will dissolve more quickly than the same amount of sugar in a cube. That\u2019s because granulated sugar has much more surface area than a cube of sugar. You can see videos of all three factors at these URLs", "situation": "Melissa and her friends were enjoying different beverages while making plans for an upcoming trip. Melisa and Barb had a cup of coffee but Barb used sugar cubes while Melisa preferred granulated sugar. Kelly and Lisa were both having tea but Kelly was having iced tea while Lisa was having hot tea but the both added a scoop of sugar to their tea.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Kelly's sugar dissolve faster or slower than Lisa's?", "id": "614901286", "answers": [{"text": "slower"}]}]}, {"background": "When you add sugar to a cold drink, you may stir it to help the sugar dissolve. If you don\u2019t stir, the sugar may eventually dissolve, but it will take much longer. Stirring is one of several factors that affect how fast a solute dissolves in a solvent. Temperature is another factor. A solid solute dissolves faster at a higher temperature. For example, sugar dissolves faster in hot tea than in ice tea. A third factor that affects the rate of dissolving is the surface area of the solute. For example, if you put granulated sugar in a glass of ice tea, it will dissolve more quickly than the same amount of sugar in a cube. That\u2019s because granulated sugar has much more surface area than a cube of sugar. You can see videos of all three factors at these URLs", "situation": "Melissa and her friends were enjoying different beverages while making plans for an upcoming trip. Melisa and Barb had a cup of coffee but Barb used sugar cubes while Melisa preferred granulated sugar. Kelly and Lisa were both having tea but Kelly was having iced tea while Lisa was having hot tea but the both added a scoop of sugar to their tea.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Kelly's sugar dissolve faster or slower than Barb's?", "id": "607102484", "answers": [{"text": "faster"}]}]}, {"background": "When you add sugar to a cold drink, you may stir it to help the sugar dissolve. If you don't stir, the sugar may eventually dissolve, but it will take much longer. Stirring is one of several factors that affect how fast a solute dissolves in a solvent. Temperature is another factor. A solid solute dissolves faster at a higher temperature. For example, sugar dissolves faster in hot tea than in ice tea. A third factor that affects the rate of dissolving is the surface area of the solute. For example, if you put granulated sugar in a glass of ice tea, it will dissolve more quickly than the same amount of sugar in a cube. That's because granulated sugar has much more surface area than a cube of sugar. You can see videos of all three factors at these URLs", "situation": "Sue and Beth both liked tea but Sue liked iced tea while Beth liked hot tea. They both liked their tea with one cube of sugar rather than granulated sugar.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's sugar will dissolve in their tea fastest if neither stirs it.", "id": "4153631818", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "When you add sugar to a cold drink, you may stir it to help the sugar dissolve. If you don't stir, the sugar may eventually dissolve, but it will take much longer. Stirring is one of several factors that affect how fast a solute dissolves in a solvent. Temperature is another factor. A solid solute dissolves faster at a higher temperature. For example, sugar dissolves faster in hot tea than in ice tea. A third factor that affects the rate of dissolving is the surface area of the solute. For example, if you put granulated sugar in a glass of ice tea, it will dissolve more quickly than the same amount of sugar in a cube. That's because granulated sugar has much more surface area than a cube of sugar. You can see videos of all three factors at these URLs", "situation": "Sue and Beth both liked tea but Sue liked iced tea while Beth liked hot tea. They both liked their tea with one cube of sugar rather than granulated sugar.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's sugar will dissolve in their tea slowes if neither stirs it.", "id": "2477024237", "answers": [{"text": "Sue"}]}]}, {"background": "When you add sugar to a cold drink, you may stir it to help the sugar dissolve. If you don't stir, the sugar may eventually dissolve, but it will take much longer. Stirring is one of several factors that affect how fast a solute dissolves in a solvent. Temperature is another factor. A solid solute dissolves faster at a higher temperature. For example, sugar dissolves faster in hot tea than in ice tea. A third factor that affects the rate of dissolving is the surface area of the solute. For example, if you put granulated sugar in a glass of ice tea, it will dissolve more quickly than the same amount of sugar in a cube. That's because granulated sugar has much more surface area than a cube of sugar. You can see videos of all three factors at these URLs", "situation": "Sue and Beth both liked tea but Sue liked iced tea while Beth liked hot tea. They both liked their tea with one cube of sugar rather than granulated sugar.", "qas": [{"question": "What could they add to their tea if they wanted the sugar to  dissolve faster?", "id": "1170892768", "answers": [{"text": "granulated sugar"}]}]}, {"background": "When you add sugar to a cold drink, you may stir it to help the sugar dissolve. If you don't stir, the sugar may eventually dissolve, but it will take much longer. Stirring is one of several factors that affect how fast a solute dissolves in a solvent. Temperature is another factor. A solid solute dissolves faster at a higher temperature. For example, sugar dissolves faster in hot tea than in ice tea. A third factor that affects the rate of dissolving is the surface area of the solute. For example, if you put granulated sugar in a glass of ice tea, it will dissolve more quickly than the same amount of sugar in a cube. That's because granulated sugar has much more surface area than a cube of sugar. You can see videos of all three factors at these URLs", "situation": "Sue and Beth both liked tea but Sue liked iced tea while Beth liked hot tea. They both liked their tea with one cube of sugar rather than granulated sugar.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the sugar cub dissolve faster or slower in the hot tea?", "id": "1136419222", "answers": [{"text": "faster"}]}]}, {"background": "Higher pressures increase the solubility of gases. You are probably familiar with this concept as it relates to carbonated beverages. Before opening the container, the inside is pressurized, so a large amount of CO 2 is dissolved in the liquid. After opening, the pressure decreases (to the ambient pressure), so the solubility of CO 2 drops, causing it to bubble out of solution. Because they are not compressible like gases, solid and liquid solutes do not have noticeable changes in solubility at different external pressures.", "situation": "Dan and Sam were enjoying a beverage on a hot day. Dan was drinking a soda while Sam was drinking lemonade. They both left their drinks open while they went for a quick swim then returned to finish them.", "qas": [{"question": "Whos drink bubbled when it was first opened Dan's or Sam's?", "id": "3844284019", "answers": [{"text": "Dan's"}]}]}, {"background": "Higher pressures increase the solubility of gases. You are probably familiar with this concept as it relates to carbonated beverages. Before opening the container, the inside is pressurized, so a large amount of CO 2 is dissolved in the liquid. After opening, the pressure decreases (to the ambient pressure), so the solubility of CO 2 drops, causing it to bubble out of solution. Because they are not compressible like gases, solid and liquid solutes do not have noticeable changes in solubility at different external pressures.", "situation": "Dan and Sam were enjoying a beverage on a hot day. Dan was drinking a soda while Sam was drinking lemonade. They both left their drinks open while they went for a quick swim then returned to finish them.", "qas": [{"question": "Whos drink did not bubble when it was first opened Dan's or Sam's?", "id": "3226607825", "answers": [{"text": "Sam's"}]}]}, {"background": "Higher pressures increase the solubility of gases. You are probably familiar with this concept as it relates to carbonated beverages. Before opening the container, the inside is pressurized, so a large amount of CO 2 is dissolved in the liquid. After opening, the pressure decreases (to the ambient pressure), so the solubility of CO 2 drops, causing it to bubble out of solution. Because they are not compressible like gases, solid and liquid solutes do not have noticeable changes in solubility at different external pressures.", "situation": "Dan and Sam were enjoying a beverage on a hot day. Dan was drinking a soda while Sam was drinking lemonade. They both left their drinks open while they went for a quick swim then returned to finish them.", "qas": [{"question": "Which dink was not flat when the boys returned the lemonade or the soda?", "id": "2599297992", "answers": [{"text": "the lemonade"}]}]}, {"background": "Higher pressures increase the solubility of gases. You are probably familiar with this concept as it relates to carbonated beverages. Before opening the container, the inside is pressurized, so a large amount of CO 2 is dissolved in the liquid. After opening, the pressure decreases (to the ambient pressure), so the solubility of CO 2 drops, causing it to bubble out of solution. Because they are not compressible like gases, solid and liquid solutes do not have noticeable changes in solubility at different external pressures.", "situation": "Dan and Sam were enjoying a beverage on a hot day. Dan was drinking a soda while Sam was drinking lemonade. They both left their drinks open while they went for a quick swim then returned to finish them.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's drink responded to a change in pressure Sam's or Dan's?", "id": "464396043", "answers": [{"text": "Dan's"}]}]}, {"background": "Higher pressures increase the solubility of gases. You are probably familiar with this concept as it relates to carbonated beverages. Before opening the container, the inside is pressurized, so a large amount of CO 2 is dissolved in the liquid. After opening, the pressure decreases (to the ambient pressure), so the solubility of CO 2 drops, causing it to bubble out of solution. Because they are not compressible like gases, solid and liquid solutes do not have noticeable changes in solubility at different external pressures.", "situation": "Dan and Sam were enjoying a beverage on a hot day. Dan was drinking a soda while Sam was drinking lemonade. They both left their drinks open while they went for a quick swim then returned to finish them.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's drink did not responded to a change in pressure Sam's or Dan's?", "id": "504046029", "answers": [{"text": "Sam's"}]}]}, {"background": "Higher pressures increase the solubility of gases. You are probably familiar with this concept as it relates to carbonated beverages. Before opening the container, the inside is pressurized, so a large amount of CO 2 is dissolved in the liquid. After opening, the pressure decreases (to the ambient pressure), so the solubility of CO 2 drops, causing it to bubble out of solution. Because they are not compressible like gases, solid and liquid solutes do not have noticeable changes in solubility at different external pressures.", "situation": "Jane worked at a bottling company she liked her job but her favorite thing was to watch as carbon dioxide was added to the soda to make it fizzy. Today she grabbed a cola on her way to break. When she opened the can and poured it into a cup she hear a fizzing sound and saw the soda bubbling in the glass. She got to talk and forgot about her drink when she took a sip later the soda was flat, there was no carbonation left.", "qas": [{"question": "Is pressure increased or decreased to get carbon dioxide to dissolve in the soda?", "id": "3801576788", "answers": [{"text": "increased"}]}]}, {"background": "Higher pressures increase the solubility of gases. You are probably familiar with this concept as it relates to carbonated beverages. Before opening the container, the inside is pressurized, so a large amount of CO 2 is dissolved in the liquid. After opening, the pressure decreases (to the ambient pressure), so the solubility of CO 2 drops, causing it to bubble out of solution. Because they are not compressible like gases, solid and liquid solutes do not have noticeable changes in solubility at different external pressures.", "situation": "Jane worked at a bottling company she liked her job but her favorite thing was to watch as carbon dioxide was added to the soda to make it fizzy. Today she grabbed a cola on her way to break. When she opened the can and poured it into a cup she hear a fizzing sound and saw the soda bubbling in the glass. She got to talk and forgot about her drink when she took a sip later the soda was flat, there was no carbonation left.", "qas": [{"question": "Is pressure increased or decreased when the soda can is opened??", "id": "1155559117", "answers": [{"text": "decreased"}]}]}, {"background": "Higher pressures increase the solubility of gases. You are probably familiar with this concept as it relates to carbonated beverages. Before opening the container, the inside is pressurized, so a large amount of CO 2 is dissolved in the liquid. After opening, the pressure decreases (to the ambient pressure), so the solubility of CO 2 drops, causing it to bubble out of solution. Because they are not compressible like gases, solid and liquid solutes do not have noticeable changes in solubility at different external pressures.", "situation": "Jane worked at a bottling company she liked her job but her favorite thing was to watch as carbon dioxide was added to the soda to make it fizzy. Today she grabbed a cola on her way to break. When she opened the can and poured it into a cup she hear a fizzing sound and saw the soda bubbling in the glass. She got to talk and forgot about her drink when she took a sip later the soda was flat, there was no carbonation left.", "qas": [{"question": "Is carbon dioxide absorbed or released by the soda when it is opened?", "id": "1686138991", "answers": [{"text": "released"}]}]}, {"background": "Higher pressures increase the solubility of gases. You are probably familiar with this concept as it relates to carbonated beverages. Before opening the container, the inside is pressurized, so a large amount of CO 2 is dissolved in the liquid. After opening, the pressure decreases (to the ambient pressure), so the solubility of CO 2 drops, causing it to bubble out of solution. Because they are not compressible like gases, solid and liquid solutes do not have noticeable changes in solubility at different external pressures.", "situation": "Jane worked at a bottling company she liked her job but her favorite thing was to watch as carbon dioxide was added to the soda to make it fizzy. Today she grabbed a cola on her way to break. When she opened the can and poured it into a cup she hear a fizzing sound and saw the soda bubbling in the glass. She got to talk and forgot about her drink when she took a sip later the soda was flat, there was no carbonation left.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the Is carbon dioxide level higher or lower before the can is opened?", "id": "2776527185", "answers": [{"text": "before"}]}]}, {"background": "Higher pressures increase the solubility of gases. You are probably familiar with this concept as it relates to carbonated beverages. Before opening the container, the inside is pressurized, so a large amount of CO 2 is dissolved in the liquid. After opening, the pressure decreases (to the ambient pressure), so the solubility of CO 2 drops, causing it to bubble out of solution. Because they are not compressible like gases, solid and liquid solutes do not have noticeable changes in solubility at different external pressures.", "situation": "Jane worked at a bottling company she liked her job but her favorite thing was to watch as carbon dioxide was added to the soda to make it fizzy. Today she grabbed a cola on her way to break. When she opened the can and poured it into a cup she hear a fizzing sound and saw the soda bubbling in the glass. She got to talk and forgot about her drink when she took a sip later the soda was flat, there was no carbonation left.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the Is carbon dioxide level higher or lower after the can is opened?", "id": "865628400", "answers": [{"text": "lower"}]}]}, {"background": "Higher pressures increase the solubility of gases. You are probably familiar with this concept as it relates to carbonated beverages. Before opening the container, the inside is pressurized, so a large amount of CO 2 is dissolved in the liquid. After opening, the pressure decreases (to the ambient pressure), so the solubility of CO 2 drops, causing it to bubble out of solution. Because they are not compressible like gases, solid and liquid solutes do not have noticeable changes in solubility at different external pressures.", "situation": "Jane worked at a bottling company she liked her job but her favorite thing was to watch as carbon dioxide was added to the soda to make it fizzy. Today she grabbed a cola on her way to break. When she opened the can and poured it into a cup she hear a fizzing sound and saw the soda bubbling in the glass. She got to talk and forgot about her drink when she took a sip later the soda was flat, there was no carbonation left.", "qas": [{"question": "When the soda was flat was the Is carbon dioxide in the soda equal to or greater than the Is carbon dioxide in the air?", "id": "4074209714", "answers": [{"text": "equal"}]}]}, {"background": "Higher pressures increase the solubility of gases. You are probably familiar with this concept as it relates to carbonated beverages. Before opening the container, the inside is pressurized, so a large amount of CO 2 is dissolved in the liquid. After opening, the pressure decreases (to the ambient pressure), so the solubility of CO 2 drops, causing it to bubble out of solution. Because they are not compressible like gases, solid and liquid solutes do not have noticeable changes in solubility at different external pressures.", "situation": "Jane worked at a bottling company she liked her job but her favorite thing was to watch as carbon dioxide was added to the soda to make it fizzy. Today she grabbed a cola on her way to break. When she opened the can and poured it into a cup she hear a fizzing sound and saw the soda bubbling in the glass. She got to talk and forgot about her drink when she took a sip later the soda was flat, there was no carbonation left.", "qas": [{"question": "When the can was closed was the carbon dioxide in the soda equal to or greater than the Is carbon dioxide in the air?", "id": "33325364", "answers": [{"text": "greater"}]}]}, {"background": "Higher pressures increase the solubility of gases. You are probably familiar with this concept as it relates to carbonated beverages. Before opening the container, the inside is pressurized, so a large amount of CO 2 is dissolved in the liquid. After opening, the pressure decreases (to the ambient pressure), so the solubility of CO 2 drops, causing it to bubble out of solution. Because they are not compressible like gases, solid and liquid solutes do not have noticeable changes in solubility at different external pressures.", "situation": "Jane worked at a bottling company she liked her job but her favorite thing was to watch as carbon dioxide was added to the soda to make it fizzy. Today she grabbed a cola on her way to break. When she opened the can and poured it into a cup she hear a fizzing sound and saw the soda bubbling in the glass. She got to talk and forgot about her drink when she took a sip later the soda was flat, there was no carbonation left.", "qas": [{"question": "When the can was first opened was the carbon dioxide in the soda equal to or greater than the Is carbon dioxide in the air?", "id": "527860605", "answers": [{"text": "greater"}]}]}, {"background": "Higher pressures increase the solubility of gases. You are probably familiar with this concept as it relates to carbonated beverages. Before opening the container, the inside is pressurized, so a large amount of CO 2 is dissolved in the liquid. After opening, the pressure decreases (to the ambient pressure), so the solubility of CO 2 drops, causing it to bubble out of solution. Because they are not compressible like gases, solid and liquid solutes do not have noticeable changes in solubility at different external pressures.", "situation": "Jane worked at a bottling company she liked her job but her favorite thing was to watch as carbon dioxide was added to the soda to make it fizzy. Today she grabbed a cola on her way to break. When she opened the can and poured it into a cup she hear a fizzing sound and saw the soda bubbling in the glass. She got to talk and forgot about her drink when she took a sip later the soda was flat, there was no carbonation left.", "qas": [{"question": "is the Is carbon dioxide pressure decreasing or staying the same after the soda is flat??", "id": "2367518700", "answers": [{"text": "staying the same"}]}]}, {"background": "All fluids exert pressure like the air inside a tire. The particles of fluids are constantly moving in all directions at random. As the particles move, they keep bumping into each other and into anything else in their path. These collisions cause pressure, and the pressure is exerted equally in all directions. When particles are crowded together in one part of an enclosed space, such as the air particles first entering a tire, they quickly spread out to fill all the available space. That's because particles of fluids always move from an area of higher pressure to an area of lower pressure. This explains why air entering a tire through a tiny opening quickly fills the entire tire.", "situation": "During a particularly dry year the far At first he was carrying water from the near by creek but decided he needed to find an easier way to get water to his crops. The farmer decided to dig an irrigation ditch from the creek to his fields. He used rocks to block off the creek while he dug. when he was done digging the ditch he removed the rocks and watched as the water flowed down the irrigation ditch to his fields.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the water pressure higher in the creek or the canal.", "id": "3484002020", "answers": [{"text": "canal"}]}]}, {"background": "All fluids exert pressure like the air inside a tire. The particles of fluids are constantly moving in all directions at random. As the particles move, they keep bumping into each other and into anything else in their path. These collisions cause pressure, and the pressure is exerted equally in all directions. When particles are crowded together in one part of an enclosed space, such as the air particles first entering a tire, they quickly spread out to fill all the available space. That's because particles of fluids always move from an area of higher pressure to an area of lower pressure. This explains why air entering a tire through a tiny opening quickly fills the entire tire.", "situation": "During a particularly dry year the far At first he was carrying water from the near by creek but decided he needed to find an easier way to get water to his crops. The farmer decided to dig an irrigation ditch from the creek to his fields. He used rocks to block off the creek while he dug. when he was done digging the ditch he removed the rocks and watched as the water flowed down the irrigation ditch to his fields.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the water pressure lower in the creek or the canal.", "id": "706717334", "answers": [{"text": "creek"}]}]}, {"background": "All fluids exert pressure like the air inside a tire. The particles of fluids are constantly moving in all directions at random. As the particles move, they keep bumping into each other and into anything else in their path. These collisions cause pressure, and the pressure is exerted equally in all directions. When particles are crowded together in one part of an enclosed space, such as the air particles first entering a tire, they quickly spread out to fill all the available space. That's because particles of fluids always move from an area of higher pressure to an area of lower pressure. This explains why air entering a tire through a tiny opening quickly fills the entire tire.", "situation": "During a particularly dry year the far At first he was carrying water from the near by creek but decided he needed to find an easier way to get water to his crops. The farmer decided to dig an irrigation ditch from the creek to his fields. He used rocks to block off the creek while he dug. when he was done digging the ditch he removed the rocks and watched as the water flowed down the irrigation ditch to his fields.", "qas": [{"question": "was the presssure behind the rocks high or low?", "id": "100705291", "answers": [{"text": "high"}]}]}, {"background": "All fluids exert pressure like the air inside a tire. The particles of fluids are constantly moving in all directions at random. As the particles move, they keep bumping into each other and into anything else in their path. These collisions cause pressure, and the pressure is exerted equally in all directions. When particles are crowded together in one part of an enclosed space, such as the air particles first entering a tire, they quickly spread out to fill all the available space. That's because particles of fluids always move from an area of higher pressure to an area of lower pressure. This explains why air entering a tire through a tiny opening quickly fills the entire tire.", "situation": "Mary blew up the punching balloon for her daughter. She blew air into the narrow opening until the balloon was full then tucked it closed. After Ann played with it for awhile she gave it back to her mother. Mary opened the balloon back up and the air rushed out of the opening.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the air pressure higher or lower iside the balloon when it was flat?", "id": "1661172354", "answers": [{"text": "lower"}]}]}, {"background": "All fluids exert pressure like the air inside a tire. The particles of fluids are constantly moving in all directions at random. As the particles move, they keep bumping into each other and into anything else in their path. These collisions cause pressure, and the pressure is exerted equally in all directions. When particles are crowded together in one part of an enclosed space, such as the air particles first entering a tire, they quickly spread out to fill all the available space. That's because particles of fluids always move from an area of higher pressure to an area of lower pressure. This explains why air entering a tire through a tiny opening quickly fills the entire tire.", "situation": "Mary blew up the punching balloon for her daughter. She blew air into the narrow opening until the balloon was full then tucked it closed. After Ann played with it for awhile she gave it back to her mother. Mary opened the balloon back up and the air rushed out of the opening.", "qas": [{"question": "When it was flat was there more air pressure in the ballon or outside or was it the same?", "id": "2878373971", "answers": [{"text": "same"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Many people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer's disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Mark enjoyed going to work everyday. He knew that he was at his physical peak and liked to run marathons and participate in martial arts. Jim retired last year and is having fun traveling around the country and golfing with his friends. Sometimes Jim has trouble remembering where he left his keys. His doctor has warned him to be careful about being exposed to to the flu or even a cold. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is older?", "id": "3085781783", "answers": [{"text": "Jim"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Many people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer's disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Mark enjoyed going to work everyday. He knew that he was at his physical peak and liked to run marathons and participate in martial arts. Jim retired last year and is having fun traveling around the country and golfing with his friends. Sometimes Jim has trouble remembering where he left his keys. His doctor has warned him to be careful about being exposed to to the flu or even a cold. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is younger?", "id": "1351306250", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Many people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer's disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Mark enjoyed going to work everyday. He knew that he was at his physical peak and liked to run marathons and participate in martial arts. Jim retired last year and is having fun traveling around the country and golfing with his friends. Sometimes Jim has trouble remembering where he left his keys. His doctor has warned him to be careful about being exposed to to the flu or even a cold. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who has more time to persue their interests?", "id": "2282903255", "answers": [{"text": "Jim"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Many people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer's disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Mark enjoyed going to work everyday. He knew that he was at his physical peak and liked to run marathons and participate in martial arts. Jim retired last year and is having fun traveling around the country and golfing with his friends. Sometimes Jim has trouble remembering where he left his keys. His doctor has warned him to be careful about being exposed to to the flu or even a cold. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is stronger?", "id": "2636205173", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Many people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer's disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Mark enjoyed going to work everyday. He knew that he was at his physical peak and liked to run marathons and participate in martial arts. Jim retired last year and is having fun traveling around the country and golfing with his friends. Sometimes Jim has trouble remembering where he left his keys. His doctor has warned him to be careful about being exposed to to the flu or even a cold. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who has a stronger immune system?", "id": "3846263494", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Many people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer's disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Mark enjoyed going to work everyday. He knew that he was at his physical peak and liked to run marathons and participate in martial arts. Jim retired last year and is having fun traveling around the country and golfing with his friends. Sometimes Jim has trouble remembering where he left his keys. His doctor has warned him to be careful about being exposed to to the flu or even a cold. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who has a weaker immune system?", "id": "1017139665", "answers": [{"text": "Jim"}]}]}, {"background": "Rain dissolves fertilizer in the soil. Runoff carries it away. The fertilizer ends up in bodies of water, from ponds to oceans. The nitrogen is a fertilizer in the water bodies. Since there is a lot of nitrogen it causes algae to grow out of control. Figure below shows a pond covered with algae. Algae may use up so much oxygen in the water that nothing else can grow. Soon, even the algae die out. Decomposers break down the dead tissue and use up all the oxygen in the water. This creates a dead zone. A dead zone is an area in a body of water where nothing grows because there is too little oxygen. There is a large dead zone in the Gulf of Mexico. You can see it Figure below .", "situation": "Mark's grandparents owned some land in the country and he remembered fishing there when he was young. Mark decided to go visit the place and do some fishing. He was disappointed when he got there and saw the pond covered in algae. Since he had come all this way he decided to try fishing anyway but didn't catch any fish all day.", "qas": [{"question": "what caused the algae to grow too much nitrogen or too much oxygen?", "id": "730169441", "answers": [{"text": "algae"}]}]}, {"background": "Rain dissolves fertilizer in the soil. Runoff carries it away. The fertilizer ends up in bodies of water, from ponds to oceans. The nitrogen is a fertilizer in the water bodies. Since there is a lot of nitrogen it causes algae to grow out of control. Figure below shows a pond covered with algae. Algae may use up so much oxygen in the water that nothing else can grow. Soon, even the algae die out. Decomposers break down the dead tissue and use up all the oxygen in the water. This creates a dead zone. A dead zone is an area in a body of water where nothing grows because there is too little oxygen. There is a large dead zone in the Gulf of Mexico. You can see it Figure below .", "situation": "Mark's grandparents owned some land in the country and he remembered fishing there when he was young. Mark decided to go visit the place and do some fishing. He was disappointed when he got there and saw the pond covered in algae and there were very few fish. Since he had come all this way he decided to try fishing anyway but didn't catch any fish all day.", "qas": [{"question": "What was killing the fish?", "id": "1383168928", "answers": [{"text": "algae"}]}]}, {"background": "Rain dissolves fertilizer in the soil. Runoff carries it away. The fertilizer ends up in bodies of water, from ponds to oceans. The nitrogen is a fertilizer in the water bodies. Since there is a lot of nitrogen it causes algae to grow out of control. Figure below shows a pond covered with algae. Algae may use up so much oxygen in the water that nothing else can grow. Soon, even the algae die out. Decomposers break down the dead tissue and use up all the oxygen in the water. This creates a dead zone. A dead zone is an area in a body of water where nothing grows because there is too little oxygen. There is a large dead zone in the Gulf of Mexico. You can see it Figure below .", "situation": "Mark's grandparents owned some land in the country and he remembered fishing there when he was young. Mark decided to go visit the place and do some fishing. He was disappointed when he got there and saw the pond covered in algae and there were very few fish. Since he had come all this way he decided to try fishing anyway but didn't catch any fish all day.", "qas": [{"question": "Is there too much nitrogen or to much oxygen in the water?", "id": "2264696651", "answers": [{"text": "oxygen"}]}]}, {"background": "Rain dissolves fertilizer in the soil. Runoff carries it away. The fertilizer ends up in bodies of water, from ponds to oceans. The nitrogen is a fertilizer in the water bodies. Since there is a lot of nitrogen it causes algae to grow out of control. Figure below shows a pond covered with algae. Algae may use up so much oxygen in the water that nothing else can grow. Soon, even the algae die out. Decomposers break down the dead tissue and use up all the oxygen in the water. This creates a dead zone. A dead zone is an area in a body of water where nothing grows because there is too little oxygen. There is a large dead zone in the Gulf of Mexico. You can see it Figure below .", "situation": "Mark's grandparents owned some land in the country and he remembered fishing there when he was young. Mark decided to go visit the place and do some fishing. He was disappointed when he got there and saw the pond covered in algae and there were very few fish. Since he had come all this way he decided to try fishing anyway but didn't catch any fish all day.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the algea keep growing or eventually die?", "id": "1209041693", "answers": [{"text": "die"}]}]}, {"background": "Rain dissolves fertilizer in the soil. Runoff carries it away. The fertilizer ends up in bodies of water, from ponds to oceans. The nitrogen is a fertilizer in the water bodies. Since there is a lot of nitrogen it causes algae to grow out of control. Figure below shows a pond covered with algae. Algae may use up so much oxygen in the water that nothing else can grow. Soon, even the algae die out. Decomposers break down the dead tissue and use up all the oxygen in the water. This creates a dead zone. A dead zone is an area in a body of water where nothing grows because there is too little oxygen. There is a large dead zone in the Gulf of Mexico. You can see it Figure below .", "situation": "As mark walked along the field he saw a small pond and walked over to it.  As Mark looked around at the wide open farm land he wondered why none fished there. Once he was closer noticed that the pond was completely covered with algae.", "qas": [{"question": "Is there too much oxygen or nitrogen in the water?", "id": "3024443367", "answers": [{"text": "nitrogen"}]}]}, {"background": "Rain dissolves fertilizer in the soil. Runoff carries it away. The fertilizer ends up in bodies of water, from ponds to oceans. The nitrogen is a fertilizer in the water bodies. Since there is a lot of nitrogen it causes algae to grow out of control. Figure below shows a pond covered with algae. Algae may use up so much oxygen in the water that nothing else can grow. Soon, even the algae die out. Decomposers break down the dead tissue and use up all the oxygen in the water. This creates a dead zone. A dead zone is an area in a body of water where nothing grows because there is too little oxygen. There is a large dead zone in the Gulf of Mexico. You can see it Figure below .", "situation": "As mark walked along the field he saw a small pond and walked over to it.  As Mark looked around at the wide open farm land he wondered why none fished there. Once he was closer noticed that the pond was completely covered with algae.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the algea consuming the oxygen or carbondioxide?", "id": "211638425", "answers": [{"text": "carbondioxide"}]}]}, {"background": "Rain dissolves fertilizer in the soil. Runoff carries it away. The fertilizer ends up in bodies of water, from ponds to oceans. The nitrogen is a fertilizer in the water bodies. Since there is a lot of nitrogen it causes algae to grow out of control. Figure below shows a pond covered with algae. Algae may use up so much oxygen in the water that nothing else can grow. Soon, even the algae die out. Decomposers break down the dead tissue and use up all the oxygen in the water. This creates a dead zone. A dead zone is an area in a body of water where nothing grows because there is too little oxygen. There is a large dead zone in the Gulf of Mexico. You can see it Figure below .", "situation": "As mark walked along the field he saw a small pond and walked over to it.  As Mark looked around at the wide open farm land he wondered why none fished there. Once he was closer noticed that the pond was completely covered with algae.", "qas": [{"question": "will decomposser use up the oxygen or carbondioxide?", "id": "2077972829", "answers": [{"text": "oxygen"}]}]}, {"background": "Rain dissolves fertilizer in the soil. Runoff carries it away. The fertilizer ends up in bodies of water, from ponds to oceans. The nitrogen is a fertilizer in the water bodies. Since there is a lot of nitrogen it causes algae to grow out of control. Figure below shows a pond covered with algae. Algae may use up so much oxygen in the water that nothing else can grow. Soon, even the algae die out. Decomposers break down the dead tissue and use up all the oxygen in the water. This creates a dead zone. A dead zone is an area in a body of water where nothing grows because there is too little oxygen. There is a large dead zone in the Gulf of Mexico. You can see it Figure below .", "situation": "As mark walked along the field he saw a small pond and walked over to it.  As Mark looked around at the wide open farm land he wondered why none fished there. Once he was closer noticed that the pond was completely covered with algae.", "qas": [{"question": "Does a lot of algea benefit or harm fish?", "id": "2571850738", "answers": [{"text": "harm"}]}]}, {"background": "Rain dissolves fertilizer in the soil. Runoff carries it away. The fertilizer ends up in bodies of water, from ponds to oceans. The nitrogen is a fertilizer in the water bodies. Since there is a lot of nitrogen it causes algae to grow out of control. Figure below shows a pond covered with algae. Algae may use up so much oxygen in the water that nothing else can grow. Soon, even the algae die out. Decomposers break down the dead tissue and use up all the oxygen in the water. This creates a dead zone. A dead zone is an area in a body of water where nothing grows because there is too little oxygen. There is a large dead zone in the Gulf of Mexico. You can see it Figure below .", "situation": "As mark walked along the field he saw a small pond and walked over to it.  As Mark looked around at the wide open farm land he wondered why none fished there. Once he was closer noticed that the pond was completely covered with algae.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the water habitable or uninhabitable?", "id": "1422742635", "answers": [{"text": "uninhabitable"}]}]}, {"background": "Rain dissolves fertilizer in the soil. Runoff carries it away. The fertilizer ends up in bodies of water, from ponds to oceans. The nitrogen is a fertilizer in the water bodies. Since there is a lot of nitrogen it causes algae to grow out of control. Figure below shows a pond covered with algae. Algae may use up so much oxygen in the water that nothing else can grow. Soon, even the algae die out. Decomposers break down the dead tissue and use up all the oxygen in the water. This creates a dead zone. A dead zone is an area in a body of water where nothing grows because there is too little oxygen. There is a large dead zone in the Gulf of Mexico. You can see it Figure below .", "situation": "Mark had been fishing all morning and only caught one fish. He was disappointed because he remembers catching a lot of fish here as a child. There was a lot more algae than back then but other wise the area looked pretty much the same, dotted with lots of small farms.", "qas": [{"question": "Was there more or less nitrogen in the water than when Mark was a child.", "id": "3256773569", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Rain dissolves fertilizer in the soil. Runoff carries it away. The fertilizer ends up in bodies of water, from ponds to oceans. The nitrogen is a fertilizer in the water bodies. Since there is a lot of nitrogen it causes algae to grow out of control. Figure below shows a pond covered with algae. Algae may use up so much oxygen in the water that nothing else can grow. Soon, even the algae die out. Decomposers break down the dead tissue and use up all the oxygen in the water. This creates a dead zone. A dead zone is an area in a body of water where nothing grows because there is too little oxygen. There is a large dead zone in the Gulf of Mexico. You can see it Figure below .", "situation": "Mark had been fishing all morning and only caught one fish. He was disappointed because he remembers catching a lot of fish here as a child. There was a lot more algae than back then but other wise the area looked pretty much the same, dotted with lots of small farms.", "qas": [{"question": "Was there more or less oxygen in the water than when Mark was a child.", "id": "3871894261", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Rain dissolves fertilizer in the soil. Runoff carries it away. The fertilizer ends up in bodies of water, from ponds to oceans. The nitrogen is a fertilizer in the water bodies. Since there is a lot of nitrogen it causes algae to grow out of control. Figure below shows a pond covered with algae. Algae may use up so much oxygen in the water that nothing else can grow. Soon, even the algae die out. Decomposers break down the dead tissue and use up all the oxygen in the water. This creates a dead zone. A dead zone is an area in a body of water where nothing grows because there is too little oxygen. There is a large dead zone in the Gulf of Mexico. You can see it Figure below .", "situation": "Mark had been fishing all morning and only caught one fish. He was disappointed because he remembers catching a lot of fish here as a child. There was a lot more algae than back then but other wise the area looked pretty much the same, dotted with lots of small farms.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the pond able to support more or less fish than in the past?", "id": "4152649885", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Rain dissolves fertilizer in the soil. Runoff carries it away. The fertilizer ends up in bodies of water, from ponds to oceans. The nitrogen is a fertilizer in the water bodies. Since there is a lot of nitrogen it causes algae to grow out of control. Figure below shows a pond covered with algae. Algae may use up so much oxygen in the water that nothing else can grow. Soon, even the algae die out. Decomposers break down the dead tissue and use up all the oxygen in the water. This creates a dead zone. A dead zone is an area in a body of water where nothing grows because there is too little oxygen. There is a large dead zone in the Gulf of Mexico. You can see it Figure below .", "situation": "Mark had been fishing all morning and only caught one fish. He was disappointed because he remembers catching a lot of fish here as a child. There was a lot more algae than back then but other wise the area looked pretty much the same, dotted with lots of small farms.", "qas": [{"question": "If the algea dies will the oxygen level increase or decrease?", "id": "617572396", "answers": [{"text": "decrease"}]}]}, {"background": "Rain dissolves fertilizer in the soil. Runoff carries it away. The fertilizer ends up in bodies of water, from ponds to oceans. The nitrogen is a fertilizer in the water bodies. Since there is a lot of nitrogen it causes algae to grow out of control. Figure below shows a pond covered with algae. Algae may use up so much oxygen in the water that nothing else can grow. Soon, even the algae die out. Decomposers break down the dead tissue and use up all the oxygen in the water. This creates a dead zone. A dead zone is an area in a body of water where nothing grows because there is too little oxygen. There is a large dead zone in the Gulf of Mexico. You can see it Figure below .", "situation": "Mark had been fishing all morning and only caught one fish. He was disappointed because he remembers catching a lot of fish here as a child. There was a lot more algae than back then but other wise the area looked pretty much the same, dotted with lots of small farms.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the pond able to support more or less algae than in the past?", "id": "1606183149", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "White blood cells also make chemicals that cause a fever. A fever is a higher-than-normal body temperature. Normal human body temperature is 98.6\u00b0F (37\u00b0C). Most bacteria and viruses that infect people reproduce fastest at this temperature. When the temperature is higher, the pathogens cannot reproduce as fast, so the body raises the temperature to kill them. A fever also causes the immune system to make more white blood cells. In these ways, a fever helps the body fight infection.", "situation": "Ben was feeling tired and ache all day so he decided to go to bed. When Ben woke  up he felt even worse and his head felt hot. Ben went to the doctor who told him he had a fever and should get plenty of rest.", "qas": [{"question": "Was Ben's temperature above or below 98.6 degrees F?", "id": "613944009", "answers": [{"text": "above"}]}]}, {"background": "White blood cells also make chemicals that cause a fever. A fever is a higher-than-normal body temperature. Normal human body temperature is 98.6\u00b0F (37\u00b0C). Most bacteria and viruses that infect people reproduce fastest at this temperature. When the temperature is higher, the pathogens cannot reproduce as fast, so the body raises the temperature to kill them. A fever also causes the immune system to make more white blood cells. In these ways, a fever helps the body fight infection.", "situation": "Ben was feeling tired and ache all day so he decided to go to bed. When Ben woke  up he felt even worse and his head felt hot. Ben went to the doctor who told him he had a virus that had caused a fever and he should get plenty of rest.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the virus reproducing faster or slower?", "id": "1019613891", "answers": [{"text": "slower"}]}]}, {"background": "White blood cells also make chemicals that cause a fever. A fever is a higher-than-normal body temperature. Normal human body temperature is 98.6\u00b0F (37\u00b0C). Most bacteria and viruses that infect people reproduce fastest at this temperature. When the temperature is higher, the pathogens cannot reproduce as fast, so the body raises the temperature to kill them. A fever also causes the immune system to make more white blood cells. In these ways, a fever helps the body fight infection.", "situation": "Ben was feeling tired and ache all day so he decided to go to bed. When Ben woke  up he felt even worse and his head felt hot. Ben went to the doctor who told him he had a virus that had caused a fever and he should get plenty of rest.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the fever helping or hurting the virus?", "id": "839651937", "answers": [{"text": "hurting"}]}]}, {"background": "White blood cells also make chemicals that cause a fever. A fever is a higher-than-normal body temperature. Normal human body temperature is 98.6\u00b0F (37\u00b0C). Most bacteria and viruses that infect people reproduce fastest at this temperature. When the temperature is higher, the pathogens cannot reproduce as fast, so the body raises the temperature to kill them. A fever also causes the immune system to make more white blood cells. In these ways, a fever helps the body fight infection.", "situation": "Ben was feeling tired and ache all day so he decided to go to bed. When Ben woke  up he felt even worse and his head felt hot. Ben went to the doctor who told him he had a virus that had caused a fever and he should get plenty of rest.", "qas": [{"question": "Did Ben have more or less white blood cells?", "id": "823136787", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "White blood cells also make chemicals that cause a fever. A fever is a higher-than-normal body temperature. Normal human body temperature is 98.6\u00b0F (37\u00b0C). Most bacteria and viruses that infect people reproduce fastest at this temperature. When the temperature is higher, the pathogens cannot reproduce as fast, so the body raises the temperature to kill them. A fever also causes the immune system to make more white blood cells. In these ways, a fever helps the body fight infection.", "situation": "Ann had not been feeling well for several days. When she woke up this morning she had a fever. She went to the doctors and was told she had the flu and should rest.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Ann's temerature above or below 98.6\u00b0F?", "id": "2242705965", "answers": [{"text": "above"}]}]}, {"background": "White blood cells also make chemicals that cause a fever. A fever is a higher-than-normal body temperature. Normal human body temperature is 98.6\u00b0F (37\u00b0C). Most bacteria and viruses that infect people reproduce fastest at this temperature. When the temperature is higher, the pathogens cannot reproduce as fast, so the body raises the temperature to kill them. A fever also causes the immune system to make more white blood cells. In these ways, a fever helps the body fight infection.", "situation": "Ann had not been feeling well for several days. When she woke up this morning she had a fever. She went to the doctors and was told she had the flu and should rest.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Ann's temerature higher or lower than yesterday?", "id": "1848049087", "answers": [{"text": "higher"}]}]}, {"background": "White blood cells also make chemicals that cause a fever. A fever is a higher-than-normal body temperature. Normal human body temperature is 98.6\u00b0F (37\u00b0C). Most bacteria and viruses that infect people reproduce fastest at this temperature. When the temperature is higher, the pathogens cannot reproduce as fast, so the body raises the temperature to kill them. A fever also causes the immune system to make more white blood cells. In these ways, a fever helps the body fight infection.", "situation": "Ann had not been feeling well for several days. When she woke up this morning she had a fever. She went to the doctors and was told she had the flu virus and should rest.", "qas": [{"question": "What is Ann's body fighting??", "id": "3323131749", "answers": [{"text": "virus"}]}]}, {"background": "White blood cells also make chemicals that cause a fever. A fever is a higher-than-normal body temperature. Normal human body temperature is 98.6\u00b0F (37\u00b0C). Most bacteria and viruses that infect people reproduce fastest at this temperature. When the temperature is higher, the pathogens cannot reproduce as fast, so the body raises the temperature to kill them. A fever also causes the immune system to make more white blood cells. In these ways, a fever helps the body fight infection.", "situation": "Ann had not been feeling well for several days. When she woke up this morning she had a fever. She went to the doctors and was told she had the flu virus and should rest.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Ann's body making more or less white blood cells?", "id": "1647181768", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "White blood cells also make chemicals that cause a fever. A fever is a higher-than-normal body temperature. Normal human body temperature is 98.6\u00b0F (37\u00b0C). Most bacteria and viruses that infect people reproduce fastest at this temperature. When the temperature is higher, the pathogens cannot reproduce as fast, so the body raises the temperature to kill them. A fever also causes the immune system to make more white blood cells. In these ways, a fever helps the body fight infection.", "situation": "Ann had not been feeling well since yesterday. When she woke up this morning she had a fever. She went to the doctors and was told she had the flu virus and should rest.", "qas": [{"question": "When was the virus reproducing fastest?", "id": "3315268598", "answers": [{"text": "yesterday"}]}]}, {"background": "White blood cells also make chemicals that cause a fever. A fever is a higher-than-normal body temperature. Normal human body temperature is 98.6\u00b0F (37\u00b0C). Most bacteria and viruses that infect people reproduce fastest at this temperature. When the temperature is higher, the pathogens cannot reproduce as fast, so the body raises the temperature to kill them. A fever also causes the immune system to make more white blood cells. In these ways, a fever helps the body fight infection.", "situation": "Ann had not been feeling well since yesterday. When she woke up this morning she had a fever. She went to the doctors and was told she had the flu virus and should rest.", "qas": [{"question": "When was the virus reproducing slowest?", "id": "3326540813", "answers": [{"text": "this morning"}]}]}, {"background": "White blood cells also make chemicals that cause a fever. A fever is a higher-than-normal body temperature. Normal human body temperature is 98.6\u00b0F (37\u00b0C). Most bacteria and viruses that infect people reproduce fastest at this temperature. When the temperature is higher, the pathogens cannot reproduce as fast, so the body raises the temperature to kill them. A fever also causes the immune system to make more white blood cells. In these ways, a fever helps the body fight infection.", "situation": "Ann had not been feeling well since yesterday. When she woke up this morning she had a fever. She went to the doctors and was told she had the flu virus and should rest.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Ann's immune system working or not?", "id": "3174497017", "answers": [{"text": "working"}]}]}, {"background": "In most species of birds and mammals, one or both parents care for their offspring. Caring for the young may include making a nest or other shelter. It may also include feeding the young and protecting them from predators. Caring for offspring increases their chances of surviving. Birds called killdeers have an interesting way of protecting their chicks. When a predator gets too close to her nest, a mother killdeer pretends to have a broken wing. The mother walks away from the nest holding her wing as though it were injured ( Figure below ). The predator thinks she is injured and will be easy prey. The mother leads the predator away from the nest and then flies away.", "situation": "Mark was pruning a tree in his yard when he heard the sound of young squirrels. He started to look for the nest but to his surprise he only saw the mother. She was in a nearby tree and the noise he heard was coming from that direction.", "qas": [{"question": "Was Mark hearing the babies or the mother?", "id": "716068698", "answers": [{"text": "the mother"}]}]}, {"background": "In most species of birds and mammals, one or both parents care for their offspring. Caring for the young may include making a nest or other shelter. It may also include feeding the young and protecting them from predators. Caring for offspring increases their chances of surviving. Birds called killdeers have an interesting way of protecting their chicks. When a predator gets too close to her nest, a mother killdeer pretends to have a broken wing. The mother walks away from the nest holding her wing as though it were injured ( Figure below ). The predator thinks she is injured and will be easy prey. The mother leads the predator away from the nest and then flies away.", "situation": "Mark was pruning a tree in his yard when he heard the sound of young squirrels. He started to look for the nest but to his surprise he only saw the mother. She was in a nearby tree and the noise he heard was coming from that direction.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the nest near Mark or the mother?", "id": "2026591606", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "In most species of birds and mammals, one or both parents care for their offspring. Caring for the young may include making a nest or other shelter. It may also include feeding the young and protecting them from predators. Caring for offspring increases their chances of surviving. Birds called killdeers have an interesting way of protecting their chicks. When a predator gets too close to her nest, a mother killdeer pretends to have a broken wing. The mother walks away from the nest holding her wing as though it were injured ( Figure below ). The predator thinks she is injured and will be easy prey. The mother leads the predator away from the nest and then flies away.", "situation": "Mark was pruning a tree in his yard when he heard the sound of young squirrels. He started to look for the nest but to his surprise he only saw the mother. She was in a nearby tree and the noise he heard was coming from that direction.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the mother trying to draw marks attention to or away from her nest?", "id": "3425722990", "answers": [{"text": "away from"}]}]}, {"background": "In most species of birds and mammals, one or both parents care for their offspring. Caring for the young may include making a nest or other shelter. It may also include feeding the young and protecting them from predators. Caring for offspring increases their chances of surviving. Birds called killdeers have an interesting way of protecting their chicks. When a predator gets too close to her nest, a mother killdeer pretends to have a broken wing. The mother walks away from the nest holding her wing as though it were injured ( Figure below ). The predator thinks she is injured and will be easy prey. The mother leads the predator away from the nest and then flies away.", "situation": "Mark was pruning a tree in his yard when he heard the sound of young squirrels. He started to look for the nest but to his surprise he only saw the mother. She was in a nearby tree and the noise he heard was coming from that direction.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the mother safe or in danger", "id": "2114278243", "answers": [{"text": "in danger"}]}]}, {"background": "In most species of birds and mammals, one or both parents care for their offspring. Caring for the young may include making a nest or other shelter. It may also include feeding the young and protecting them from predators. Caring for offspring increases their chances of surviving. Birds called killdeers have an interesting way of protecting their chicks. When a predator gets too close to her nest, a mother killdeer pretends to have a broken wing. The mother walks away from the nest holding her wing as though it were injured ( Figure below ). The predator thinks she is injured and will be easy prey. The mother leads the predator away from the nest and then flies away.", "situation": "As the fox entered the clearing the wild turkey noticed the predator. The hen did not run, instead she folded up her wing and hopped around as if she was injured. The fox changed directions and moved towards her. She continued to hope around making noise until the fox was close. She then flew onto the branch of a near by tree.", "qas": [{"question": "Does the turkey see the fox as a threat or harmless?", "id": "572292395", "answers": [{"text": "threat"}]}]}, {"background": "In most species of birds and mammals, one or both parents care for their offspring. Caring for the young may include making a nest or other shelter. It may also include feeding the young and protecting them from predators. Caring for offspring increases their chances of surviving. Birds called killdeers have an interesting way of protecting their chicks. When a predator gets too close to her nest, a mother killdeer pretends to have a broken wing. The mother walks away from the nest holding her wing as though it were injured ( Figure below ). The predator thinks she is injured and will be easy prey. The mother leads the predator away from the nest and then flies away.", "situation": "As the fox entered the clearing the wild turkey noticed the predator. The hen did not run, instead she folded up her wing and hopped around as if she was injured. The fox changed directions and moved towards her. She continued to hope around making noise until the fox was close. She then flew onto the branch of a near by tree.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the turkey alone or with young?", "id": "454915711", "answers": [{"text": "with young"}]}]}, {"background": "In most species of birds and mammals, one or both parents care for their offspring. Caring for the young may include making a nest or other shelter. It may also include feeding the young and protecting them from predators. Caring for offspring increases their chances of surviving. Birds called killdeers have an interesting way of protecting their chicks. When a predator gets too close to her nest, a mother killdeer pretends to have a broken wing. The mother walks away from the nest holding her wing as though it were injured ( Figure below ). The predator thinks she is injured and will be easy prey. The mother leads the predator away from the nest and then flies away.", "situation": "As the fox entered the clearing the wild turkey noticed the predator. The hen did not run, instead she folded up her wing and hopped around as if she was injured. The fox changed directions and moved towards her. She continued to hope around making noise until the fox was close. She then flew onto the branch of a near by tree.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the turkey injured or faking?", "id": "809858499", "answers": [{"text": "faking"}]}]}, {"background": "In most species of birds and mammals, one or both parents care for their offspring. Caring for the young may include making a nest or other shelter. It may also include feeding the young and protecting them from predators. Caring for offspring increases their chances of surviving. Birds called killdeers have an interesting way of protecting their chicks. When a predator gets too close to her nest, a mother killdeer pretends to have a broken wing. The mother walks away from the nest holding her wing as though it were injured ( Figure below ). The predator thinks she is injured and will be easy prey. The mother leads the predator away from the nest and then flies away.", "situation": "As the fox entered the clearing the wild turkey noticed the predator. The hen did not run, instead she folded up her wing and hopped around as if she was injured. The fox changed directions and moved towards her. She continued to hope around making noise until the fox was close. She then flew onto the branch of a near by tree.", "qas": [{"question": "Why did the fox follow the hen?", "id": "3036312838", "answers": [{"text": "she was injured"}]}]}, {"background": "In most species of birds and mammals, one or both parents care for their offspring. Caring for the young may include making a nest or other shelter. It may also include feeding the young and protecting them from predators. Caring for offspring increases their chances of surviving. Birds called killdeers have an interesting way of protecting their chicks. When a predator gets too close to her nest, a mother killdeer pretends to have a broken wing. The mother walks away from the nest holding her wing as though it were injured ( Figure below ). The predator thinks she is injured and will be easy prey. The mother leads the predator away from the nest and then flies away.", "situation": "As the fox entered the clearing the wild turkey noticed the predator. The hen did not run, instead she folded up her wing and hopped around as if she was injured. The fox changed directions and moved towards her. She continued to hope around making noise until the fox was close. She then flew onto the branch of a near by tree.", "qas": [{"question": "Do turkeys care for their young or abandon them?", "id": "3212213148", "answers": [{"text": "care for their young"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Sue and Ann were both having a glass of ice tea. Sue put 2 cubes of sugar into her tea. Ann decided to use granulated sugar and added the same amount of sugar to her tea. They both gave their tea a stir to dissolve the sugar before enjoying it.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's tea was ready faster.", "id": "2515157685", "answers": [{"text": "Ann"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Sue and Ann were both having a glass of ice tea. Sue put 2 cubes of sugar into her tea. Ann decided to use granulated sugar and added the same amount of sugar to her tea. They both gave their tea a stir to dissolve the sugar before enjoying it.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's tea was ready last?", "id": "279331317", "answers": [{"text": "Sue"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Sue and Ann were both having a glass of ice tea. Sue put 2 cubes of sugar into her tea. Ann decided to use granulated sugar and added the same amount of sugar to her tea. They both gave their tea a stir to dissolve the sugar before enjoying it.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's tea needed to be stirred longer?", "id": "2305902260", "answers": [{"text": "Sue"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Sue and Ann were both having a glass of ice tea. Sue put 2 cubes of sugar into her tea. Ann decided to use granulated sugar and added the same amount of sugar to her tea. They both gave their tea a stir to dissolve the sugar before enjoying it.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's tea needed to be stirred lless?", "id": "1117210192", "answers": [{"text": "Ann"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Jane and Beth both decided to have a glass of ice tea. Beth put a large chunk of ice in her glass then poured the tea while Jane use crushed ice.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose ice has more exposed surface area?", "id": "1497965602", "answers": [{"text": "Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Jane and Beth both decided to have a glass of ice tea. Beth put a large chunk of ice in her glass then poured the tea while Jane use crushed ice.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose ice has less exposed surface area?", "id": "1502553126", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Jane and Beth both decided to have a glass of ice tea. Beth put a large chunk of ice in her glass then poured the tea while Jane use crushed ice.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose ice will melt faster?", "id": "2684559208", "answers": [{"text": "Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Jane and Beth both decided to have a glass of ice tea. Beth put a large chunk of ice in her glass then poured the tea while Jane use crushed ice.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose ice will melt slower?", "id": "2694324095", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Jane and Beth both decided to have a glass of ice tea. Beth put a large chunk of ice in her glass then poured the tea while Jane use crushed ice.", "qas": [{"question": "If Beth breaks up her chunk of ice will it melt slower or faster??", "id": "1594109143", "answers": [{"text": "slower"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Beth, Jane and Ann were making chocolate eggs for their churches Easter sale. They decided to make three batches s of chocolate coating. They all started with a chunk of chocolate that needed to be melted in a double boiler.  Beth and Jane grated their chocolate first. Ann just threw the hole chunk into the double boiler. Beth stirred her chocolate while Jane and Ann let their melt on it's own.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Jane or Ann's chocolate melt faster?", "id": "273841871", "answers": [{"text": "Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Beth, Jane and Ann were making chocolate eggs for their churches Easter sale. They decided to make three batches s of chocolate coating. They all started with a chunk of chocolate that needed to be melted in a double boiler.  Beth and Jane grated their chocolate first. Ann just threw the hole chunk into the double boiler. Beth stirred her chocolate while Jane and Ann let their melt on it's own.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Jane or Beth's chocolate melt faster?", "id": "2421325621", "answers": [{"text": "Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Beth, Jane and Ann were making chocolate eggs for their churches Easter sale. They decided to make three batches s of chocolate coating. They all started with a chunk of chocolate that needed to be melted in a double boiler.  Beth and Jane grated their chocolate first. Ann just threw the hole chunk into the double boiler. Beth stirred her chocolate while Jane and Ann let their melt on it's own.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Beth or Ann's chocolate melt faster?", "id": "283999956", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Beth, Jane and Ann were making chocolate eggs for their churches Easter sale. They decided to make three batches s of chocolate coating. They all started with a chunk of chocolate that needed to be melted in a double boiler.  Beth and Jane grated their chocolate first. Ann just threw the hole chunk into the double boiler. Beth stirred her chocolate while Jane and Ann let their melt on it's own.", "qas": [{"question": "Does Beth or Ann's chocolate have more surface area?", "id": "2559279785", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Beth, Jane and Ann were making chocolate eggs for their churches Easter sale. They decided to make three batches s of chocolate coating. They all started with a chunk of chocolate that needed to be melted in a double boiler.  Beth and Jane grated their chocolate first. Ann just threw the hole chunk into the double boiler. Beth stirred her chocolate while Jane and Ann let their melt on it's own.", "qas": [{"question": "Does Jane or Ann's chocolate have more surface area?", "id": "2545517220", "answers": [{"text": "Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Beth, Jane and Ann were making chocolate eggs for their churches Easter sale. They decided to make three batches s of chocolate coating. They all started with a chunk of chocolate that needed to be melted in a double boiler.  Beth and Jane grated their chocolate first. Ann just threw the hole chunk into the double boiler. Beth stirred her chocolate while Jane and Ann let theirs melt on it's own.", "qas": [{"question": "Would chopping her chocolate make Ann's chocolate melt faster or slower?", "id": "3673983802", "answers": [{"text": "faster"}]}]}, {"background": "Mechanical weathering increases the rate of chemical weathering. As rock breaks into smaller pieces, the surface area of the pieces increases. With more surfaces exposed, there are more places for chemical weathering to occur. Let\u2019s say you wanted to make some hot chocolate on a cold day. It would be hard to get a big chunk of chocolate to dissolve in your milk or hot water. Maybe you could make hot chocolate from some smaller pieces like chocolate chips, but it is much easier to add a powder to your milk. This is because the smaller the pieces are, the more surface area they have. Smaller pieces dissolve more easily.", "situation": "Beth, Jane and Ann were making chocolate eggs for their churches Easter sale. They decided to make three batches s of chocolate coating. They all started with a chunk of chocolate that needed to be melted in a double boiler.  Beth and Jane grated their chocolate first. Ann just threw the hole chunk into the double boiler. Beth stirred her chocolate while Jane and Ann let theirs melt on it's own.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's chocolate will melt the fastest?", "id": "644578986", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "Mark moved from the country to a large city. Since moving to the city he noticed that he was exposed to a lot more smog and other air pollution. When he turned 60 he found out he had lung cancer even though he had never smoked.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Mark's cancer risk higher or lower in the city?", "id": "21700577", "answers": [{"text": "higher"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "Mark moved from the country to a large city. Since moving to the city he noticed that he was exposed to a lot more smog and other air pollution. When he turned 60 he found out he had lung cancer even though he had never smoked.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Mark's cancer risk higher or lower in the country?", "id": "1682055484", "answers": [{"text": "lower"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "Mark moved from the country were he worked in a retail store to a large city were he worked in a factory. Since moving to the city he noticed that he was exposed to a lot more smog and other air pollution. When he turned 60 he found out he had lung cancer even though he had never smoked.", "qas": [{"question": "What contributed to Mark's lung cancer?", "id": "1283994168", "answers": [{"text": "air pollution"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "Mark moved from the country were he worked in a retail store to a large city were he worked in a factory. Since moving to the city he noticed that he was exposed to a lot more smog and other air pollution. When he turned 60 he found out he had lung cancer even though he had never smoked.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Mark at higher or lower risk for heart disease in the city?", "id": "393820695", "answers": [{"text": "higher"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "Mark moved from the country were he worked in a retail store to a large city were he worked in a factory. Since moving to the city he noticed that he was exposed to a lot more smog and other air pollution. When he turned 60 he found out he had lung cancer even though he had never smoked.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Mark at higher or lower risk for heart disease in the country?", "id": "3373415282", "answers": [{"text": "lower"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "The cities smog [problem had been growing worse for years. It seemed like there was more traffic everyday. Mark was thinking about moving out of the city.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Mark at higher risk for lung cancer in the city or country?", "id": "2133986227", "answers": [{"text": "city"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "The cities smog [problem had been growing worse for years. It seemed like there was more traffic everyday. Mark was thinking about moving out of the city.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Mark at lower risk for lung cancer in the city or country?", "id": "1987251045", "answers": [{"text": "country"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "The cities smog [problem had been growing worse for years. It seemed like there was more traffic everyday. Mark was thinking about moving out of the city.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Mark at lower risk for repository diseases in the city or country?", "id": "4115795700", "answers": [{"text": "country"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "The cities smog [problem had been growing worse for years. It seemed like there was more traffic everyday. Mark was thinking about moving out of the city.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Mark at higher risk for repository diseases in the city or country?", "id": "9441090", "answers": [{"text": "city"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "Mark enjoyed walking in the fields and woods near his house. He had walked in the same area as a child and remembered seeing lots of white and brown moths. Now though he did not often see moths. One day while walking he realized that there were several brown moths on a tree after that he noticed them more often he realized that they were just harder to see against the brown trees.", "qas": [{"question": "Which moth was better adapted to the environment?", "id": "1409508386", "answers": [{"text": "brown"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "Mark enjoyed walking in the fields and woods near his house. He had walked in the same area as a child and remembered seeing lots of white and brown moths. Now though he did not often see moths. One day while walking he realized that there were several brown moths on a tree after that he noticed them more often he realized that they were just harder to see against the brown trees.", "qas": [{"question": "Which moth survived?", "id": "2588432765", "answers": [{"text": "brown"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "Mark enjoyed walking in the fields and woods near his house. He had walked in the same area as a child and remembered seeing lots of white and brown moths. Now though he did not often see moths. One day while walking he realized that there were several brown moths on a tree after that he noticed them more often he realized that they were just harder to see against the brown trees.", "qas": [{"question": "Which moth was easier prey?", "id": "313285577", "answers": [{"text": "white"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "Mark enjoyed walking in the fields and woods near his house. He had walked in the same area as a child and remembered seeing lots of white and brown moths. Now though he did not often see moths. One day while walking he realized that there were several brown moths on a tree after that he noticed them more often he realized that they were just harder to see against the brown trees.", "qas": [{"question": "Which moth was easier to see?", "id": "3394395209", "answers": [{"text": "white"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "Mark enjoyed walking in the fields and woods near his house. He had walked in the same area as a child and remembered seeing lots of white and brown moths. Now though he did not often see moths. One day while walking he realized that there were several brown moths on a tree after that he noticed them more often he realized that they were just harder to see against the brown trees.", "qas": [{"question": "Which moth was hader to see?", "id": "1827101652", "answers": [{"text": "brown"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "Mike was sitting in the yard of his new home when he noticed that there were a lot of squirrels in the area. Some of the squirrels were very good at gliding from tree to tree by spreading their legs apart the others often had to run across the ground and then climb another tree. Mark also observed several cats in the area watching carefully as the squirrels scampered across the ground to other trees.", "qas": [{"question": "Which squirrels are most likely to be killed by the cats gliding or nongliding?", "id": "1230403550", "answers": [{"text": "nongliding"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "Mike was sitting in the yard of his new home when he noticed that there were a lot of squirrels in the area. Some of the squirrels were very good at gliding from tree to tree by spreading their legs apart the others often had to run across the ground and then climb another tree. Mark also observed several cats in the area watching carefully as the squirrels scampered across the ground to other trees.", "qas": [{"question": "Which squirrels are least likely to be killed by the cats gliding or nongliding?", "id": "3219552308", "answers": [{"text": "gliding"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "Mike was sitting in the yard of his new home when he noticed that there were a lot of squirrels in the area. Some of the squirrels were very good at gliding from tree to tree by spreading their legs apart the others often had to run across the ground and then climb another tree. Mark also observed several cats in the area watching carefully as the squirrels scampered across the ground to other trees.", "qas": [{"question": "Does the gliding squirell have an advantage or a disadvantage?", "id": "2113827220", "answers": [{"text": "advantage"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "Mike was sitting in the yard of his new home when he noticed that there were a lot of squirrels in the area. Some of the squirrels were very good at gliding from tree to tree by spreading their legs apart the others often had to run across the ground and then climb another tree. Mark also observed several cats in the area watching carefully as the squirrels scampered across the ground to other trees.", "qas": [{"question": "Does the nongliding squirell have an advantage or a disadvantage?", "id": "3736826591", "answers": [{"text": "disadvantage"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "Mike was sitting in the yard of his new home when he noticed that there were a lot of squirrels in the area. Some of the squirrels were very good at gliding from tree to tree by spreading their legs apart the others often had to run across the ground and then climb another tree. Mark also observed several cats in the area watching carefully as the squirrels scampered across the ground to other trees.", "qas": [{"question": "In a few years will there be more or less gliding squirrels?", "id": "2157998230", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "Mike was sitting in the yard of his new home when he noticed that there were a lot of squirrels in the area. Some of the squirrels were very good at gliding from tree to tree by spreading their legs apart the others often had to run across the ground and then climb another tree. Mark also observed several cats in the area watching carefully as the squirrels scampered across the ground to other trees.", "qas": [{"question": "In a few years will there be more or less nongliding squirrels?", "id": "3604509153", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "A species of flower was either white and violet. But the plants were dependent on bees to pollinate them and the bees were more attracted to the violet flowers.", "qas": [{"question": "which flower is less likely to be pollenated?", "id": "281088785", "answers": [{"text": "white"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "A species of flower was either white and violet. But the plants were dependent on bees to pollinate them and the bees were more attracted to the violet flowers.", "qas": [{"question": "which flower is more likely to be pollenated?", "id": "275714829", "answers": [{"text": "violet"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "A species of flower was either white and violet. But the plants were dependent on bees to pollinate them and the bees were more attracted to the violet flowers.", "qas": [{"question": "which flower is more likely to pass on it's genes?", "id": "1910969467", "answers": [{"text": "violet"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "A species of flower was either white and violet. But the plants were dependent on bees to pollinate them and the bees were more attracted to the violet flowers.", "qas": [{"question": "which flower is less likely to pass on it's genes?", "id": "229118632", "answers": [{"text": "white"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "A species of flower was either white and violet. But the plants were dependent on bees to pollinate them and the bees were more attracted to the violet flowers.", "qas": [{"question": "Over time wich flower will be more common?", "id": "3533312448", "answers": [{"text": "violet"}]}]}, {"background": "A period of very low rainfall occurred while the Grants were on the islands. The drought resulted in fewer seeds for the finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks were better off. They could eat seeds of all sizes. Therefore, there was more food available to them. Many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. More of the big-beaked birds survived and reproduced. Within just a couple of years, the average beak size in the finches increased. This was clearly evolution by natural selection.", "situation": "A species of flower was either white and violet. But the plants were dependent on bees to pollinate them and the bees were more attracted to the violet flowers.", "qas": [{"question": "Over time wich flower will be less common?", "id": "3534229956", "answers": [{"text": "white"}]}]}, {"background": "This law is sometimes paraphrased as \u201cFor every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction.\u201d A very important point to remember is that the two forces are on different objects\u2014never on the same object. It is frequently the case that one of the objects moves as a result of the force applied but the motion of the other object in the opposite direction is not apparent. Consider the situation where an ice skater is standing at the edge of the skating rink holding on to the side rail. If the skater exerts a force on the rail, the rail is held in place with tremendous friction and therefore, will not move in any noticeable way. The skater, on the other hand, had little friction with the ice, and therefore will be accelerated in the direction opposite of her original push. This is the process people use to jump up into the air. The person's feet exert force on the ground and the ground exerts an equal and opposite force on the person's feet. The force on the feet is sufficient to raise the person off the ground. The force on the ground has little effect because the Earth is so large. One of the accelerations is visible but the other is not visible.", "situation": "Mike had spent the morning fishing and decided to head home. When he got to the dock he forgot to tie his boat to the dock before stepping off of it.", "qas": [{"question": "What is exerting a force on the boat?", "id": "2723343004", "answers": [{"text": "Mike"}]}]}, {"background": "This law is sometimes paraphrased as \u201cFor every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction.\u201d A very important point to remember is that the two forces are on different objects\u2014never on the same object. It is frequently the case that one of the objects moves as a result of the force applied but the motion of the other object in the opposite direction is not apparent. Consider the situation where an ice skater is standing at the edge of the skating rink holding on to the side rail. If the skater exerts a force on the rail, the rail is held in place with tremendous friction and therefore, will not move in any noticeable way. The skater, on the other hand, had little friction with the ice, and therefore will be accelerated in the direction opposite of her original push. This is the process people use to jump up into the air. The person's feet exert force on the ground and the ground exerts an equal and opposite force on the person's feet. The force on the feet is sufficient to raise the person off the ground. The force on the ground has little effect because the Earth is so large. One of the accelerations is visible but the other is not visible.", "situation": "Mike had spent the morning fishing and decided to head home. When he got to the dock he forgot to tie his boat to the dock before stepping off of it.", "qas": [{"question": "What is exerting a force on Mike?", "id": "4184271131", "answers": [{"text": "boat"}]}]}, {"background": "This law is sometimes paraphrased as \u201cFor every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction.\u201d A very important point to remember is that the two forces are on different objects\u2014never on the same object. It is frequently the case that one of the objects moves as a result of the force applied but the motion of the other object in the opposite direction is not apparent. Consider the situation where an ice skater is standing at the edge of the skating rink holding on to the side rail. If the skater exerts a force on the rail, the rail is held in place with tremendous friction and therefore, will not move in any noticeable way. The skater, on the other hand, had little friction with the ice, and therefore will be accelerated in the direction opposite of her original push. This is the process people use to jump up into the air. The person's feet exert force on the ground and the ground exerts an equal and opposite force on the person's feet. The force on the feet is sufficient to raise the person off the ground. The force on the ground has little effect because the Earth is so large. One of the accelerations is visible but the other is not visible.", "situation": "Mike had spent the morning fishing and decided to head home. When he got to the dock he forgot to tie his boat to the dock before stepping off of it.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the boat move towards or away from Mike?", "id": "175369657", "answers": [{"text": "away"}]}]}, {"background": "This law is sometimes paraphrased as \u201cFor every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction.\u201d A very important point to remember is that the two forces are on different objects\u2014never on the same object. It is frequently the case that one of the objects moves as a result of the force applied but the motion of the other object in the opposite direction is not apparent. Consider the situation where an ice skater is standing at the edge of the skating rink holding on to the side rail. If the skater exerts a force on the rail, the rail is held in place with tremendous friction and therefore, will not move in any noticeable way. The skater, on the other hand, had little friction with the ice, and therefore will be accelerated in the direction opposite of her original push. This is the process people use to jump up into the air. The person's feet exert force on the ground and the ground exerts an equal and opposite force on the person's feet. The force on the feet is sufficient to raise the person off the ground. The force on the ground has little effect because the Earth is so large. One of the accelerations is visible but the other is not visible.", "situation": "Mike had spent the morning fishing and decided to head home. When he got to the dock he forgot to tie his boat to the dock before stepping off of it.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Mike move towards or away from the boat?", "id": "150269369", "answers": [{"text": "away"}]}]}, {"background": "This law is sometimes paraphrased as \u201cFor every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction.\u201d A very important point to remember is that the two forces are on different objects\u2014never on the same object. It is frequently the case that one of the objects moves as a result of the force applied but the motion of the other object in the opposite direction is not apparent. Consider the situation where an ice skater is standing at the edge of the skating rink holding on to the side rail. If the skater exerts a force on the rail, the rail is held in place with tremendous friction and therefore, will not move in any noticeable way. The skater, on the other hand, had little friction with the ice, and therefore will be accelerated in the direction opposite of her original push. This is the process people use to jump up into the air. The person's feet exert force on the ground and the ground exerts an equal and opposite force on the person's feet. The force on the feet is sufficient to raise the person off the ground. The force on the ground has little effect because the Earth is so large. One of the accelerations is visible but the other is not visible.", "situation": "Matt had been fishing in his boat all morning and decided it was time to go for a swim. He stood on the edge of the boat and dived into the water. As he pushed of the boat he went forward into the water.", "qas": [{"question": "When Matt pushed off the boat did the boat move or stay stationary?", "id": "175179856", "answers": [{"text": "move"}]}]}, {"background": "This law is sometimes paraphrased as \u201cFor every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction.\u201d A very important point to remember is that the two forces are on different objects\u2014never on the same object. It is frequently the case that one of the objects moves as a result of the force applied but the motion of the other object in the opposite direction is not apparent. Consider the situation where an ice skater is standing at the edge of the skating rink holding on to the side rail. If the skater exerts a force on the rail, the rail is held in place with tremendous friction and therefore, will not move in any noticeable way. The skater, on the other hand, had little friction with the ice, and therefore will be accelerated in the direction opposite of her original push. This is the process people use to jump up into the air. The person's feet exert force on the ground and the ground exerts an equal and opposite force on the person's feet. The force on the feet is sufficient to raise the person off the ground. The force on the ground has little effect because the Earth is so large. One of the accelerations is visible but the other is not visible.", "situation": "Matt had been fishing in his boat all morning and decided it was time to go for a swim. He stood on the edge of the boat and dived into the water. As he pushed of the boat he went forward into the water.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the boat move in the same direction as Matt or away from him?", "id": "4034463483", "answers": [{"text": "away from him"}]}]}, {"background": "This law is sometimes paraphrased as \u201cFor every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction.\u201d A very important point to remember is that the two forces are on different objects\u2014never on the same object. It is frequently the case that one of the objects moves as a result of the force applied but the motion of the other object in the opposite direction is not apparent. Consider the situation where an ice skater is standing at the edge of the skating rink holding on to the side rail. If the skater exerts a force on the rail, the rail is held in place with tremendous friction and therefore, will not move in any noticeable way. The skater, on the other hand, had little friction with the ice, and therefore will be accelerated in the direction opposite of her original push. This is the process people use to jump up into the air. The person's feet exert force on the ground and the ground exerts an equal and opposite force on the person's feet. The force on the feet is sufficient to raise the person off the ground. The force on the ground has little effect because the Earth is so large. One of the accelerations is visible but the other is not visible.", "situation": "Matt had been fishing in his boat all morning and decided it was time to go for a swim. He stood on the edge of the boat and dived into the water. As he pushed of the boat he went forward into the water.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the force on the boat less than or equal to the force on Matt?", "id": "4207478590", "answers": [{"text": "equal"}]}]}, {"background": "This law is sometimes paraphrased as \u201cFor every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction.\u201d A very important point to remember is that the two forces are on different objects\u2014never on the same object. It is frequently the case that one of the objects moves as a result of the force applied but the motion of the other object in the opposite direction is not apparent. Consider the situation where an ice skater is standing at the edge of the skating rink holding on to the side rail. If the skater exerts a force on the rail, the rail is held in place with tremendous friction and therefore, will not move in any noticeable way. The skater, on the other hand, had little friction with the ice, and therefore will be accelerated in the direction opposite of her original push. This is the process people use to jump up into the air. The person's feet exert force on the ground and the ground exerts an equal and opposite force on the person's feet. The force on the feet is sufficient to raise the person off the ground. The force on the ground has little effect because the Earth is so large. One of the accelerations is visible but the other is not visible.", "situation": "Matt had been fishing in his boat all morning and decided it was time to go for a swim. He stood on the edge of the boat and dived into the water. As he pushed of the boat he went forward into the water.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the force on Matt less than or equal to the force on the boat?", "id": "4188342078", "answers": [{"text": "equal"}]}]}, {"background": "This law is sometimes paraphrased as \u201cFor every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction.\u201d A very important point to remember is that the two forces are on different objects\u2014never on the same object. It is frequently the case that one of the objects moves as a result of the force applied but the motion of the other object in the opposite direction is not apparent. Consider the situation where an ice skater is standing at the edge of the skating rink holding on to the side rail. If the skater exerts a force on the rail, the rail is held in place with tremendous friction and therefore, will not move in any noticeable way. The skater, on the other hand, had little friction with the ice, and therefore will be accelerated in the direction opposite of her original push. This is the process people use to jump up into the air. The person's feet exert force on the ground and the ground exerts an equal and opposite force on the person's feet. The force on the feet is sufficient to raise the person off the ground. The force on the ground has little effect because the Earth is so large. One of the accelerations is visible but the other is not visible.", "situation": "Matt had been fishing in his boat all morning and decided it was time to go for a swim. He stood on the edge of the boat and dived into the water. As he pushed of the boat he went forward into the water.", "qas": [{"question": "What exerted force on the boat?", "id": "3575970599", "answers": [{"text": "Matt"}]}]}, {"background": "This law is sometimes paraphrased as \u201cFor every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction.\u201d A very important point to remember is that the two forces are on different objects\u2014never on the same object. It is frequently the case that one of the objects moves as a result of the force applied but the motion of the other object in the opposite direction is not apparent. Consider the situation where an ice skater is standing at the edge of the skating rink holding on to the side rail. If the skater exerts a force on the rail, the rail is held in place with tremendous friction and therefore, will not move in any noticeable way. The skater, on the other hand, had little friction with the ice, and therefore will be accelerated in the direction opposite of her original push. This is the process people use to jump up into the air. The person's feet exert force on the ground and the ground exerts an equal and opposite force on the person's feet. The force on the feet is sufficient to raise the person off the ground. The force on the ground has little effect because the Earth is so large. One of the accelerations is visible but the other is not visible.", "situation": "Matt had been fishing in his boat all morning and decided it was time to go for a swim. He stood on the edge of the boat and dived into the water. As he pushed of the boat he went forward into the water.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the a lot or little friction with the water?", "id": "2971730279", "answers": [{"text": "little"}]}]}, {"background": "Other pathogens spread when they get on objects or surfaces. A fungus may spread in this way. For example, you can pick up the fungus that causes athlete\u2019s foot by wearing shoes that an infected person has worn. You can also pick up this fungus from the floor of a public shower or other damp areas. After acne, athlete\u2019s foot is the most common skin disease in the United States. Therefore, the chance of coming in contact with the fungus in one of these ways is fairly high.", "situation": "Jane has only been working at a daycare for a few months. But she has already noticed that there always seems to be at least one sick child. She often jokes that the children not only share toys they also share colds.", "qas": [{"question": "What is Jane likely to get if she touches the toys?", "id": "563547890", "answers": [{"text": "colds"}]}]}, {"background": "Other pathogens spread when they get on objects or surfaces. A fungus may spread in this way. For example, you can pick up the fungus that causes athlete\u2019s foot by wearing shoes that an infected person has worn. You can also pick up this fungus from the floor of a public shower or other damp areas. After acne, athlete\u2019s foot is the most common skin disease in the United States. Therefore, the chance of coming in contact with the fungus in one of these ways is fairly high.", "situation": "Jane has only been working at a daycare for a few months. But she has already noticed that there always seems to be at least one sick child. She often jokes that the children not only share toys they also share colds.", "qas": [{"question": "What surface is likely to have viruses on it?", "id": "3758230834", "answers": [{"text": "toys"}]}]}, {"background": "Pollutants also affect the atmosphere through their contribution to global warming. Global warming is an increase in the Earth\u2019s temperature. It is thought to be caused mostly by the increase of greenhouse gases like carbon dioxide. Greenhouse gases can be released by factories that burn fossil fuels. Over the past 20 years, burning fossil fuels has produced about three-quarters of the carbon dioxide from human activity. The rest of the carbon dioxide in the atmosphere is there because of deforestation, or cutting down trees ( Figure below ). Trees absorb carbon dioxide during cellular respiration, so when trees are cut down, they cannot remove carbon dioxide from the air.", "situation": "Sue is very passionate about protecting the earth and wildlife. It makes her sad to see people cutting down forest to build homes or driving huge cars that burn lots of gas. This year she is planning or organizing a community project to plant more trees in her town.", "qas": [{"question": "What reduces carbondioxide in the air?", "id": "3201657384", "answers": [{"text": "trees"}]}]}, {"background": "Pollutants also affect the atmosphere through their contribution to global warming. Global warming is an increase in the Earth\u2019s temperature. It is thought to be caused mostly by the increase of greenhouse gases like carbon dioxide. Greenhouse gases can be released by factories that burn fossil fuels. Over the past 20 years, burning fossil fuels has produced about three-quarters of the carbon dioxide from human activity. The rest of the carbon dioxide in the atmosphere is there because of deforestation, or cutting down trees ( Figure below ). Trees absorb carbon dioxide during cellular respiration, so when trees are cut down, they cannot remove carbon dioxide from the air.", "situation": "Sue is very passionate about protecting the earth and wildlife. It makes her sad to see people cutting down forest to build homes or driving huge cars that burn lots of gas. This year she is planning or organizing a community project to plant more trees in her town.", "qas": [{"question": "What increases carbondioxide in the air?", "id": "2529258234", "answers": [{"text": "cars that burn lots of gas"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "Joe wanted to drink his bottle of juice but it was warm. Joe decided to toss it in the freezer for a few minutes to chill. A few minutes later his friend Mike came over to play video games and mike forgot about his juice for several hours.", "qas": [{"question": "Will there be more or less room in the bottle when Mike gets it out of the freezer?", "id": "1026570583", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "Joe wanted to drink his bottle of juice but it was warm. Joe decided to toss it in the freezer for a few minutes to chill. A few minutes later his friend Mike came over to play video games and mike forgot about his juice for several hours.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the tea expand or contract in the freezer?", "id": "340012234", "answers": [{"text": "expand"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "Joe wanted to drink his bottle of juice but it was warm. Joe decided to toss it in the freezer for a few minutes to chill. A few minutes later his friend Mike came over to play video games and mike forgot about his juice for several hours.", "qas": [{"question": "Does the tea get bigger or smaller as it freezes?", "id": "1698770233", "answers": [{"text": "bigger"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "When Mary go home she brought her grocery in but forgot to grab the bottled water from the trunk. When she went out to get it in the morning it had frozen and the bottles were bulging.", "qas": [{"question": "was the temerature overnight above or below 32 degrees farienheit. ", "id": "2306613513", "answers": [{"text": "below"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "When Mary go home she brought her grocery in but forgot to grab the bottled water from the trunk. When she went out to get it in the morning it had frozen and the bottles were bulging.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the pressure inside the bottles higher in the morning or afternoon", "id": "3935707846", "answers": [{"text": "morning"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "When Mary go home she brought her grocery in but forgot to grab the bottled water from the trunk. When she went out to get it in the morning it had frozen and the bottles were bulging.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the pressure inside the bottles lower in the morning or afternoon", "id": "3389661816", "answers": [{"text": "afternoon"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "When Mary go home she brought her grocery in but forgot to grab the bottled water from the trunk. When she went out to get it in the morning it had frozen and the bottles were bulging.", "qas": [{"question": "was the pressure increasing or decreasing overnight?", "id": "3288079492", "answers": [{"text": "increasing"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "When Mary go home she brought her grocery in but forgot to grab the bottled water from the trunk. When she went out to get it in the morning it had frozen and the bottles were bulging.", "qas": [{"question": "If Mary took the bottles inside would the pressure increase or decrease?", "id": "586228539", "answers": [{"text": "decrease"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "When Mary go home in the afternoon she brought her grocery in but forgot to grab the bottled water from the trunk. When she went out to get it in the morning it had frozen and the bottles were bulging.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the volume of the water higher  in the afternoon or morning?", "id": "1932862983", "answers": [{"text": "morning"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "When Mary go home in the afternoon she brought her grocery in but forgot to grab the bottled water from the trunk. When she went out to get it in the morning it had frozen and the bottles were bulging.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the volume of the water lower in the afternoon or morning?", "id": "812656025", "answers": [{"text": "afternoon"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "When Mary go home in the afternoon she brought her grocery in but forgot to grab the bottled water from the trunk. When she went out to get it in the morning it had frozen and the bottles were bulging.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the density of the water lower in the afternoon or morning?", "id": "1474045441", "answers": [{"text": "morning"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "When Mary go home in the afternoon she brought her grocery in but forgot to grab the bottled water from the trunk. When she went out to get it in the morning it had frozen and the bottles were bulging.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the density of the water higher in the afternoon or morning?", "id": "2080384591", "answers": [{"text": "afternoon"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "When Mary go home in the afternoon she brought her grocery in but forgot to grab the bottled water from the trunk. When she went out to get it in the morning it had frozen and the bottles were bulging.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the water expand or contract overnight?", "id": "2837454558", "answers": [{"text": "expand"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "The was a major winter storm last week along with freezing temperatures the storm knocked out the power where Bob lives. Without power Bob had no heat. He went to stay with family for a few days until the power could be restored. Unfortunately when he returned he found that one of his water pipes had burst and flooded his basement.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the water expand or contract when the tempeture dropped.", "id": "1252611532", "answers": [{"text": "expand"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "The was a major winter storm last week along with freezing temperatures the storm knocked out the power where Bob lives. Without power Bob had no heat. He went to stay with family for a few days until the power could be restored. Unfortunately when he returned he found that one of his water pipes had burst and flooded his basement.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the water expand or contract when the tempeture rose.", "id": "1239700631", "answers": [{"text": "contract"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "The was a major winter storm last week along with freezing temperatures the storm knocked out the power where Bob lives. Without power Bob had no heat. He went to stay with family for a few days until the power could be restored. Unfortunately when he returned he found that one of his water pipes had burst and flooded his basement.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the pressure in the pipe increase or decrease when the tempeture rose.", "id": "443505339", "answers": [{"text": "decrease"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "The was a major winter storm last week along with freezing temperatures the storm knocked out the power where Bob lives. Without power Bob had no heat. He went to stay with family for a few days until the power could be restored. Unfortunately when he returned he found that one of his water pipes had burst and flooded his basement.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the pressure in the pipe increase or decrease when the tempeture dropped?", "id": "766598145", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "Mark was getting all the supplies he needed for his big Christmas party. He opened the trunk and sat 2 cases of beer in the garage while he carried the food into the kitchen.  Bob put the food away and started dinner. When Mark wen out to the garage the next morning he saw that the beer can's had exploded and there was beer everywhere.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the beer expand or contract in the cans.", "id": "1592413557", "answers": [{"text": "expand"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "Mark hurried in from the cold he had gone shopping for all the supplies he needed for his big Christmas party. He opened the trunk and sat 2 cases of beer in the garage while he carried the food into the kitchen.  Bob put the food away and started dinner. When Mark wen out to the garage the next morning he saw that the beer can's had exploded and there was beer everywhere.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the weather hot or cold over night.", "id": "609704287", "answers": [{"text": "cold"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "Mark hurried in from the cold he had gone shopping for all the supplies he needed for his big Christmas party. He opened the trunk and sat 2 cases of beer in the garage while he carried the food into the kitchen.  Bob put the food away and started dinner. When Mark wen out to the garage the next morning he saw that the beer can's had exploded and there was beer everywhere.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the volume of beer increase or decrease overnight?", "id": "2337038122", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "Mark hurried in from the cold he had gone shopping for all the supplies he needed for his big Christmas party. He opened the trunk and sat 2 cases of beer in the garage while he carried the food into the kitchen.  Bob put the food away and started dinner. When Mark wen out to the garage the next morning he saw that the beer can's had exploded and there was beer everywhere.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the pressure increase or decrease inside of the can?", "id": "1450598310", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "Mark hurried in from the cold he had gone shopping for all the supplies he needed for his big Christmas party. He opened the trunk and sat 2 cases of beer in the garage while he carried the food into the kitchen.  Bob put the food away and started dinner. When Mark went out to the garage the next morning he saw that the beer can's had exploded and there was beer everywhere.", "qas": [{"question": "What made the beer expand?", "id": "367154446", "answers": [{"text": "cold"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "Mark hurried in from the cold he had gone shopping for all the supplies he needed for his big Christmas party. He opened the trunk and sat 2 cases of beer in the garage while he carried the food into the kitchen.  Bob put the food away and started dinner. When Mark went out to the garage the next morning he saw that the beer can's had exploded and there was beer everywhere.", "qas": [{"question": "What made the beer volume increase?", "id": "638343312", "answers": [{"text": "cold"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "Mark hurried in from the cold he had gone shopping for all the supplies he needed for his big Christmas party. He opened the trunk and sat 2 cases of beer in the garage while he carried the food into the kitchen.  Bob put the food away and started dinner. When Mark went out to the garage the next morning he saw that the beer can's had exploded and there was beer everywhere.", "qas": [{"question": "Was heat or cold added to the beer cans?", "id": "3676461485", "answers": [{"text": "cold"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "Mark hurried in from the cold he had gone shopping for all the supplies he needed for his big Christmas party. He opened the trunk and sat 2 cases of beer in the garage while he carried the food into the kitchen.  Bob put the food away and started dinner. When Mark went out to the garage the next morning he saw that the beer can's had exploded and there was beer everywhere.", "qas": [{"question": "Did heat or cold incease the beer's volume?", "id": "3957086979", "answers": [{"text": "cold"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "Mark hurried in from the cold he had gone shopping for all the supplies he needed for his big Christmas party. He opened the trunk and sat 2 cases of beer in the garage while he carried the food into the kitchen.  Bob put the food away and started dinner. When Mark went out to the garage the next morning he saw that the beer can's had exploded and there was beer everywhere.", "qas": [{"question": "Did heat or cold increase the pressure in the cans?", "id": "3634847259", "answers": [{"text": "cold"}]}]}, {"background": "This is how ice wedging works. When liquid water changes into solid ice, it increases in volume. You see this when you fill an ice cube tray with water and put it in the freezer. The ice cubes go to a higher level in the tray than the water. You also may have seen this if you put a can of soda into the freezer so that it cools down quickly. If you leave the can in the freezer too long, the liquid expands so much that it bends or pops the can. (For the record, water is very unusual. Most substances get smaller when they change from a liquid to a solid.)", "situation": "Mark hurried in from the cold he had gone shopping for all the supplies he needed for his big Christmas party. He opened the trunk and sat 2 cases of beer in the garage while he carried the food into the kitchen.  Bob put the food away and started dinner. When Mark went out to the garage the next morning he saw that the beer can's had exploded and there was beer everywhere.", "qas": [{"question": "As the temperature rose inthe morning did the beer expand or contract??", "id": "2625332704", "answers": [{"text": "contract"}]}]}, {"background": "The earliest members of the human species evolved around 200,000 years ago in Africa. Early humans lived in small populations of nomadic hunters and gatherers. Human beings remained in Africa until about 40,000 years ago. After that, they spread throughout Europe, Asia, and Australia. By 10,000 years ago, the first human beings colonized the Americas. During this long period of time, the total number of human beings increased very slowly. Birth rates were fairly high but so were death rates, producing low rates of population growth.", "situation": "Bill lives in the country. Over the last few years he has noticed that there are way more feral cats running around than there used to be. In fact he usually sees several litters of kittens each year. On the plus side he has noticed that there are a lot fewer mice getting into things in his barn or getting into his house.", "qas": [{"question": "Which population is experiencing growth?", "id": "1203716993", "answers": [{"text": "cats"}]}]}, {"background": "The earliest members of the human species evolved around 200,000 years ago in Africa. Early humans lived in small populations of nomadic hunters and gatherers. Human beings remained in Africa until about 40,000 years ago. After that, they spread throughout Europe, Asia, and Australia. By 10,000 years ago, the first human beings colonized the Americas. During this long period of time, the total number of human beings increased very slowly. Birth rates were fairly high but so were death rates, producing low rates of population growth.", "situation": "Bill lives in the country. Over the last few years he has noticed that there are way more feral cats running around than there used to be. In fact he usually sees several litters of kittens each year. On the plus side he has noticed that there are a lot fewer mice getting into things in his barn or getting into his house.", "qas": [{"question": "Which population is experiencing a decline?", "id": "285623355", "answers": [{"text": "mice"}]}]}, {"background": "The earliest members of the human species evolved around 200,000 years ago in Africa. Early humans lived in small populations of nomadic hunters and gatherers. Human beings remained in Africa until about 40,000 years ago. After that, they spread throughout Europe, Asia, and Australia. By 10,000 years ago, the first human beings colonized the Americas. During this long period of time, the total number of human beings increased very slowly. Birth rates were fairly high but so were death rates, producing low rates of population growth.", "situation": "Bill lives in the country. Over the last few years he has noticed that there are way more feral cats running around than there used to be. In fact he usually sees several litters of kittens each year. On the plus side he has noticed that there are a lot fewer mice getting into things in his barn or getting into his house.", "qas": [{"question": "Which population is experiencing more births than deaths?", "id": "4179708329", "answers": [{"text": "cats"}]}]}, {"background": "The earliest members of the human species evolved around 200,000 years ago in Africa. Early humans lived in small populations of nomadic hunters and gatherers. Human beings remained in Africa until about 40,000 years ago. After that, they spread throughout Europe, Asia, and Australia. By 10,000 years ago, the first human beings colonized the Americas. During this long period of time, the total number of human beings increased very slowly. Birth rates were fairly high but so were death rates, producing low rates of population growth.", "situation": "Bill lives in the country. Over the last few years he has noticed that there are way more feral cats running around than there used to be. In fact he usually sees several litters of kittens each year. On the plus side he has noticed that there are a lot fewer mice getting into things in his barn or getting into his house.", "qas": [{"question": "Which population is experiencing less deaths than births?", "id": "4168829357", "answers": [{"text": "cats"}]}]}, {"background": "The earliest members of the human species evolved around 200,000 years ago in Africa. Early humans lived in small populations of nomadic hunters and gatherers. Human beings remained in Africa until about 40,000 years ago. After that, they spread throughout Europe, Asia, and Australia. By 10,000 years ago, the first human beings colonized the Americas. During this long period of time, the total number of human beings increased very slowly. Birth rates were fairly high but so were death rates, producing low rates of population growth.", "situation": "Bill lives in the country. Over the last few years he has noticed that there are way more feral cats running around than there used to be. In fact he usually sees several litters of kittens each year. On the plus side he has noticed that there are a lot fewer mice getting into things in his barn or getting into his house.", "qas": [{"question": "Which population is experiencing more deaths than births?", "id": "4164766121", "answers": [{"text": "mice"}]}]}, {"background": "The earliest members of the human species evolved around 200,000 years ago in Africa. Early humans lived in small populations of nomadic hunters and gatherers. Human beings remained in Africa until about 40,000 years ago. After that, they spread throughout Europe, Asia, and Australia. By 10,000 years ago, the first human beings colonized the Americas. During this long period of time, the total number of human beings increased very slowly. Birth rates were fairly high but so were death rates, producing low rates of population growth.", "situation": "Bill lives in the country. Over the last few years he has noticed that there are way more feral cats running around than there used to be. In fact he usually sees several litters of kittens each year. On the plus side he has noticed that there are a lot fewer mice getting into things in his barn or getting into his house.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the mice population increase or decrease as the cat population increases?", "id": "1014321449", "answers": [{"text": "decrease"}]}]}, {"background": "The earliest members of the human species evolved around 200,000 years ago in Africa. Early humans lived in small populations of nomadic hunters and gatherers. Human beings remained in Africa until about 40,000 years ago. After that, they spread throughout Europe, Asia, and Australia. By 10,000 years ago, the first human beings colonized the Americas. During this long period of time, the total number of human beings increased very slowly. Birth rates were fairly high but so were death rates, producing low rates of population growth.", "situation": "Bill lives in the country. Over the last few years he has noticed that there are way more feral cats running around than there used to be. In fact he usually sees several litters of kittens each year. On the plus side he has noticed that there are a lot fewer mice getting into things in his barn or getting into his house.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the mice population increase or decrease if the cat poulation decreases?", "id": "3915665574", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "The earliest members of the human species evolved around 200,000 years ago in Africa. Early humans lived in small populations of nomadic hunters and gatherers. Human beings remained in Africa until about 40,000 years ago. After that, they spread throughout Europe, Asia, and Australia. By 10,000 years ago, the first human beings colonized the Americas. During this long period of time, the total number of human beings increased very slowly. Birth rates were fairly high but so were death rates, producing low rates of population growth.", "situation": "Bob lived in an area that was known for its wildlife including deer. Once there had been larger predictors like wolves and mountain lions but they had been extinct in this area for decades. Now the other animals like deer had no natural predators.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the deer populatin increasing or decreasing?", "id": "4099746540", "answers": [{"text": "increasing"}]}]}, {"background": "The earliest members of the human species evolved around 200,000 years ago in Africa. Early humans lived in small populations of nomadic hunters and gatherers. Human beings remained in Africa until about 40,000 years ago. After that, they spread throughout Europe, Asia, and Australia. By 10,000 years ago, the first human beings colonized the Americas. During this long period of time, the total number of human beings increased very slowly. Birth rates were fairly high but so were death rates, producing low rates of population growth.", "situation": "Bob lived in an area that was known for its wildlife including deer. Once there had been larger predictors like wolves and mountain lions but they had been extinct in this area since the last century. Now the other animals like deer had no natural predators. ", "qas": [{"question": "Was the higher or lower in the last century?", "id": "2320051646", "answers": [{"text": "higher"}]}]}, {"background": "The earliest members of the human species evolved around 200,000 years ago in Africa. Early humans lived in small populations of nomadic hunters and gatherers. Human beings remained in Africa until about 40,000 years ago. After that, they spread throughout Europe, Asia, and Australia. By 10,000 years ago, the first human beings colonized the Americas. During this long period of time, the total number of human beings increased very slowly. Birth rates were fairly high but so were death rates, producing low rates of population growth.", "situation": "Bob lived in an area that was known for its wildlife including deer. Once there had been larger predictors like wolves and mountain lions but they had been extinct in this area since the last century. Now the other animals like deer had no natural predators. ", "qas": [{"question": "Was the higher or lower in this century?", "id": "3617533025", "answers": [{"text": "higher"}]}]}, {"background": "The earliest members of the human species evolved around 200,000 years ago in Africa. Early humans lived in small populations of nomadic hunters and gatherers. Human beings remained in Africa until about 40,000 years ago. After that, they spread throughout Europe, Asia, and Australia. By 10,000 years ago, the first human beings colonized the Americas. During this long period of time, the total number of human beings increased very slowly. Birth rates were fairly high but so were death rates, producing low rates of population growth.", "situation": "Bob lived in an area that was known for its wildlife including deer. Once there had been larger predictors like wolves and mountain lions but they had been extinct in this area since the last century. Now the other animals like deer had no natural predators. ", "qas": [{"question": "In what century did more deer die?", "id": "3579128294", "answers": [{"text": "last century"}]}]}, {"background": "The earliest members of the human species evolved around 200,000 years ago in Africa. Early humans lived in small populations of nomadic hunters and gatherers. Human beings remained in Africa until about 40,000 years ago. After that, they spread throughout Europe, Asia, and Australia. By 10,000 years ago, the first human beings colonized the Americas. During this long period of time, the total number of human beings increased very slowly. Birth rates were fairly high but so were death rates, producing low rates of population growth.", "situation": "Bob lived in an area that was known for its wildlife including deer. Once there had been larger predictors like wolves and mountain lions but they had been extinct in this area since the last century. Now the other animals like deer had no natural predators. ", "qas": [{"question": "In what century did the deer population increase this century or last century??", "id": "3406248759", "answers": [{"text": "this century "}]}]}, {"background": "The earliest members of the human species evolved around 200,000 years ago in Africa. Early humans lived in small populations of nomadic hunters and gatherers. Human beings remained in Africa until about 40,000 years ago. After that, they spread throughout Europe, Asia, and Australia. By 10,000 years ago, the first human beings colonized the Americas. During this long period of time, the total number of human beings increased very slowly. Birth rates were fairly high but so were death rates, producing low rates of population growth.", "situation": "Bob lived in an area that was known for its wildlife including deer. Once there had been larger predictors like wolves and mountain lions but they had been extinct in this area since the last century. Now the other animals like deer had no natural predators. ", "qas": [{"question": "In what century was the deer population stable this century or last century??", "id": "1497053826", "answers": [{"text": "last century"}]}]}, {"background": "Natural resources include energy, minerals and other materials. Natural resources may be renewable or non-renewable. Non-renewable resources cannot be replaced. When they're gone, they're gone. Renewable resources can be replaced. They can supply human activities forever. Fossil fuels are crucial for modern human society. Fossil fuels are essential for transportation, industry and agriculture. Renewable energy resources tend to be clean. They emit fewer pollutants and greenhouse gases than fossil fuels. Renewable resources often have other problems. They are more costly and less efficient than fossil fuels. Still, they have many advantages. Research is going into developing renewable resources. Conservation is the best way to increase resource availability. Anyone can conserve! You and your family can. Society can. The world can. Just reduce, reuse, recycle.", "situation": "Where mike lived it was very rural and people heated their homes mainly in two ways. They either burned coal that was mined locally or the used fire wood. Recently some people have started to use solar panels to heat their homes.", "qas": [{"question": "Which heating method uses renewabal energy?", "id": "1272947554", "answers": [{"text": "solar"}]}]}, {"background": "Natural resources include energy, minerals and other materials. Natural resources may be renewable or non-renewable. Non-renewable resources cannot be replaced. When they're gone, they're gone. Renewable resources can be replaced. They can supply human activities forever. Fossil fuels are crucial for modern human society. Fossil fuels are essential for transportation, industry and agriculture. Renewable energy resources tend to be clean. They emit fewer pollutants and greenhouse gases than fossil fuels. Renewable resources often have other problems. They are more costly and less efficient than fossil fuels. Still, they have many advantages. Research is going into developing renewable resources. Conservation is the best way to increase resource availability. Anyone can conserve! You and your family can. Society can. The world can. Just reduce, reuse, recycle.", "situation": "Where mike lived it was very rural and people heated their homes mainly in two ways. They either burned coal that was mined locally or the used fire wood. Recently some people have started to use solar panels to heat their homes.", "qas": [{"question": "Which heating method uses nonrenewabal energy?", "id": "988193965", "answers": [{"text": "coal"}]}]}, {"background": "Natural resources include energy, minerals and other materials. Natural resources may be renewable or non-renewable. Non-renewable resources cannot be replaced. When they're gone, they're gone. Renewable resources can be replaced. They can supply human activities forever. Fossil fuels are crucial for modern human society. Fossil fuels are essential for transportation, industry and agriculture. Renewable energy resources tend to be clean. They emit fewer pollutants and greenhouse gases than fossil fuels. Renewable resources often have other problems. They are more costly and less efficient than fossil fuels. Still, they have many advantages. Research is going into developing renewable resources. Conservation is the best way to increase resource availability. Anyone can conserve! You and your family can. Society can. The world can. Just reduce, reuse, recycle.", "situation": "Where mike lived it was very rural and people heated their homes mainly in two ways. They either burned coal that was mined locally or the used fire wood. Recently some people have started to use solar panels to heat their homes.", "qas": [{"question": "which heating method uses fossil fuel?", "id": "586785155", "answers": [{"text": "coal"}]}]}, {"background": "Natural resources include energy, minerals and other materials. Natural resources may be renewable or non-renewable. Non-renewable resources cannot be replaced. When they're gone, they're gone. Renewable resources can be replaced. They can supply human activities forever. Fossil fuels are crucial for modern human society. Fossil fuels are essential for transportation, industry and agriculture. Renewable energy resources tend to be clean. They emit fewer pollutants and greenhouse gases than fossil fuels. Renewable resources often have other problems. They are more costly and less efficient than fossil fuels. Still, they have many advantages. Research is going into developing renewable resources. Conservation is the best way to increase resource availability. Anyone can conserve! You and your family can. Society can. The world can. Just reduce, reuse, recycle.", "situation": "Where mike lived it was very rural and people heated their homes mainly in two ways. They either burned coal that was mined locally or the used fire wood. Recently some people have started to use solar panels to heat their homes.", "qas": [{"question": "Which is the cleanest energy source?", "id": "3584270477", "answers": [{"text": "solar"}]}]}, {"background": "Natural resources include energy, minerals and other materials. Natural resources may be renewable or non-renewable. Non-renewable resources cannot be replaced. When they're gone, they're gone. Renewable resources can be replaced. They can supply human activities forever. Fossil fuels are crucial for modern human society. Fossil fuels are essential for transportation, industry and agriculture. Renewable energy resources tend to be clean. They emit fewer pollutants and greenhouse gases than fossil fuels. Renewable resources often have other problems. They are more costly and less efficient than fossil fuels. Still, they have many advantages. Research is going into developing renewable resources. Conservation is the best way to increase resource availability. Anyone can conserve! You and your family can. Society can. The world can. Just reduce, reuse, recycle.", "situation": "Where mike lived it was very rural and people heated their homes mainly in two ways. They either burned coal that was mined locally or the used fire wood. Recently some people have started to use solar panels to heat their homes.", "qas": [{"question": "Which energy source will eventually runout?", "id": "1370072015", "answers": [{"text": "coal"}]}]}, {"background": "Natural resources include energy, minerals and other materials. Natural resources may be renewable or non-renewable. Non-renewable resources cannot be replaced. When they're gone, they're gone. Renewable resources can be replaced. They can supply human activities forever. Fossil fuels are crucial for modern human society. Fossil fuels are essential for transportation, industry and agriculture. Renewable energy resources tend to be clean. They emit fewer pollutants and greenhouse gases than fossil fuels. Renewable resources often have other problems. They are more costly and less efficient than fossil fuels. Still, they have many advantages. Research is going into developing renewable resources. Conservation is the best way to increase resource availability. Anyone can conserve! You and your family can. Society can. The world can. Just reduce, reuse, recycle.", "situation": "Where mike lived it was very rural and people heated their homes mainly in two ways. They either burned coal that was mined locally or the used fire wood. Recently some people have started to use solar panels to heat their homes.", "qas": [{"question": "Which energy source can be renewable if managed correctly?", "id": "4270106786", "answers": [{"text": "wood"}]}]}, {"background": "Natural resources include energy, minerals and other materials. Natural resources may be renewable or non-renewable. Non-renewable resources cannot be replaced. When they're gone, they're gone. Renewable resources can be replaced. They can supply human activities forever. Fossil fuels are crucial for modern human society. Fossil fuels are essential for transportation, industry and agriculture. Renewable energy resources tend to be clean. They emit fewer pollutants and greenhouse gases than fossil fuels. Renewable resources often have other problems. They are more costly and less efficient than fossil fuels. Still, they have many advantages. Research is going into developing renewable resources. Conservation is the best way to increase resource availability. Anyone can conserve! You and your family can. Society can. The world can. Just reduce, reuse, recycle.", "situation": "Where mike lived it was very rural and people heated their homes mainly in two ways. They either burned coal that was mined locally or the used fire wood. Recently some people have started to use solar panels to heat their homes.", "qas": [{"question": "Which energy source cost the most?", "id": "2603851742", "answers": [{"text": "solar"}]}]}, {"background": "Natural resources include energy, minerals and other materials. Natural resources may be renewable or non-renewable. Non-renewable resources cannot be replaced. When they're gone, they're gone. Renewable resources can be replaced. They can supply human activities forever. Fossil fuels are crucial for modern human society. Fossil fuels are essential for transportation, industry and agriculture. Renewable energy resources tend to be clean. They emit fewer pollutants and greenhouse gases than fossil fuels. Renewable resources often have other problems. They are more costly and less efficient than fossil fuels. Still, they have many advantages. Research is going into developing renewable resources. Conservation is the best way to increase resource availability. Anyone can conserve! You and your family can. Society can. The world can. Just reduce, reuse, recycle.", "situation": "Where mike lived it was very rural and people heated their homes mainly in two ways. They either burned coal that was mined locally or the used fire wood. Recently some people have started to use solar panels to heat their homes.", "qas": [{"question": "Which energy source emits the least pollutants?", "id": "3733628179", "answers": [{"text": "solar"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Mark retired recently. While he enjoyed spending time with his grandchildren he often felt like he could not keep up with them. He was also having trouble remembering things.", "qas": [{"question": "Is mark over or under 65?", "id": "3858366988", "answers": [{"text": "over"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Mark retired recently. While he enjoyed spending time with his grandchildren he often felt like he could not keep up with them. He was also having trouble remembering things.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is getting old?", "id": "3738173562", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Sue was active often rock climbing on the weekend. During the week she enjoyed her job and looking after her children. Her neighbor Beth had retired a few years ago. When not spending time gardening or visiting with friends she enjoyed spending time with her grandchildren. She often asked her grandchildren to help her in the garden as she found she no longer had the stamina to garden all day.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is older?", "id": "450317620", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Sue was active often rock climbing on the weekend. During the week she enjoyed her job and looking after her children. Her neighbor Beth had retired a few years ago. When not spending time gardening or visiting with friends she enjoyed spending time with her grandchildren. She often asked her grandchildren to help her in the garden as she found she no longer had the stamina to garden all day.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is younger?", "id": "3080736295", "answers": [{"text": "Sue"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Sue was active often rock climbing on the weekend. During the week she enjoyed her job and looking after her children. Her neighbor Beth had retired a few years ago. When not spending time gardening or visiting with friends she enjoyed spending time with her grandchildren. She often asked her grandchildren to help her in the garden as she found she no longer had the stamina to garden all day.", "qas": [{"question": "Who probably under 65?", "id": "3854979142", "answers": [{"text": "Sue"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Sue was active often rock climbing on the weekend. During the week she enjoyed her job and looking after her children. Her neighbor Beth had retired a few years ago. When not spending time gardening or visiting with friends she enjoyed spending time with her grandchildren. She often asked her grandchildren to help her in the garden as she found she no longer had the stamina to garden all day.", "qas": [{"question": "Who probably over 65?", "id": "2496745444", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Sue was active often rock climbing on the weekend. During the week she enjoyed her job and looking after her children. Her neighbor Beth had retired a few years ago. When not spending time gardening or visiting with friends she enjoyed spending time with her grandchildren. She often asked her grandchildren to help her in the garden as she found she no longer had the stamina to garden all day.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's immune system is more efficent?", "id": "3404748351", "answers": [{"text": "Sue"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Sue was active often rock climbing on the weekend. During the week she enjoyed her job and looking after her children. Her neighbor Beth had retired a few years ago. When not spending time gardening or visiting with friends she enjoyed spending time with her grandchildren. She often asked her grandchildren to help her in the garden as she found she no longer had the stamina to garden all day.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's immune system is less efficent?", "id": "3406190147", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Sue was active often rock climbing on the weekend. During the week she enjoyed her job and looking after her children. Her neighbor Beth had retired a few years ago. When not spending time gardening or visiting with friends she enjoyed spending time with her grandchildren. She often asked her grandchildren to help her in the garden as she found she no longer had the stamina to garden all day.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's at higher risk for cancer?", "id": "386094068", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Sue was active often rock climbing on the weekend. During the week she enjoyed her job and looking after her children. Her neighbor Beth had retired a few years ago. When not spending time gardening or visiting with friends she enjoyed spending time with her grandchildren. She often asked her grandchildren to help her in the garden as she found she no longer had the stamina to garden all day.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's at lower risk for cancer?", "id": "3292550054", "answers": [{"text": "Sue"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Sue was active often rock climbing on the weekend. During the week she enjoyed her job and looking after her children. Her neighbor Beth had retired a few years ago. When not spending time gardening or visiting with friends she enjoyed spending time with her grandchildren. She often asked her grandchildren to help her in the garden as she found she no longer had the stamina to garden all day.", "qas": [{"question": "Who has better reflexes?", "id": "2254393730", "answers": [{"text": "Sue"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Sue was active often rock climbing on the weekend. During the week she enjoyed her job and looking after her children. Her neighbor Beth had retired a few years ago. When not spending time gardening or visiting with friends she enjoyed spending time with her grandchildren. She often asked her grandchildren to help her in the garden as she found she no longer had the stamina to garden all day.", "qas": [{"question": "Who has slower reflexes?", "id": "2277069208", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Bob and Elaine are neighbors. Elaine goes for a five mile run every morning before work. She hasn't been sick in years and is proud to be healthy and physically fit. Bob retired last year. He is not as active as he used to be but he takes advantage of his extra free time to build cabinets and other furniture, something he has always enjoyed doing.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is younger?", "id": "835730431", "answers": [{"text": "Elaine"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Bob and Elaine are neighbors. Elaine goes for a five mile run every morning before work. She hasn't been sick in years and is proud to be healthy and physically fit. Bob retired last year. He is not as active as he used to be but he takes advantage of his extra free time to build cabinets and other furniture, something he has always enjoyed doing.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is older?", "id": "3108518668", "answers": [{"text": "Bob"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Bob and Elaine are neighbors. Elaine goes for a five mile run every morning before work. She hasn't been sick in years and is proud to be healthy and physically fit. Bob retired last year. He is not as active as he used to be but he takes advantage of his extra free time to build cabinets and other furniture, something he has always enjoyed doing.", "qas": [{"question": "Who has more stamina?", "id": "2680241686", "answers": [{"text": "Elaine"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Bob and Elaine are neighbors. Elaine goes for a five mile run every morning before work. She hasn't been sick in years and is proud to be healthy and physically fit. Bob retired last year. He is not as active as he used to be but he takes advantage of his extra free time to build cabinets and other furniture, something he has always enjoyed doing.", "qas": [{"question": "Who has less stamina?", "id": "2681421338", "answers": [{"text": "Bob"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Bob and Elaine are neighbors. Elaine goes for a five mile run every morning before work. She hasn't been sick in years and is proud to be healthy and physically fit. Bob retired last year. He is not as active as he used to be but he takes advantage of his extra free time to build cabinets and other furniture, something he has always enjoyed doing.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is less likely to get sick?", "id": "512311684", "answers": [{"text": "Elaine"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Bob and Elaine are neighbors. Elaine goes for a five mile run every morning before work. She hasn't been sick in years and is proud to be healthy and physically fit. Bob retired last year. He is not as active as he used to be but he takes advantage of his extra free time to build cabinets and other furniture, something he has always enjoyed doing.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is more likely to get sick?", "id": "508248448", "answers": [{"text": "Bob"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Bob and Elaine are neighbors. Elaine goes for a five mile run every morning before work. She hasn't been sick in years and is proud to be healthy and physically fit. Bob retired last year. He is not as active as he used to be but he takes advantage of his extra free time to build cabinets and other furniture, something he has always enjoyed doing.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is more brain cells?", "id": "1516781320", "answers": [{"text": "Elaine"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Bob and Elaine are neighbors. Elaine goes for a five mile run every morning before work. She hasn't been sick in years and is proud to be healthy and physically fit. Bob retired last year. He is not as active as he used to be but he takes advantage of his extra free time to build cabinets and other furniture, something he has always enjoyed doing.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is fewer brain cells?", "id": "2587246446", "answers": [{"text": "Bob"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Bob and Elaine are neighbors. Elaine goes for a five mile run every morning before work. She hasn't been sick in years and is proud to be healthy and physically fit. Bob retired last year. He is not as active as he used to be but he takes advantage of his extra free time to build cabinets and other furniture, something he has always enjoyed doing.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is more at risk for cancer?", "id": "458441066", "answers": [{"text": "Bob"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Bob and Elaine are neighbors. Elaine goes for a five mile run every morning before work. She hasn't been sick in years and is proud to be healthy and physically fit. Bob retired last year. He is not as active as he used to be but he takes advantage of his extra free time to build cabinets and other furniture, something he has always enjoyed doing.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is less at risk for cancer?", "id": "462504302", "answers": [{"text": "Elaine"}]}]}, {"background": "Nearsightedness, or myopia, is the condition in which nearby objects are seen clearly, but distant objects appear blurry. The Figure below shows how it occurs. The eyeball is longer (from front to back) than normal. This causes images to be focused in front of the retina instead of on the retina. Myopia can be corrected with concave lenses. The lenses focus images farther back in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of in front of it.", "situation": "Matt liked school and always did well but lately he was having trouble keeping up in class. He usually sat in the back but was having trouble seeing the board. His teacher moved him to the front of the classroom and now he could see the board clearly.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Matt nearsighted or farsighted?", "id": "3819701991", "answers": [{"text": "near"}]}]}, {"background": "Nearsightedness, or myopia, is the condition in which nearby objects are seen clearly, but distant objects appear blurry. The Figure below shows how it occurs. The eyeball is longer (from front to back) than normal. This causes images to be focused in front of the retina instead of on the retina. Myopia can be corrected with concave lenses. The lenses focus images farther back in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of in front of it.", "situation": "Matt liked school and always did well but lately he was having trouble keeping up in class. He usually sat in the back but was having trouble seeing the board. His teacher moved him to the front of the classroom and now he could see the board clearly.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Matt's eyeball longer or shorter?", "id": "3939305310", "answers": [{"text": "longer"}]}]}, {"background": "Nearsightedness, or myopia, is the condition in which nearby objects are seen clearly, but distant objects appear blurry. The Figure below shows how it occurs. The eyeball is longer (from front to back) than normal. This causes images to be focused in front of the retina instead of on the retina. Myopia can be corrected with concave lenses. The lenses focus images farther back in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of in front of it.", "situation": "Matt liked school and always did well but lately he was having trouble keeping up in class. He usually sat in the back but was having trouble seeing the board. His teacher moved him to the front of the classroom and now he could see the board clearly.", "qas": [{"question": "Do images focus in front of or on Matt's retina?", "id": "1508838196", "answers": [{"text": "in front"}]}]}, {"background": "Nearsightedness, or myopia, is the condition in which nearby objects are seen clearly, but distant objects appear blurry. The Figure below shows how it occurs. The eyeball is longer (from front to back) than normal. This causes images to be focused in front of the retina instead of on the retina. Myopia can be corrected with concave lenses. The lenses focus images farther back in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of in front of it.", "situation": "Matt liked school and always did well but lately he was having trouble keeping up in class. He usually sat in the back but was having trouble seeing the board. His teacher moved him to the front of the classroom and now he could see the board clearly.", "qas": [{"question": "Who would be helped by concave lenses?", "id": "4283893787", "answers": [{"text": "Matt"}]}]}, {"background": "Nearsightedness, or myopia, is the condition in which nearby objects are seen clearly, but distant objects appear blurry. The Figure below shows how it occurs. The eyeball is longer (from front to back) than normal. This causes images to be focused in front of the retina instead of on the retina. Myopia can be corrected with concave lenses. The lenses focus images farther back in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of in front of it.", "situation": "Mark found that that he was having trouble seeing things at a distance when driving and had to sit closer to his monitor at work in order to see clearly.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Mark's eyeball longer or shorter than normal?", "id": "3301370092", "answers": [{"text": "longer"}]}]}, {"background": "Nearsightedness, or myopia, is the condition in which nearby objects are seen clearly, but distant objects appear blurry. The Figure below shows how it occurs. The eyeball is longer (from front to back) than normal. This causes images to be focused in front of the retina instead of on the retina. Myopia can be corrected with concave lenses. The lenses focus images farther back in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of in front of it.", "situation": "Mark found that that he was having trouble seeing things at a distance when driving and had to sit closer to his monitor at work in order to see clearly.", "qas": [{"question": "Are images being focused in front of or behind Mark's retina?", "id": "3073568046", "answers": [{"text": "in front"}]}]}, {"background": "Nearsightedness, or myopia, is the condition in which nearby objects are seen clearly, but distant objects appear blurry. The Figure below shows how it occurs. The eyeball is longer (from front to back) than normal. This causes images to be focused in front of the retina instead of on the retina. Myopia can be corrected with concave lenses. The lenses focus images farther back in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of in front of it.", "situation": "Mark found that that he was having trouble seeing things at a distance when driving and had to sit closer to his monitor at work in order to see clearly.", "qas": [{"question": "Will concave or convex lenses help Mark?", "id": "2502157843", "answers": [{"text": "concave"}]}]}, {"background": "Nearsightedness, or myopia, is the condition in which nearby objects are seen clearly, but distant objects appear blurry. The Figure below shows how it occurs. The eyeball is longer (from front to back) than normal. This causes images to be focused in front of the retina instead of on the retina. Myopia can be corrected with concave lenses. The lenses focus images farther back in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of in front of it.", "situation": "Mark found that that he was having trouble seeing things at a distance when driving and had to sit closer to his monitor at work in order to see clearly.", "qas": [{"question": "Will concave lenses focus images further back or forward?", "id": "509734056", "answers": [{"text": "further back"}]}]}, {"background": "A few insects, such as mayflies and some moths, never eat. That\u2019s because their lives are over in just a few hours or days. Once these insects become adults, they lay eggs, and then die. On the other hand, some insects are very healthy eaters. A silkworm eats enough leaves to increase its weight more than 4,000 times in just 56 days, as the silkworm increases in size about 10,000 times since birth. A locust eats its own weight in plants every day. Just imagine eating your own weight in food every day. You probably couldn't. You would most likely get very sick even if you tried.", "situation": "Ann was fascinated with insects and often kept butterflies or lady bugs in jars. She liked watching them and was always careful to make sure they had food.  She had been feeding a caterpillar for several days and was amazed at how much it ate. She caught a luna moth yesterday but it would not eat anything she gave it. Her mom said luna moths didn't eat but Ann couldn't believe that so she kept trying.", "qas": [{"question": "Does the luna moth have a short or long life?", "id": "934572415", "answers": [{"text": "short"}]}]}, {"background": "A few insects, such as mayflies and some moths, never eat. That\u2019s because their lives are over in just a few hours or days. Once these insects become adults, they lay eggs, and then die. On the other hand, some insects are very healthy eaters. A silkworm eats enough leaves to increase its weight more than 4,000 times in just 56 days, as the silkworm increases in size about 10,000 times since birth. A locust eats its own weight in plants every day. Just imagine eating your own weight in food every day. You probably couldn't. You would most likely get very sick even if you tried.", "situation": "Ann was fascinated with insects and often kept butterflies or lady bugs in jars. She liked watching them and was always careful to make sure they had food.  She had been feeding a caterpillar for several days and was amazed at how much it ate. She caught a luna moth yesterday but it would not eat anything she gave it. Her mom said luna moths didn't eat but Ann couldn't believe that so she kept trying.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the catipillar eat a litttle or a lot?", "id": "1566339313", "answers": [{"text": "a lot"}]}]}, {"background": "A few insects, such as mayflies and some moths, never eat. That\u2019s because their lives are over in just a few hours or days. Once these insects become adults, they lay eggs, and then die. On the other hand, some insects are very healthy eaters. A silkworm eats enough leaves to increase its weight more than 4,000 times in just 56 days, as the silkworm increases in size about 10,000 times since birth. A locust eats its own weight in plants every day. Just imagine eating your own weight in food every day. You probably couldn't. You would most likely get very sick even if you tried.", "situation": "Ann was fascinated with insects and often kept butterflies or lady bugs in jars. She liked watching them and was always careful to make sure they had food.  She had been feeding a caterpillar for several days and was amazed at how much it ate. She caught a luna moth yesterday but it would not eat anything she gave it. Her mom said luna moths didn't eat but Ann couldn't believe that so she kept trying.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the moth eat or not?", "id": "2636016226", "answers": [{"text": "not"}]}]}, {"background": "Millions of people in the world jog for exercise. For the most part, jogging can be a healthy way to stay fit. However, problems can also develop for those who jog in the heat. Excessive sweating can lead to electrolyte loss that could be life-threatening. Early symptoms of electrolyte deficiency can include nausea, fatugue, and dizziness. If not treated, individuals can experience muscle weakness and increased heart rate (which could lead to a heart attack). Many sports drinks can be consumed to restore electrolytes quickly in the body.", "situation": "Dave was training cycling race that was in only a few weeks. Since the marathon was coming up soon Dave decided to go for a run despite the heat wave. After about 45 minutes Dave was soaked in sweat and was feeling nauseous and dizzy. He decided to stop for a break and have some of the sports drink he had brought along.  After a little while he was feeling better and headed home.", "qas": [{"question": "Which would have helped Dave more water or a sports drink.", "id": "85287502", "answers": [{"text": "sports drink"}]}]}, {"background": "Millions of people in the world jog for exercise. For the most part, jogging can be a healthy way to stay fit. However, problems can also develop for those who jog in the heat. Excessive sweating can lead to electrolyte loss that could be life-threatening. Early symptoms of electrolyte deficiency can include nausea, fatugue, and dizziness. If not treated, individuals can experience muscle weakness and increased heart rate (which could lead to a heart attack). Many sports drinks can be consumed to restore electrolytes quickly in the body.", "situation": "Dave was training cycling race that was in only a few weeks. Since the marathon was coming up soon Dave decided to go for a run despite the heat wave. After about 45 minutes Dave was sweating a lot and was feeling nauseous and dizzy. He decided to stop for a break and have some of the sports drink he had brought along.  After a little while he was feeling better and headed home.", "qas": [{"question": "what was causing Dave to lose electrolytes?", "id": "229334286", "answers": [{"text": "sweating"}]}]}, {"background": "Millions of people in the world jog for exercise. For the most part, jogging can be a healthy way to stay fit. However, problems can also develop for those who jog in the heat. Excessive sweating can lead to electrolyte loss that could be life-threatening. Early symptoms of electrolyte deficiency can include nausea, fatugue, and dizziness. If not treated, individuals can experience muscle weakness and increased heart rate (which could lead to a heart attack). Many sports drinks can be consumed to restore electrolytes quickly in the body.", "situation": "Dave was training cycling race that was in only a few weeks. Since the marathon was coming up soon Dave decided to go for a run despite the heat wave. After about 45 minutes Dave was sweating a lot and was feeling nauseous and dizzy. He decided to stop for a break and have some of the sports drink he had brought along.  After a little while he was feeling better and headed home.", "qas": [{"question": "What restored Dave's electrolytes?", "id": "3639040453", "answers": [{"text": "sports drink"}]}]}, {"background": "Millions of people in the world jog for exercise. For the most part, jogging can be a healthy way to stay fit. However, problems can also develop for those who jog in the heat. Excessive sweating can lead to electrolyte loss that could be life-threatening. Early symptoms of electrolyte deficiency can include nausea, fatugue, and dizziness. If not treated, individuals can experience muscle weakness and increased heart rate (which could lead to a heart attack). Many sports drinks can be consumed to restore electrolytes quickly in the body.", "situation": "Dave was training cycling race that was in only a few weeks. Since the marathon was coming up soon Dave decided to go for a run despite the heat wave. After about 45 minutes Dave was sweating a lot and was feeling nauseous and dizzy. He decided to stop for a break and have some of the sports drink he had brought along.  After a little while he was feeling better and headed home.", "qas": [{"question": "What symptoms of electrolyte loss was Dave having?", "id": "2976800698", "answers": [{"text": "feeling nauseous and dizzy"}]}]}, {"background": "In nature, when the population size is small, there is usually plenty of food and other resources for each individual. When there is plenty of food and other resources, organisms can easily reproduce, so the birth rate is high. As the population increases, the food supply, or the supply of another necessary resource, may decrease. When necessary resources, such as food, decrease, some individuals will die. Overall, the population cannot reproduce at the same rate, so the birth rates drop. This will cause the population growth rate to decrease.", "situation": "The lioness was sitting on a rock looking hopefully out across the flat grasslands. The Savannah was in the midst of a drought. Water hole were small and scarce and most of the grass had died. Most of the herds had moved on to other areas. Many of those who hadn't died. ", "qas": [{"question": "Were the populations of grazing animals decreasing or increasing?", "id": "474431822", "answers": [{"text": "decreasing"}]}]}, {"background": "In nature, when the population size is small, there is usually plenty of food and other resources for each individual. When there is plenty of food and other resources, organisms can easily reproduce, so the birth rate is high. As the population increases, the food supply, or the supply of another necessary resource, may decrease. When necessary resources, such as food, decrease, some individuals will die. Overall, the population cannot reproduce at the same rate, so the birth rates drop. This will cause the population growth rate to decrease.", "situation": "The lioness was sitting on a rock looking hopefully out across the flat grasslands. The Savannah was in the midst of a drought. Water hole were small and scarce and most of the grass had died. Most of the herds had moved on to other areas. Many of those who hadn't died. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is the birth rate increasing or decreasing for grazing animals?", "id": "2189901840", "answers": [{"text": "decreasing"}]}]}, {"background": "In nature, when the population size is small, there is usually plenty of food and other resources for each individual. When there is plenty of food and other resources, organisms can easily reproduce, so the birth rate is high. As the population increases, the food supply, or the supply of another necessary resource, may decrease. When necessary resources, such as food, decrease, some individuals will die. Overall, the population cannot reproduce at the same rate, so the birth rates drop. This will cause the population growth rate to decrease.", "situation": "The lioness was sitting on a rock looking hopefully out across the flat grasslands. The Savannah was in the midst of a drought. Water hole were small and scarce and most of the grass had died. Most of the herds had moved on to other areas. Many of those who hadn't died. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is food scarce or plentiful for grazing animals?", "id": "3937221246", "answers": [{"text": "scarce"}]}]}, {"background": "In nature, when the population size is small, there is usually plenty of food and other resources for each individual. When there is plenty of food and other resources, organisms can easily reproduce, so the birth rate is high. As the population increases, the food supply, or the supply of another necessary resource, may decrease. When necessary resources, such as food, decrease, some individuals will die. Overall, the population cannot reproduce at the same rate, so the birth rates drop. This will cause the population growth rate to decrease.", "situation": "The lioness was sitting on a rock looking hopefully out across the flat grasslands. The Savannah was in the midst of a drought. Water hole were small and scarce and most of the grass had died. Most of the herds had moved on to other areas. Many of those who hadn't died. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is food scarce or plentiful for lions?", "id": "2995205804", "answers": [{"text": "scarce"}]}]}, {"background": "In nature, when the population size is small, there is usually plenty of food and other resources for each individual. When there is plenty of food and other resources, organisms can easily reproduce, so the birth rate is high. As the population increases, the food supply, or the supply of another necessary resource, may decrease. When necessary resources, such as food, decrease, some individuals will die. Overall, the population cannot reproduce at the same rate, so the birth rates drop. This will cause the population growth rate to decrease.", "situation": "The lioness was sitting on a rock looking hopefully out across the flat grasslands. The Savannah was in the midst of a drought. Water hole were small and scarce and most of the grass had died. Most of the herds had moved on to other areas. Many of those who hadn't died. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is the birthrate increasing or decreasing for lions?", "id": "3765451806", "answers": [{"text": "decreasing"}]}]}, {"background": "In nature, when the population size is small, there is usually plenty of food and other resources for each individual. When there is plenty of food and other resources, organisms can easily reproduce, so the birth rate is high. As the population increases, the food supply, or the supply of another necessary resource, may decrease. When necessary resources, such as food, decrease, some individuals will die. Overall, the population cannot reproduce at the same rate, so the birth rates drop. This will cause the population growth rate to decrease.", "situation": "The lioness was sitting on a rock looking hopefully out across the flat grasslands. The Savannah was in the midst of a drought. Water hole were small and scarce and most of the grass had died. Most of the herds had moved on to other areas. Many of those who hadn't died. ", "qas": [{"question": "Are resources increasing or decreasing for the grazers?", "id": "2686991721", "answers": [{"text": "decreasing"}]}]}, {"background": "In nature, when the population size is small, there is usually plenty of food and other resources for each individual. When there is plenty of food and other resources, organisms can easily reproduce, so the birth rate is high. As the population increases, the food supply, or the supply of another necessary resource, may decrease. When necessary resources, such as food, decrease, some individuals will die. Overall, the population cannot reproduce at the same rate, so the birth rates drop. This will cause the population growth rate to decrease.", "situation": "The lioness was sitting on a rock looking hopefully out across the flat grasslands. The Savannah was in the midst of a drought. Water hole were small and scarce and most of the grass had died. Most of the herds had moved on to other areas. Many of those who hadn't died. ", "qas": [{"question": "Are resources increasing or decreasing for the lions?", "id": "629357712", "answers": [{"text": "decreasing"}]}]}, {"background": "In nature, when the population size is small, there is usually plenty of food and other resources for each individual. When there is plenty of food and other resources, organisms can easily reproduce, so the birth rate is high. As the population increases, the food supply, or the supply of another necessary resource, may decrease. When necessary resources, such as food, decrease, some individuals will die. Overall, the population cannot reproduce at the same rate, so the birth rates drop. This will cause the population growth rate to decrease.", "situation": "The lioness was sitting on a rock looking hopefully out across the flat grasslands. The Savannah was in the midst of a drought. Water hole were small and scarce and most of the grass had died. Most of the herds had moved on to other areas. Many of those who hadn't died. ", "qas": [{"question": "Are death rates increasing or decreasing for the lions?", "id": "2412330234", "answers": [{"text": "increasing"}]}]}, {"background": "In nature, when the population size is small, there is usually plenty of food and other resources for each individual. When there is plenty of food and other resources, organisms can easily reproduce, so the birth rate is high. As the population increases, the food supply, or the supply of another necessary resource, may decrease. When necessary resources, such as food, decrease, some individuals will die. Overall, the population cannot reproduce at the same rate, so the birth rates drop. This will cause the population growth rate to decrease.", "situation": "The lioness was sitting on a rock looking hopefully out across the flat grasslands. The Savannah was in the midst of a drought. Water hole were small and scarce and most of the grass had died. Most of the herds had moved on to other areas. Many of those who hadn't died. ", "qas": [{"question": "Are death rates increasing or decreasing for the grazers?", "id": "189873619", "answers": [{"text": "increasing"}]}]}, {"background": "In nature, when the population size is small, there is usually plenty of food and other resources for each individual. When there is plenty of food and other resources, organisms can easily reproduce, so the birth rate is high. As the population increases, the food supply, or the supply of another necessary resource, may decrease. When necessary resources, such as food, decrease, some individuals will die. Overall, the population cannot reproduce at the same rate, so the birth rates drop. This will cause the population growth rate to decrease.", "situation": "The lioness was sitting on a rock looking hopefully out across the flat grasslands. The Savannah was in the midst of a drought. Water hole were small and scarce and most of the grass had died. Most of the herds had moved on to other areas. Many of those who hadn't died. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will lion population increase or decrease if rain comes and grass grows?", "id": "3854058344", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark was in a hurry when he left his house. It had been a hectic day but he did not want to be late for his date. When he got to the restaurant he realized he had left his glasses at home. Mark had to hold the menu at arms length to make out the print so he could order?", "qas": [{"question": "Is Mark nearsighted or farsighted?", "id": "3215135102", "answers": [{"text": "farsighted"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark was in a hurry when he left his house. It had been a hectic day but he did not want to be late for his date. When he got to the restaurant he realized he had left his glasses at home. Mark had to hold the menu at arms length to make out the print so he could order?", "qas": [{"question": "Are images focused in front of or behind Mark's retina?", "id": "1990006918", "answers": [{"text": "behind"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark was in a hurry when he left his house. It had been a hectic day but he did not want to be late for his date. When he got to the restaurant he realized he had left his glasses at home. Mark had to hold the menu at arms length to make out the print so he could order?", "qas": [{"question": "Is Mark's eyeball shorter or longer than normal?", "id": "3516274281", "answers": [{"text": "shorter"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark was in a hurry when he left his house. It had been a hectic day but he did not want to be late for his date. When he got to the restaurant he realized he had left his glasses at home. Mark had to hold the menu at arms length to make out the print so he could order?", "qas": [{"question": "Do Mark's glasses have a convex or concave lens?", "id": "3336705531", "answers": [{"text": "convex"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark found that he often needed to hold a book or menu at arms length to see it. He was beginning to feel silly holding his arms out every time he wanted to read something so he decided to go to the eye doctor and get glasses.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Mark nearsighted or farsighted?", "id": "1265501082", "answers": [{"text": "farsighted"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark found that he often needed to hold a book or menu at arms length to see it. He was beginning to feel silly holding his arms out every time he wanted to read something so he decided to go to the eye doctor and get glasses.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Mark's eye shorter or longer than normal?", "id": "2005272298", "answers": [{"text": "shorter"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark found that he often needed to hold a book or menu at arms length to see it. He was beginning to feel silly holding his arms out every time he wanted to read something so he decided to go to the eye doctor and get glasses.", "qas": [{"question": "Are images being focused infront of or behind his retina?", "id": "4261415878", "answers": [{"text": "behind"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark found that he often needed to hold a book or menu at arms length to see it. He was beginning to feel silly holding his arms out every time he wanted to read something so he decided to go to the eye doctor and get glasses.", "qas": [{"question": "Does Mark need concave or convex lenses?", "id": "1647510930", "answers": [{"text": "convex"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark found that he often needed to hold a book or menu at arms length to see it. He was beginning to feel silly holding his arms out every time he wanted to read something so he decided to go to the eye doctor and get glasses.", "qas": [{"question": "Will conves lenses focus images farther back or forward?", "id": "60820444", "answers": [{"text": "forward"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark found himself sitting closer to his TV and computer screens than he used to. His wife Beth however seemed to be having the opposite problem. She was holding her books and even menus at arms length just to read.", "qas": [{"question": "Was mark nearsighted or farsighted?", "id": "185008446", "answers": [{"text": "nearsighted"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark found himself sitting closer to his TV and computer screens than he used to. His wife Beth however seemed to be having the opposite problem. She was holding her books and even menus at arms length just to read.", "qas": [{"question": "Who was farsighted?", "id": "622197539", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark found himself sitting closer to his TV and computer screens than he used to. His wife Beth however seemed to be having the opposite problem. She was holding her books and even menus at arms length just to read.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's eyeball is shorter than normal?", "id": "134873525", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark found himself sitting closer to his TV and computer screens than he used to. His wife Beth however seemed to be having the opposite problem. She was holding her books and even menus at arms length just to read.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's eyes focus images behind the retina?", "id": "317260634", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark found himself sitting closer to his TV and computer screens than he used to. His wife Beth however seemed to be having the opposite problem. She was holding her books and even menus at arms length just to read.", "qas": [{"question": "Who could see better with convex lenses?", "id": "302777081", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark found himself sitting closer to his TV and computer screens than he used to. His wife Beth however seemed to be having the opposite problem. She was holding her books and even menus at arms length just to read.", "qas": [{"question": "Who could not see better with convex lenses?", "id": "533660778", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark found himself sitting closer to his TV and computer screens than he used to. His wife Beth however seemed to be having the opposite problem. She was holding her books and even menus at arms length just to read.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose eyeball is not shorter than normal?", "id": "437846884", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark found himself sitting closer to his TV and computer screens than he used to. His wife Beth however seemed to be having the opposite problem. She was holding her books and even menus at arms length just to read.", "qas": [{"question": "Who can see close things normally?", "id": "30343334", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark was having trouble seeing things up close when he was reading. Menu or books even files at the office had to be held as far away as possible so he could read.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Marks eyeball shorter or longer than normal?", "id": "3114004941", "answers": [{"text": "shorter"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark was having trouble seeing things up close when he was reading. Menu or books even files at the office had to be held as far away as possible so he could read.", "qas": [{"question": "Are images focusing behind or infront of Mark's retina?", "id": "1400108134", "answers": [{"text": "behind"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark was having trouble seeing things up close when he was reading. Menu or books even files at the office had to be held as far away as possible so he could read.", "qas": [{"question": "Will convex or concave lenses help Mark?", "id": "709160731", "answers": [{"text": "convex"}]}]}, {"background": "Farsightedness, or hyperopia, is the condition in which distant objects are seen clearly, but nearby objects appear blurry. It occurs when the eyeball is shorter than normal (see Figure below ). This causes images to be focused in a spot that would fall behind the retina (if light could pass through the retina). Hyperopia can be corrected with convex lenses. The lenses focus images farther forward in the eye, so they fall on the retina instead of behind it.", "situation": "Mark was having trouble seeing things up close when he was reading. Menu or books even files at the office had to be held as far away as possible so he could read.", "qas": [{"question": "Will conves lenses focus images further back or forward on his retina?", "id": "3922655843", "answers": [{"text": "forward"}]}]}, {"background": "For example, your body has an internal thermostat. During a winter day, in your house a thermostat senses the temperature in a room and responds by turning on or off the heater. Your body acts in much the same way. When body temperature rises, receptors in the skin and the brain sense the temperature change. The temperature change triggers a command from the brain. This command can cause several responses. If you are too hot, the skin makes sweat and blood vessels near the skin surface dilate. This response helps decrease body temperature.", "situation": "Mark had been doing yard work all morning. He was soaked in sweat and was glad he could go inside now where it was air conditioned. Mark was only inside for a few minutes before he started shivering so he turned down the air conditioner.", "qas": [{"question": "Was Mark's body hot or cold outside?", "id": "1042884775", "answers": [{"text": "hot"}]}]}, {"background": "For example, your body has an internal thermostat. During a winter day, in your house a thermostat senses the temperature in a room and responds by turning on or off the heater. Your body acts in much the same way. When body temperature rises, receptors in the skin and the brain sense the temperature change. The temperature change triggers a command from the brain. This command can cause several responses. If you are too hot, the skin makes sweat and blood vessels near the skin surface dilate. This response helps decrease body temperature.", "situation": "Mark had been doing yard work all morning. He was soaked in sweat and was glad he could go inside now where it was air conditioned. Mark was only inside for a few minutes before he started shivering so he turned down the air conditioner.", "qas": [{"question": "Was Mark's body hot or cold inside?", "id": "349055014", "answers": [{"text": "cold"}]}]}, {"background": "For example, your body has an internal thermostat. During a winter day, in your house a thermostat senses the temperature in a room and responds by turning on or off the heater. Your body acts in much the same way. When body temperature rises, receptors in the skin and the brain sense the temperature change. The temperature change triggers a command from the brain. This command can cause several responses. If you are too hot, the skin makes sweat and blood vessels near the skin surface dilate. This response helps decrease body temperature.", "situation": "Mark had been doing yard work all morning. He was soaked in sweat and was glad he could go inside now where it was air conditioned. Mark was only inside for a few minutes before he started shivering so he turned down the air conditioner.", "qas": [{"question": "When he was outside was Mark's body trying to warm itself or cool off??", "id": "3180148041", "answers": [{"text": "cool off"}]}]}, {"background": "For example, your body has an internal thermostat. During a winter day, in your house a thermostat senses the temperature in a room and responds by turning on or off the heater. Your body acts in much the same way. When body temperature rises, receptors in the skin and the brain sense the temperature change. The temperature change triggers a command from the brain. This command can cause several responses. If you are too hot, the skin makes sweat and blood vessels near the skin surface dilate. This response helps decrease body temperature.", "situation": "Mark had been doing yard work all morning. He was soaked in sweat and was glad he could go inside now where it was air conditioned. Mark was only inside for a few minutes before he started shivering so he turned down the air conditioner.", "qas": [{"question": "When he was inside was Mark's body trying to warm itself or cool off??", "id": "2147562696", "answers": [{"text": "warm itself"}]}]}, {"background": "For example, your body has an internal thermostat. During a winter day, in your house a thermostat senses the temperature in a room and responds by turning on or off the heater. Your body acts in much the same way. When body temperature rises, receptors in the skin and the brain sense the temperature change. The temperature change triggers a command from the brain. This command can cause several responses. If you are too hot, the skin makes sweat and blood vessels near the skin surface dilate. This response helps decrease body temperature.", "situation": "Mark had been doing yard work all morning. He was soaked in sweat and was glad he could go inside now where it was air conditioned. Mark was only inside for a few minutes before he started shivering so he turned down the air conditioner.", "qas": [{"question": "Mas Mark's blood vessels dilated inside or outside?", "id": "3586862730", "answers": [{"text": "outside"}]}]}, {"background": "For example, your body has an internal thermostat. During a winter day, in your house a thermostat senses the temperature in a room and responds by turning on or off the heater. Your body acts in much the same way. When body temperature rises, receptors in the skin and the brain sense the temperature change. The temperature change triggers a command from the brain. This command can cause several responses. If you are too hot, the skin makes sweat and blood vessels near the skin surface dilate. This response helps decrease body temperature.", "situation": "Mark had been doing yard work all morning. He was soaked in sweat and was glad he could go inside now where it was air conditioned. Mark was only inside for a few minutes before he started shivering so he turned down the air conditioner.", "qas": [{"question": "Mas Mark's blood vessels constricted inside or outside?", "id": "2608803925", "answers": [{"text": "inside"}]}]}, {"background": "For example, your body has an internal thermostat. During a winter day, in your house a thermostat senses the temperature in a room and responds by turning on or off the heater. Your body acts in much the same way. When body temperature rises, receptors in the skin and the brain sense the temperature change. The temperature change triggers a command from the brain. This command can cause several responses. If you are too hot, the skin makes sweat and blood vessels near the skin surface dilate. This response helps decrease body temperature.", "situation": "Ann couldn't believe her luck. Her cars air conditioning had broken yesterday and now she was stuck in traffic. As she sat in the car waiting for traffic to start moving she began to sweat.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the temerature in the car rising or decreasing?", "id": "470031659", "answers": [{"text": "rising"}]}]}, {"background": "For example, your body has an internal thermostat. During a winter day, in your house a thermostat senses the temperature in a room and responds by turning on or off the heater. Your body acts in much the same way. When body temperature rises, receptors in the skin and the brain sense the temperature change. The temperature change triggers a command from the brain. This command can cause several responses. If you are too hot, the skin makes sweat and blood vessels near the skin surface dilate. This response helps decrease body temperature.", "situation": "Ann couldn't believe her luck. Her cars air conditioning had broken yesterday and now she was stuck in traffic. As she sat in the car waiting for traffic to start moving she began to sweat.", "qas": [{"question": "Were Ann's blood vessels dialating or contracting?", "id": "4197063930", "answers": [{"text": "dialating"}]}]}, {"background": "For example, your body has an internal thermostat. During a winter day, in your house a thermostat senses the temperature in a room and responds by turning on or off the heater. Your body acts in much the same way. When body temperature rises, receptors in the skin and the brain sense the temperature change. The temperature change triggers a command from the brain. This command can cause several responses. If you are too hot, the skin makes sweat and blood vessels near the skin surface dilate. This response helps decrease body temperature.", "situation": "Ann couldn't believe her luck. Her cars air conditioning had broken yesterday and now she was stuck in traffic. As she sat in the car waiting for traffic to start moving she began to sweat.", "qas": [{"question": "Was Ann's body temperature rising or falling?", "id": "1846352633", "answers": [{"text": "rising"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Beth put water on the stove to boil for making rice. While she was waiting for the water to boil she filled her ice cube trays with water and put them in the freezer. When the water on the stove reached a boil she added her rice and removed it from the heat.", "qas": [{"question": "Were the water molecules in the pot moving or stationary?", "id": "2526508048", "answers": [{"text": "moving"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Beth put water on the stove to boil for making rice. While she was waiting for the water to boil she filled her ice cube trays with water and put them in the freezer. When the water on the stove reached a boil she added her rice and removed it from the heat.", "qas": [{"question": "As the water heated did the molecules speed up or slow down??", "id": "1432057015", "answers": [{"text": "speed up"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Beth put water on the stove to boil for making rice. While she was waiting for the water to boil she filled her ice cube trays with water and put them in the freezer. When the water on the stove reached a boil she added her rice and removed it from the heat.", "qas": [{"question": "When the water reached boiling were the molecules moving faster or staying at a constant speed?", "id": "3708584431", "answers": [{"text": "constant speed"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Beth put water on the stove to boil for making rice. While she was waiting for the water to boil she filled her ice cube trays with water and put them in the freezer. When the water on the stove reached a boil she added her rice and removed it from the heat.", "qas": [{"question": "Were the molecules moving in a pattern or randomly?", "id": "3848892848", "answers": [{"text": "randomly"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Beth put water on the stove to boil for making rice. While she was waiting for the water to boil she filled her ice cube trays with water and put them in the freezer. When the water on the stove reached a boil she added her rice and removed it from the heat.", "qas": [{"question": "Which molecules moved faster room temperature or boiling water ?", "id": "3809441493", "answers": [{"text": "boiling"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Beth put water on the stove to boil for making rice. While she was waiting for the water to boil she filled her ice cube trays with water and put them in the freezer. When the water on the stove reached a boil she added her rice and removed it from the heat.", "qas": [{"question": "Which molecules moved slower room temperature or boiling water ?", "id": "3871962860", "answers": [{"text": "room temperature"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Beth put water on the stove to boil for making rice. While she was waiting for the water to boil she filled her ice cube trays with water and put them in the freezer. When the water on the stove reached a boil she added her rice and removed it from the heat.", "qas": [{"question": "Which molecules moved slower room temperature or frozen water ?", "id": "1885370012", "answers": [{"text": "frozen"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Beth put water on the stove to boil for making rice. While she was waiting for the water to boil she filled her ice cube trays with water and put them in the freezer. When the water on the stove reached a boil she added her rice and removed it from the heat.", "qas": [{"question": "Which molecules moved faster room temperature or frozen water ?", "id": "1824355973", "answers": [{"text": "room temperature"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Beth put water on the stove to boil for making rice. While she was waiting for the water to boil she filled her ice cube trays with water and put them in the freezer. When the water on the stove reached a boil she added her rice and removed it from the heat.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the room temperture or frozen water have more kinetic energy?", "id": "1168602882", "answers": [{"text": "room temperture"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Beth put water on the stove to boil for making rice. While she was waiting for the water to boil she filled her ice cube trays with water and put them in the freezer. When the water on the stove reached a boil she added her rice and removed it from the heat.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the room temperture or boiling water have more kinetic energy?", "id": "3134093138", "answers": [{"text": "boiling"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Jane wanted to make a batch of candy so she but some water, sugar, corn syrup and flavoring in a pot. After turning on the heat she stirred the the mixture until until it reached 300 degrees Fahrenheit and began to boil. She then turned of the candy and and poured it into molds.", "qas": [{"question": "Where the solution molecules moving or stationary before the heat was appllied?", "id": "369329112", "answers": [{"text": "moving"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Jane wanted to make a batch of candy so she but some water, sugar, corn syrup and flavoring in a pot. After turning on the heat she stirred the the mixture until until it reached 300 degrees Fahrenheit and began to boil. She then turned of the candy and and poured it into molds.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the molecules speed up or slow down when heat was applied to the liquid?", "id": "1451590052", "answers": [{"text": "speed up"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Jane wanted to make a batch of candy so she but some water, sugar, corn syrup and flavoring in a pot. After turning on the heat she stirred the the mixture until until it reached 300 degrees Fahrenheit and began to boil. She then turned of the candy and and poured it into molds.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the molecules speed up or slow down when heat was removed fromthe liquid?", "id": "3724640872", "answers": [{"text": "slow down"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Jane wanted to make a batch of candy so she but some water, sugar, corn syrup and flavoring in a pot. After turning on the heat she stirred the the mixture until until it reached 300 degrees Fahrenheit and began to boil. She then turned of the candy and and poured it into molds.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the molecules coliding more or less often when heat was removed from the liquid?", "id": "2131395812", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Jane wanted to make a batch of candy so she but some water, sugar, corn syrup and flavoring in a pot. After turning on the heat she stirred the the mixture until until it reached 300 degrees Fahrenheit and began to boil. She then turned of the candy and and poured it into molds.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the molecules coliding more or less often when heat wasapplied to the liqued the liquid?", "id": "3070134245", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Jane wanted to make a batch of candy so she but some water, sugar, corn syrup and flavoring in a pot. After turning on the heat she stirred the the mixture until until it reached 300 degrees Fahrenheit and began to boil. She then turned of the candy and and poured it into molds.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the kinetic energy increasing or decreasing when heat was applied to the liqued the liquid?", "id": "1546488080", "answers": [{"text": "increasing"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Jane wanted to make a batch of candy so she but some water, sugar, corn syrup and flavoring in a pot. After turning on the heat she stirred the the mixture until until it reached 300 degrees Fahrenheit and began to boil. She then turned of the candy and and poured it into molds.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the kinetic energy increasing or decreasing when heat was removed from the liquid?", "id": "2597422575", "answers": [{"text": "decreasing"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Jane wanted to make a batch of candy so she but some water, sugar, corn syrup and flavoring in a pot. After turning on the heat she stirred the the mixture until until it reached 300 degrees Fahrenheit and began to boil. She then turned of the candy and and poured it into molds.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the temperature of the liqued increasing or decreasing in the molds?", "id": "1768456367", "answers": [{"text": "decreasing"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Jane wanted to make a batch of candy so she but some water, sugar, corn syrup and flavoring in a pot. After turning on the heat she stirred the the mixture until until it reached 300 degrees Fahrenheit and began to boil. She then turned of the candy and and poured it into molds.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the kinetic energy of the liqued increasing or decreasing in the molds?", "id": "3760423314", "answers": [{"text": "decreasing"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Jane wanted to make a batch of candy so she but some water, sugar, corn syrup and flavoring in a pot. After turning on the heat she stirred the the mixture until until it reached 300 degrees Fahrenheit and began to boil. She then turned of the candy and and poured it into molds.", "qas": [{"question": "Were the liqued molecules speeding up or slowing down  in the molds?", "id": "1722384115", "answers": [{"text": "slowing down"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Sue needed to make a simple syrup so she added water and sugar to a pot. She put the pot over a low heat and brought it to a simmer. Sue then removed the syrup from the heat and let it cool.", "qas": [{"question": "Did heating the syrup increase or decreas the kinetic energy of the solution?", "id": "100098669", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Sue needed to make a simple syrup so she added water and sugar to a pot. She put the pot over a low heat and brought it to a simmer. Sue then removed the syrup from the heat and let it cool.", "qas": [{"question": "Did removing the syrup from the heat increase or decrease the kinetic energy of the solution?", "id": "1605331024", "answers": [{"text": "decrease"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Sue needed to make a simple syrup so she added water and sugar to a pot. She put the pot over a low heat and brought it to a simmer. Sue then removed the syrup from the heat and let it cool.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the motion of the solutions molecules increase or decrese when heat was added. ", "id": "1660970030", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Sue needed to make a simple syrup so she added water and sugar to a pot. She put the pot over a low heat and brought it to a simmer. Sue then removed the syrup from the heat and let it cool.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the motion of the solutions molecules increase or decrease when heat was removed ", "id": "798647649", "answers": [{"text": "decrease"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Sue needed to make a simple syrup so she added water and sugar to a pot. She put the pot over a low heat and brought it to a simmer. Sue then removed the syrup from the heat and let it cool.", "qas": [{"question": "Were the solutions molecules colliding or moving away from each other.", "id": "2103533612", "answers": [{"text": "colliding "}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "As Matt prepared for his latest hot air balloon flight he lit the fire beneath the balloon opening and watch as the fabric of the balloon began to expand. Eventually is once flat balloon was fully expanded and ready for flight.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the air particles moving faster inside or outside the balloon?", "id": "1116237094", "answers": [{"text": "inside"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "As Matt prepared for his latest hot air balloon flight he lit the fire beneath the balloon opening and watch as the fabric of the balloon began to expand. Eventually is once flat balloon was fully expanded and ready for flight.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the air particles moving slower inside or outside the balloon?", "id": "1171221821", "answers": [{"text": "outside"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "As Matt prepared for his latest hot air balloon flight he lit the fire beneath the balloon opening and watch as the fabric of the balloon began to expand. Eventually is once flat balloon was fully expanded and ready for flight.", "qas": [{"question": "Where the air pressure greater inside or outside the balloon?", "id": "2566220748", "answers": [{"text": "inside"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "As Matt prepared for his latest hot air balloon flight he lit the fire beneath the balloon opening and watch as the fabric of the balloon began to expand. Eventually is once flat balloon was fully expanded and ready for flight.", "qas": [{"question": "Where the air pressure less inside or outside the balloon?", "id": "1406954137", "answers": [{"text": "outside"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "As Matt prepared for his latest hot air balloon flight he lit the fire beneath the balloon opening and watch as the fabric of the balloon began to expand. Eventually is once flat balloon was fully expanded and ready for flight.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the air hotter or cooler inside the balloon?", "id": "3327026727", "answers": [{"text": "inside"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "As Matt prepared for his latest hot air balloon flight he lit the fire beneath the balloon opening and watch as the fabric of the balloon began to expand. Eventually is once flat balloon was fully expanded and ready for flight.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the air cooler inside or outside the balloon?", "id": "757163662", "answers": [{"text": "outside"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "As Matt prepared for his latest hot air balloon flight he lit the fire beneath the balloon opening and watch as the fabric of the balloon began to expand. Eventually is once flat balloon was fully expanded and ready for flight.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the air particles colliding more frequently inside or outside the balloon?", "id": "4179522116", "answers": [{"text": "inside"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "As Matt prepared for his latest hot air balloon flight he lit the fire beneath the balloon opening and watch as the fabric of the balloon began to expand. Eventually is once flat balloon was fully expanded and ready for flight.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the air particles colliding less frequently inside or outside the balloon?", "id": "4189352520", "answers": [{"text": "outside"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "As Matt prepared for his latest hot air balloon flight he lit the fire beneath the balloon opening and watch as the fabric of the balloon began to expand. Eventually is once flat balloon was fully expanded and ready for flight.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the kinetic energy of the air increasing or decreasing as the air is heated?", "id": "1239511424", "answers": [{"text": "increasing"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u2013 the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "As Matt prepared for his latest hot air balloon flight he lit the fire beneath the balloon opening and watch as the fabric of the balloon began to expand. Eventually is once flat balloon was fully expanded and ready for flight.", "qas": [{"question": "Ar the air particles colliding more or less frequently with the sides of the balloon as the air is heated??", "id": "1780055006", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Huge amounts of chemicals, such as fertilizers and pesticides, are applied to farm fields (see Figure below ). Some of the chemicals are picked up by rainwater. Runoff then carries the chemicals to nearby rivers or lakes. Dissolved fertilizer causes too much growth of water plants and algae. This can lead to dead zones where nothing can live in lakes and at the mouths of rivers. Some of the chemicals can infiltrate into groundwater. The contaminated water comes up in water wells. If people drink the polluted water, they may get sick.", "situation": "Farm A and Farm B use different methods of controlling pests on their crops. Farm A uses fertilizers and pesticides on their crops. Farm B is organic and does not use fertilizers or pesticides. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Farm A experience more or less groundwater contamination than Farm B?", "id": "652354534", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Huge amounts of chemicals, such as fertilizers and pesticides, are applied to farm fields (see Figure below ). Some of the chemicals are picked up by rainwater. Runoff then carries the chemicals to nearby rivers or lakes. Dissolved fertilizer causes too much growth of water plants and algae. This can lead to dead zones where nothing can live in lakes and at the mouths of rivers. Some of the chemicals can infiltrate into groundwater. The contaminated water comes up in water wells. If people drink the polluted water, they may get sick.", "situation": "Farm A and Farm B use different methods of controlling pests on their crops. Farm A uses fertilizers and pesticides on their crops. Farm B is organic and does not use fertilizers or pesticides. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Farm B experience more or less groundwater contamination than Farm A?", "id": "656417766", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Huge amounts of chemicals, such as fertilizers and pesticides, are applied to farm fields (see Figure below ). Some of the chemicals are picked up by rainwater. Runoff then carries the chemicals to nearby rivers or lakes. Dissolved fertilizer causes too much growth of water plants and algae. This can lead to dead zones where nothing can live in lakes and at the mouths of rivers. Some of the chemicals can infiltrate into groundwater. The contaminated water comes up in water wells. If people drink the polluted water, they may get sick.", "situation": "Farm A and Farm B use different methods of controlling pests on their crops. Farm A uses fertilizers and pesticides on their crops. Farm B is organic and does not use fertilizers or pesticides. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the lakes and rivers near Farm A have more or less water plants and algae than Farm B?", "id": "2494441667", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Huge amounts of chemicals, such as fertilizers and pesticides, are applied to farm fields (see Figure below ). Some of the chemicals are picked up by rainwater. Runoff then carries the chemicals to nearby rivers or lakes. Dissolved fertilizer causes too much growth of water plants and algae. This can lead to dead zones where nothing can live in lakes and at the mouths of rivers. Some of the chemicals can infiltrate into groundwater. The contaminated water comes up in water wells. If people drink the polluted water, they may get sick.", "situation": "Farm A and Farm B use different methods of controlling pests on their crops. Farm A uses fertilizers and pesticides on their crops. Farm B is organic and does not use fertilizers or pesticides. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the lakes and rivers near Farm B have more or less water plants and algae than Farm A?", "id": "2497915075", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Huge amounts of chemicals, such as fertilizers and pesticides, are applied to farm fields (see Figure below ). Some of the chemicals are picked up by rainwater. Runoff then carries the chemicals to nearby rivers or lakes. Dissolved fertilizer causes too much growth of water plants and algae. This can lead to dead zones where nothing can live in lakes and at the mouths of rivers. Some of the chemicals can infiltrate into groundwater. The contaminated water comes up in water wells. If people drink the polluted water, they may get sick.", "situation": "Farm A and Farm B use different methods of controlling pests on their crops. Farm A uses fertilizers and pesticides on their crops. Farm B is organic and does not use fertilizers or pesticides. ", "qas": [{"question": "Are the residents near Farm A more or less likely to experience illness due to polluted water than the residents near Farm B?", "id": "463156772", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Huge amounts of chemicals, such as fertilizers and pesticides, are applied to farm fields (see Figure below ). Some of the chemicals are picked up by rainwater. Runoff then carries the chemicals to nearby rivers or lakes. Dissolved fertilizer causes too much growth of water plants and algae. This can lead to dead zones where nothing can live in lakes and at the mouths of rivers. Some of the chemicals can infiltrate into groundwater. The contaminated water comes up in water wells. If people drink the polluted water, they may get sick.", "situation": "Farm A and Farm B use different methods of controlling pests on their crops. Farm A uses fertilizers and pesticides on their crops. Farm B is organic and does not use fertilizers or pesticides. ", "qas": [{"question": "Are the residents near Farm B more or less likely to experience illness due to polluted water than the residents near Farm A?", "id": "469382692", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Huge amounts of chemicals, such as fertilizers and pesticides, are applied to farm fields (see Figure below ). Some of the chemicals are picked up by rainwater. Runoff then carries the chemicals to nearby rivers or lakes. Dissolved fertilizer causes too much growth of water plants and algae. This can lead to dead zones where nothing can live in lakes and at the mouths of rivers. Some of the chemicals can infiltrate into groundwater. The contaminated water comes up in water wells. If people drink the polluted water, they may get sick.", "situation": "Farm A and Farm B use different methods of controlling pests on their crops. Farm A uses fertilizers and pesticides on their crops. Farm B is organic and does not use fertilizers or pesticides. ", "qas": [{"question": "If Farm A stops using pesticides and fertilizers, will Farm A experience more or less groundwater contamination?", "id": "1916088903", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Huge amounts of chemicals, such as fertilizers and pesticides, are applied to farm fields (see Figure below ). Some of the chemicals are picked up by rainwater. Runoff then carries the chemicals to nearby rivers or lakes. Dissolved fertilizer causes too much growth of water plants and algae. This can lead to dead zones where nothing can live in lakes and at the mouths of rivers. Some of the chemicals can infiltrate into groundwater. The contaminated water comes up in water wells. If people drink the polluted water, they may get sick.", "situation": "Farm A and Farm B use different methods of controlling pests on their crops. Farm A uses fertilizers and pesticides on their crops. Farm B is organic and does not use fertilizers or pesticides. ", "qas": [{"question": "If Farm B starts using pesticides and fertilizers, will Farm B experience more or less groundwater contamination?", "id": "2825401009", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Sometimes muscles and tendons get injured when a person starts doing an activity before they have warmed up properly. A warm up is a slow increase in the intensity of a physical activity that prepares muscles for an activity. Warming up increases the blood flow to the muscles and increases the heart rate. Warmed-up muscles and tendons are less likely to get injured. For example, before running or playing soccer, a person might jog slowly to warm muscles and increase their heart rate. Even elite athletes need to warm up ( Figure below ).", "situation": "Kylie and Taylor are taking an exercise class at the local gym together. Before class, Kylie does a warm-up to stretch her muscles. Taylor does not do a warm-up before class. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is more likely to suffer a muscle or tendon injury, Kylie or Taylor?", "id": "3782155770", "answers": [{"text": "Taylor"}]}]}, {"background": "Sometimes muscles and tendons get injured when a person starts doing an activity before they have warmed up properly. A warm up is a slow increase in the intensity of a physical activity that prepares muscles for an activity. Warming up increases the blood flow to the muscles and increases the heart rate. Warmed-up muscles and tendons are less likely to get injured. For example, before running or playing soccer, a person might jog slowly to warm muscles and increase their heart rate. Even elite athletes need to warm up ( Figure below ).", "situation": "Kylie and Taylor are taking an exercise class at the local gym together. Before class, Kylie does a warm-up to stretch her muscles. Taylor does not do a warm-up before class. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is less likely to suffer a muscle or tendon injury, Kylie or Taylor?", "id": "3796966910", "answers": [{"text": "Kylie"}]}]}, {"background": "Sometimes muscles and tendons get injured when a person starts doing an activity before they have warmed up properly. A warm up is a slow increase in the intensity of a physical activity that prepares muscles for an activity. Warming up increases the blood flow to the muscles and increases the heart rate. Warmed-up muscles and tendons are less likely to get injured. For example, before running or playing soccer, a person might jog slowly to warm muscles and increase their heart rate. Even elite athletes need to warm up ( Figure below ).", "situation": "Kylie and Taylor are taking an exercise class at the local gym together. Before class, Kylie does a warm-up to stretch her muscles. Taylor does not do a warm-up before class. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Taylor more or less likely to suffer a muscle or tendon injury than Kylie?", "id": "2163810306", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Sometimes muscles and tendons get injured when a person starts doing an activity before they have warmed up properly. A warm up is a slow increase in the intensity of a physical activity that prepares muscles for an activity. Warming up increases the blood flow to the muscles and increases the heart rate. Warmed-up muscles and tendons are less likely to get injured. For example, before running or playing soccer, a person might jog slowly to warm muscles and increase their heart rate. Even elite athletes need to warm up ( Figure below ).", "situation": "Kylie and Taylor are taking an exercise class at the local gym together. Before class, Kylie does a warm-up to stretch her muscles. Taylor does not do a warm-up before class. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Kylie more or less likely to suffer a muscle or tendon injury than Taylor?", "id": "2025988098", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "The brains of all mammals have a unique layer of nerve cells covering the cerebrum. This layer is called the neocortex (the pink region of the brains in Figure above ). The neocortex plays an important role in many complex brain functions. In some mammals, such as rats, the neocortex is relatively smooth. In other mammals, especially humans, the neocortex has many folds. The folds increase the surface area of the neocortex. The larger this area is, the greater the mental abilities of an animal.", "situation": "Matt is studying the brains of two different mammals. He knows that one brain belongs to a mouse and the other brain belongs to a gorilla, but is not sure which brain belongs to which mammal. To determine this, he observes the neocortex of each brain and finds that the neocortex of Brain A is relatively smooth and the neocortex of Brain B has many more folds. ", "qas": [{"question": "Which brain belongs to the mouse, Brain A or Brain B?", "id": "4005120128", "answers": [{"text": "Brain A"}]}]}, {"background": "The brains of all mammals have a unique layer of nerve cells covering the cerebrum. This layer is called the neocortex (the pink region of the brains in Figure above ). The neocortex plays an important role in many complex brain functions. In some mammals, such as rats, the neocortex is relatively smooth. In other mammals, especially humans, the neocortex has many folds. The folds increase the surface area of the neocortex. The larger this area is, the greater the mental abilities of an animal.", "situation": "Matt is studying the brains of two different mammals. He knows that one brain belongs to a mouse and the other brain belongs to a gorilla, but is not sure which brain belongs to which mammal. To determine this, he observes the neocortex of each brain and finds that the neocortex of Brain A is relatively smooth and the neocortex of Brain B has many more folds. ", "qas": [{"question": "Which brain belongs to the gorilla, Brain A or Brain B?", "id": "2214349121", "answers": [{"text": "Brain B"}]}]}, {"background": "The brains of all mammals have a unique layer of nerve cells covering the cerebrum. This layer is called the neocortex (the pink region of the brains in Figure above ). The neocortex plays an important role in many complex brain functions. In some mammals, such as rats, the neocortex is relatively smooth. In other mammals, especially humans, the neocortex has many folds. The folds increase the surface area of the neocortex. The larger this area is, the greater the mental abilities of an animal.", "situation": "Matt is studying the brains of two different mammals. He knows that one brain belongs to a mouse and the other brain belongs to a gorilla, but is not sure which brain belongs to which mammal. To determine this, he observes the neocortex of each brain and finds that the neocortex of Brain A is relatively smooth and the neocortex of Brain B has many more folds. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the mammal belonging to Brain A have greater or fewer mental abilities than the mammal belonging to Brain B?", "id": "3340918523", "answers": [{"text": "fewer"}]}]}, {"background": "The brains of all mammals have a unique layer of nerve cells covering the cerebrum. This layer is called the neocortex (the pink region of the brains in Figure above ). The neocortex plays an important role in many complex brain functions. In some mammals, such as rats, the neocortex is relatively smooth. In other mammals, especially humans, the neocortex has many folds. The folds increase the surface area of the neocortex. The larger this area is, the greater the mental abilities of an animal.", "situation": "Matt is studying the brains of two different mammals. He knows that one brain belongs to a mouse and the other brain belongs to a gorilla, but is not sure which brain belongs to which mammal. To determine this, he observes the neocortex of each brain and finds that the neocortex of Brain A is relatively smooth and the neocortex of Brain B has many more folds. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the mammal belonging to Brain B have greater or fewer mental abilities than the mammal belonging to Brain A?", "id": "3345899259", "answers": [{"text": "greater"}]}]}, {"background": "The brains of all mammals have a unique layer of nerve cells covering the cerebrum. This layer is called the neocortex (the pink region of the brains in Figure above ). The neocortex plays an important role in many complex brain functions. In some mammals, such as rats, the neocortex is relatively smooth. In other mammals, especially humans, the neocortex has many folds. The folds increase the surface area of the neocortex. The larger this area is, the greater the mental abilities of an animal.", "situation": "Matt is studying the brains of two different mammals. He knows that one brain belongs to a mouse and the other brain belongs to a gorilla, but is not sure which brain belongs to which mammal. To determine this, he observes the neocortex of each brain and finds that the neocortex of Brain A is relatively smooth and the neocortex of Brain B has many more folds. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Brain A more or less likely to belong to the mouse than Brain B?", "id": "4281159072", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "The brains of all mammals have a unique layer of nerve cells covering the cerebrum. This layer is called the neocortex (the pink region of the brains in Figure above ). The neocortex plays an important role in many complex brain functions. In some mammals, such as rats, the neocortex is relatively smooth. In other mammals, especially humans, the neocortex has many folds. The folds increase the surface area of the neocortex. The larger this area is, the greater the mental abilities of an animal.", "situation": "Matt is studying the brains of two different mammals. He knows that one brain belongs to a mouse and the other brain belongs to a gorilla, but is not sure which brain belongs to which mammal. To determine this, he observes the neocortex of each brain and finds that the neocortex of Brain A is relatively smooth and the neocortex of Brain B has many more folds. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Brain A more or less likely to belong to the ape than Brain B?", "id": "1606831277", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Another example of negative feedback has to do with blood glucose levels. When glucose (sugar) levels in the blood are too high, the pancreas secretes insulin to stimulate the absorption of glucose and the conversion of glucose into glycogen, which is stored in the liver. As blood glucose levels decrease, less insulin is produced. When glucose levels are too low, another hormone called glucagon is produced, which causes the liver to convert glycogen back to glucose.", "situation": "Jackie and her husband Ken recently had an annual physical with their primary care physician. After they received their lab results, Jackie was told that her blood sugar levels were too high, and Ken was told that his blood sugar levels were too low. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Jackie's pancreas produce more or less insulin than Ken's pancreas?", "id": "1194795259", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Another example of negative feedback has to do with blood glucose levels. When glucose (sugar) levels in the blood are too high, the pancreas secretes insulin to stimulate the absorption of glucose and the conversion of glucose into glycogen, which is stored in the liver. As blood glucose levels decrease, less insulin is produced. When glucose levels are too low, another hormone called glucagon is produced, which causes the liver to convert glycogen back to glucose.", "situation": "Jackie and her husband Ken recently had an annual physical with their primary care physician. After they received their lab results, Jackie was told that her blood sugar levels were too high, and Ken was told that his blood sugar levels were too low. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Ken's pancreas produce more or less insulin than Jackie's pancreas?", "id": "1143677179", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Another example of negative feedback has to do with blood glucose levels. When glucose (sugar) levels in the blood are too high, the pancreas secretes insulin to stimulate the absorption of glucose and the conversion of glucose into glycogen, which is stored in the liver. As blood glucose levels decrease, less insulin is produced. When glucose levels are too low, another hormone called glucagon is produced, which causes the liver to convert glycogen back to glucose.", "situation": "Jackie and her husband Ken recently had an annual physical with their primary care physician. After they received their lab results, Jackie was told that her blood sugar levels were too high, and Ken was told that his blood sugar levels were too low. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Jackie's pancreas more or less likely to produce more insulin than Ken?", "id": "2128421272", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Another example of negative feedback has to do with blood glucose levels. When glucose (sugar) levels in the blood are too high, the pancreas secretes insulin to stimulate the absorption of glucose and the conversion of glucose into glycogen, which is stored in the liver. As blood glucose levels decrease, less insulin is produced. When glucose levels are too low, another hormone called glucagon is produced, which causes the liver to convert glycogen back to glucose.", "situation": "Jackie and her husband Ken recently had an annual physical with their primary care physician. After they received their lab results, Jackie was told that her blood sugar levels were too high, and Ken was told that his blood sugar levels were too low. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Ken's pancreas more or less likely to produce more insulin than Jackie?", "id": "2062164376", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Another example of negative feedback has to do with blood glucose levels. When glucose (sugar) levels in the blood are too high, the pancreas secretes insulin to stimulate the absorption of glucose and the conversion of glucose into glycogen, which is stored in the liver. As blood glucose levels decrease, less insulin is produced. When glucose levels are too low, another hormone called glucagon is produced, which causes the liver to convert glycogen back to glucose.", "situation": "Jackie and her husband Ken recently had an annual physical with their primary care physician. After they received their lab results, Jackie was told that her blood sugar levels were too high, and Ken was told that his blood sugar levels were too low. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is more likely to produce glucagon, Jackie or Ken?", "id": "721689092", "answers": [{"text": "Ken"}]}]}, {"background": "Another example of negative feedback has to do with blood glucose levels. When glucose (sugar) levels in the blood are too high, the pancreas secretes insulin to stimulate the absorption of glucose and the conversion of glucose into glycogen, which is stored in the liver. As blood glucose levels decrease, less insulin is produced. When glucose levels are too low, another hormone called glucagon is produced, which causes the liver to convert glycogen back to glucose.", "situation": "Jackie and her husband Ken recently had an annual physical with their primary care physician. After they received their lab results, Jackie was told that her blood sugar levels were too high, and Ken was told that his blood sugar levels were too low. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is less likely to produce glucagon, Jackie or Ken?", "id": "731781640", "answers": [{"text": "Jackie"}]}]}, {"background": "The parts of the ears involved in balance are the semicircular canals . Above, the semicircular canals are colored purple ( Figure above ). The canals contain liquid and are like the bottle of water pictured below ( Figure below ). When the bottle tips, the water surface moves up and down the sides of the bottle. When the body tips, the liquid in the semicircular canals moves up and down the sides of the canals. Tiny hair cells line the semicircular canals. Movement of the liquid inside the canals causes the hair cells to send nerve impulses. The nerve impulses travel to the cerebellum in the brain along the vestibular nerve. In response, the cerebellum sends commands to muscles to contract or relax so that the body stays balanced.", "situation": "Terri and Brian have appointments with an ENT to discuss some symptoms they have been having. During the exam, Terri's doctor tells her that the structures in her ear appear to be fine. Brian's doctor tells him that it appears as though he has suffered some damage to his semicircular canals.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is more likely to have problems staying balanced, Terri or Brian?", "id": "2671152586", "answers": [{"text": "Brian"}]}]}, {"background": "The parts of the ears involved in balance are the semicircular canals . Above, the semicircular canals are colored purple ( Figure above ). The canals contain liquid and are like the bottle of water pictured below ( Figure below ). When the bottle tips, the water surface moves up and down the sides of the bottle. When the body tips, the liquid in the semicircular canals moves up and down the sides of the canals. Tiny hair cells line the semicircular canals. Movement of the liquid inside the canals causes the hair cells to send nerve impulses. The nerve impulses travel to the cerebellum in the brain along the vestibular nerve. In response, the cerebellum sends commands to muscles to contract or relax so that the body stays balanced.", "situation": "Terri and Brian have appointments with an ENT to discuss some symptoms they have been having. During the exam, Terri's doctor tells her that the structures in her ear appear to be fine. Brian's doctor tells him that it appears as though he has suffered some damage to his semicircular canals.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is less likely to have problems staying balanced, Terri or Brian?", "id": "2685177294", "answers": [{"text": "Terri"}]}]}, {"background": "The parts of the ears involved in balance are the semicircular canals . Above, the semicircular canals are colored purple ( Figure above ). The canals contain liquid and are like the bottle of water pictured below ( Figure below ). When the bottle tips, the water surface moves up and down the sides of the bottle. When the body tips, the liquid in the semicircular canals moves up and down the sides of the canals. Tiny hair cells line the semicircular canals. Movement of the liquid inside the canals causes the hair cells to send nerve impulses. The nerve impulses travel to the cerebellum in the brain along the vestibular nerve. In response, the cerebellum sends commands to muscles to contract or relax so that the body stays balanced.", "situation": "Terri and Brian have appointments with an ENT to discuss some symptoms they have been having. During the exam, Terri's doctor tells her that the structures in her ear appear to be fine. Brian's doctor tells him that it appears as though he has suffered some damage to his semicircular canals.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Terri more or less likely than Brian to have trouble staying balanced?", "id": "3443101547", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "The parts of the ears involved in balance are the semicircular canals . Above, the semicircular canals are colored purple ( Figure above ). The canals contain liquid and are like the bottle of water pictured below ( Figure below ). When the bottle tips, the water surface moves up and down the sides of the bottle. When the body tips, the liquid in the semicircular canals moves up and down the sides of the canals. Tiny hair cells line the semicircular canals. Movement of the liquid inside the canals causes the hair cells to send nerve impulses. The nerve impulses travel to the cerebellum in the brain along the vestibular nerve. In response, the cerebellum sends commands to muscles to contract or relax so that the body stays balanced.", "situation": "Terri and Brian have appointments with an ENT to discuss some symptoms they have been having. During the exam, Terri's doctor tells her that the structures in her ear appear to be fine. Brian's doctor tells him that it appears as though he has suffered some damage to his semicircular canals.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Brian more or less likely than Terri to have trouble staying balanced?", "id": "3390279531", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Dr. Smith is examining the medical records of two of her patients to get a better understanding of their medical history, what factors contribute to the difference in health between the two patients, and what factors contribute to their health at present. Patient A is a 66 year old male and Patient B is a 22 year old male.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Patient A's reflex time be faster or slower than Patient B?", "id": "2653963425", "answers": [{"text": "slower"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Dr. Smith is examining the medical records of two of her patients to get a better understanding of their medical history, what factors contribute to the difference in health between the two patients, and what factors contribute to their health at present. Patient A is a 66 year old male and Patient B is a 22 year old male.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Patient B's reflex time be faster or slower than Patient A?", "id": "2657174689", "answers": [{"text": "faster"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Dr. Smith is examining the medical records of two of her patients to get a better understanding of their medical history, what factors contribute to the difference in health between the two patients, and what factors contribute to their health at present. Patient A is a 66 year old male and Patient B is a 22 year old male.", "qas": [{"question": "Which patient will likely have more brain cells, Patient A or Patient B?", "id": "4000728979", "answers": [{"text": "Patient B"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Dr. Smith is examining the medical records of two of her patients to get a better understanding of their medical history, what factors contribute to the difference in health between the two patients, and what factors contribute to their health at present. Patient A is a 66 year old male and Patient B is a 22 year old male.", "qas": [{"question": "Which patient will likely have fewer brain cells, Patient A or Patient B?", "id": "949241849", "answers": [{"text": "Patient A"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Dr. Smith is examining the medical records of two of her patients to get a better understanding of their medical history, what factors contribute to the difference in health between the two patients, and what factors contribute to their health at present. Patient A is a 66 year old male and Patient B is a 22 year old male.", "qas": [{"question": "Who has a higher risk of developing a serious illness, Patient A or Patient B?", "id": "2387167637", "answers": [{"text": "Patient A"}]}]}, {"background": "Old age begins in the mid-60s and lasts until the end of life. Most people over 65 have retired from work, freeing up their time for hobbies, grandchildren, and other interests. Stamina, strength, reflex time, and the senses all decline during old age, and the number of brain cells decreases as well. The immune system becomes less efficient, increasing the risk of serious illnesses such as cancer and pneumonia. Diseases such as Alzheimer\u2019s disease that cause loss of mental function also become more common.", "situation": "Dr. Smith is examining the medical records of two of her patients to get a better understanding of their medical history, what factors contribute to the difference in health between the two patients, and what factors contribute to their health at present. Patient A is a 66 year old male and Patient B is a 22 year old male.", "qas": [{"question": "Who has a lower risk of developing a serious illness, Patient A or Patient B?", "id": "1210861895", "answers": [{"text": "Patient B"}]}]}, {"background": "Electrons can be removed from some objects using friction, simply by rubbing one substance against another substance. There are many examples of objects becoming charged by friction, including a rubber comb through hair, and a balloon on a sweater. In both these instances, the electrons move from the second object to the first, causing the first object to become negatively charged and the second one positively charged. Friction between the tires on a moving car and the road cause the tires to become charged, and wind causes friction between clouds and air which causes clouds to become charged and can result in tremendous bolts of lightning.", "situation": "Iris notices that while brushing her cat, especially on cold and dry days, she can hear a crackling sound. She also notices that after she is done brushing, her cat's hair stands on end and is attracted to the brush. ", "qas": [{"question": "Before Iris brushes her cat, does her cat\u2019s fur have an electrical charge?", "id": "2952287862", "answers": [{"text": "no"}]}]}, {"background": "Electrons can be removed from some objects using friction, simply by rubbing one substance against another substance. There are many examples of objects becoming charged by friction, including a rubber comb through hair, and a balloon on a sweater. In both these instances, the electrons move from the second object to the first, causing the first object to become negatively charged and the second one positively charged. Friction between the tires on a moving car and the road cause the tires to become charged, and wind causes friction between clouds and air which causes clouds to become charged and can result in tremendous bolts of lightning.", "situation": "Iris notices that while brushing her cat, especially on cold and dry days, she can hear a crackling sound. She also notices that after she is done brushing, her cat's hair stands on end and is attracted to the brush. ", "qas": [{"question": "Before Iris brushes her cat, does the brush have an electrical charge?", "id": "2578928521", "answers": [{"text": "no"}]}]}, {"background": "Electrons can be removed from some objects using friction, simply by rubbing one substance against another substance. There are many examples of objects becoming charged by friction, including a rubber comb through hair, and a balloon on a sweater. In both these instances, the electrons move from the second object to the first, causing the first object to become negatively charged and the second one positively charged. Friction between the tires on a moving car and the road cause the tires to become charged, and wind causes friction between clouds and air which causes clouds to become charged and can result in tremendous bolts of lightning.", "situation": "Iris notices that while brushing her cat, especially on cold and dry days, she can hear a crackling sound. She also notices that after she is done brushing, her cat's hair stands on end and is attracted to the brush. ", "qas": [{"question": "After brushing her cat, do the cat and the brush have the same charge or a different charge? ", "id": "1693866766", "answers": [{"text": "different"}]}]}, {"background": "Light may transfer its energy to matter rather than being reflected or transmitted by matter. This is called absorption . When light is absorbed, the added energy increases the temperature of matter. If you get into a car that has been sitting in the sun all day, the seats and other parts of the car\u2019s interior may be almost too hot to touch, especially if they are black or very dark in color. That\u2019s because dark colors absorb most of the sunlight that strikes them.", "situation": "Heather and Jen are running a marathon together. The weather is sunny and perfect for a day of running outside. Heather dresses for the marathon in a light-colored shirt and shorts. Jen dresses in a black t-shirt and black shorts. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is more likely to get hotter during the marathon, Heather or Jen? ", "id": "1106974992", "answers": [{"text": "Jen"}]}]}, {"background": "Light may transfer its energy to matter rather than being reflected or transmitted by matter. This is called absorption . When light is absorbed, the added energy increases the temperature of matter. If you get into a car that has been sitting in the sun all day, the seats and other parts of the car\u2019s interior may be almost too hot to touch, especially if they are black or very dark in color. That\u2019s because dark colors absorb most of the sunlight that strikes them.", "situation": "Heather and Jen are running a marathon together. The weather is sunny and perfect for a day of running outside. Heather dresses for the marathon in a light-colored shirt and shorts. Jen dresses in a black t-shirt and black shorts. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is more likely to stay cooler during the marathon, Heather or Jen? ", "id": "1603148159", "answers": [{"text": "Heather"}]}]}, {"background": "Light may transfer its energy to matter rather than being reflected or transmitted by matter. This is called absorption . When light is absorbed, the added energy increases the temperature of matter. If you get into a car that has been sitting in the sun all day, the seats and other parts of the car\u2019s interior may be almost too hot to touch, especially if they are black or very dark in color. That\u2019s because dark colors absorb most of the sunlight that strikes them.", "situation": "Heather and Jen are running a marathon together. The weather is sunny and perfect for a day of running outside. Heather dresses for the marathon in a light-colored shirt and shorts. Jen dresses in a black t-shirt and black shorts. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Heather\u2019s clothes absorb more or less light than Jen\u2019s clothes? ", "id": "3779271806", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Light may transfer its energy to matter rather than being reflected or transmitted by matter. This is called absorption . When light is absorbed, the added energy increases the temperature of matter. If you get into a car that has been sitting in the sun all day, the seats and other parts of the car\u2019s interior may be almost too hot to touch, especially if they are black or very dark in color. That\u2019s because dark colors absorb most of the sunlight that strikes them.", "situation": "Heather and Jen are running a marathon together. The weather is sunny and perfect for a day of running outside. Heather dresses for the marathon in a light-colored shirt and shorts. Jen dresses in a black t-shirt and black shorts. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Jen's clothes absorb more or less light than Heather\u2019s clothes? ", "id": "1624840874", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Light may transfer its energy to matter rather than being reflected or transmitted by matter. This is called absorption . When light is absorbed, the added energy increases the temperature of matter. If you get into a car that has been sitting in the sun all day, the seats and other parts of the car\u2019s interior may be almost too hot to touch, especially if they are black or very dark in color. That\u2019s because dark colors absorb most of the sunlight that strikes them.", "situation": "Heather and Jen are running a marathon together. The weather is sunny and perfect for a day of running outside. Heather dresses for the marathon in a light-colored shirt and shorts. Jen dresses in a black t-shirt and black shorts. ", "qas": [{"question": "If Jen touched Heather\u2019s shirt, would it feel hotter or cooler than her own shirt? ", "id": "331292549", "answers": [{"text": "cooler"}]}]}, {"background": "Light may transfer its energy to matter rather than being reflected or transmitted by matter. This is called absorption . When light is absorbed, the added energy increases the temperature of matter. If you get into a car that has been sitting in the sun all day, the seats and other parts of the car\u2019s interior may be almost too hot to touch, especially if they are black or very dark in color. That\u2019s because dark colors absorb most of the sunlight that strikes them.", "situation": "Heather and Jen are running a marathon together. The weather is sunny and perfect for a day of running outside. Heather dresses for the marathon in a light-colored shirt and shorts. Jen dresses in a black t-shirt and black shorts. ", "qas": [{"question": "If Heather touched Jen\u2019s shirt, would it feel hotter or cooler than her own shirt? ", "id": "374022021", "answers": [{"text": "hotter"}]}]}, {"background": "Light may transfer its energy to matter rather than being reflected or transmitted by matter. This is called absorption . When light is absorbed, the added energy increases the temperature of matter. If you get into a car that has been sitting in the sun all day, the seats and other parts of the car\u2019s interior may be almost too hot to touch, especially if they are black or very dark in color. That\u2019s because dark colors absorb most of the sunlight that strikes them.", "situation": "Heather and Jen are running a marathon together. The weather is sunny and perfect for a day of running outside. Heather dresses for the marathon in a light-colored shirt and shorts. Jen dresses in a black t-shirt and black shorts. ", "qas": [{"question": "If the day of the race was cloudy rather than sunny, would Heather\u2019s shirt be cooler, hotter, or the same temperature as Jen\u2019s shirt? ", "id": "1962292081", "answers": [{"text": "the same"}]}]}, {"background": "Cholesterol has been implicated in heart disease for decades. Atherosclerosis is a disorder of the arteries in which cholesterol and other materials are deposited on the interior of the arterial wall. These deposits lead to the formation of plaques that can restrict or even block the flow of blood through these blood vessels (see Figure below ). A decrease in the flow of blood can lead to high blood pressure and a lowered oxygen supply to the heart muscle. A complete blockage of blood flow to parts of the heart (a heart attack) can cause significant damage due to oxygen deprivation, in some cases leading to death.", "situation": "Worried about their cholesterol levels, Bob and Pauline have labs drawn to see if they need to make any lifestyle changes. Pauline's cholesterol levels are determined to be within normal limits. However, Bob learns that his LDL cholesterol level is too high. To further assess Bob's health, his doctor orders a series of tests and it is determined that Bob has atherosclerosis. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Bob more or less likely to have high blood pressure than Pauline?", "id": "1270514335", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Cholesterol has been implicated in heart disease for decades. Atherosclerosis is a disorder of the arteries in which cholesterol and other materials are deposited on the interior of the arterial wall. These deposits lead to the formation of plaques that can restrict or even block the flow of blood through these blood vessels (see Figure below ). A decrease in the flow of blood can lead to high blood pressure and a lowered oxygen supply to the heart muscle. A complete blockage of blood flow to parts of the heart (a heart attack) can cause significant damage due to oxygen deprivation, in some cases leading to death.", "situation": "Worried about their cholesterol levels, Bob and Pauline have labs drawn to see if they need to make any lifestyle changes. Pauline's cholesterol levels are determined to be within normal limits. However, Bob learns that his LDL cholesterol level is too high. To further assess Bob's health, his doctor orders a series of tests and it is determined that Bob has atherosclerosis. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Pauline more or less likely to have high blood pressure than Bob?", "id": "1540457119", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Cholesterol has been implicated in heart disease for decades. Atherosclerosis is a disorder of the arteries in which cholesterol and other materials are deposited on the interior of the arterial wall. These deposits lead to the formation of plaques that can restrict or even block the flow of blood through these blood vessels (see Figure below ). A decrease in the flow of blood can lead to high blood pressure and a lowered oxygen supply to the heart muscle. A complete blockage of blood flow to parts of the heart (a heart attack) can cause significant damage due to oxygen deprivation, in some cases leading to death.", "situation": "Worried about their cholesterol levels, Bob and Pauline have labs drawn to see if they need to make any lifestyle changes. Pauline's cholesterol levels are determined to be within normal limits. However, Bob learns that his LDL cholesterol level is too high. To further assess Bob's health, his doctor orders a series of tests and it is determined that Bob has atherosclerosis. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is at greater risk for a heart attack, Bob or Pauline?", "id": "1089633878", "answers": [{"text": "Bob"}]}]}, {"background": "Cholesterol has been implicated in heart disease for decades. Atherosclerosis is a disorder of the arteries in which cholesterol and other materials are deposited on the interior of the arterial wall. These deposits lead to the formation of plaques that can restrict or even block the flow of blood through these blood vessels (see Figure below ). A decrease in the flow of blood can lead to high blood pressure and a lowered oxygen supply to the heart muscle. A complete blockage of blood flow to parts of the heart (a heart attack) can cause significant damage due to oxygen deprivation, in some cases leading to death.", "situation": "Worried about their cholesterol levels, Bob and Pauline have labs drawn to see if they need to make any lifestyle changes. Pauline's cholesterol levels are determined to be within normal limits. However, Bob learns that his LDL cholesterol level is too high. To further assess Bob's health, his doctor orders a series of tests and it is determined that Bob has atherosclerosis. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is least likely to have a heart attack, Bob or Pauline?", "id": "3290267329", "answers": [{"text": "Pauline"}]}]}, {"background": "Cholesterol has been implicated in heart disease for decades. Atherosclerosis is a disorder of the arteries in which cholesterol and other materials are deposited on the interior of the arterial wall. These deposits lead to the formation of plaques that can restrict or even block the flow of blood through these blood vessels (see Figure below ). A decrease in the flow of blood can lead to high blood pressure and a lowered oxygen supply to the heart muscle. A complete blockage of blood flow to parts of the heart (a heart attack) can cause significant damage due to oxygen deprivation, in some cases leading to death.", "situation": "Worried about their cholesterol levels, Bob and Pauline have labs drawn to see if they need to make any lifestyle changes. Pauline's cholesterol levels are determined to be within normal limits. However, Bob learns that his LDL cholesterol level is too high. To further assess Bob's health, his doctor orders a series of tests and it is determined that Bob has atherosclerosis. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is more likely to have plaque buildup in their arteries, Bob or Pauline?", "id": "2206041469", "answers": [{"text": "Bob"}]}]}, {"background": "Cholesterol has been implicated in heart disease for decades. Atherosclerosis is a disorder of the arteries in which cholesterol and other materials are deposited on the interior of the arterial wall. These deposits lead to the formation of plaques that can restrict or even block the flow of blood through these blood vessels (see Figure below ). A decrease in the flow of blood can lead to high blood pressure and a lowered oxygen supply to the heart muscle. A complete blockage of blood flow to parts of the heart (a heart attack) can cause significant damage due to oxygen deprivation, in some cases leading to death.", "situation": "Worried about their cholesterol levels, Bob and Pauline have labs drawn to see if they need to make any lifestyle changes. Pauline's cholesterol levels are determined to be within normal limits. However, Bob learns that his LDL cholesterol level is too high. To further assess Bob's health, his doctor orders a series of tests and it is determined that Bob has atherosclerosis. ", "qas": [{"question": "Who is least likely to have plaque buildup in their arteries, Bob or Pauline?", "id": "196249059", "answers": [{"text": "Pauline"}]}]}, {"background": "Cholesterol has been implicated in heart disease for decades. Atherosclerosis is a disorder of the arteries in which cholesterol and other materials are deposited on the interior of the arterial wall. These deposits lead to the formation of plaques that can restrict or even block the flow of blood through these blood vessels (see Figure below ). A decrease in the flow of blood can lead to high blood pressure and a lowered oxygen supply to the heart muscle. A complete blockage of blood flow to parts of the heart (a heart attack) can cause significant damage due to oxygen deprivation, in some cases leading to death.", "situation": "Worried about their cholesterol levels, Bob and Pauline have labs drawn to see if they need to make any lifestyle changes. Pauline's cholesterol levels are determined to be within normal limits. However, Bob learns that his LDL cholesterol level is too high. To further assess Bob's health, his doctor orders a series of tests and it is determined that Bob has atherosclerosis. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Bob or Pauline more likely to develop heart disease?", "id": "3371924977", "answers": [{"text": "Bob"}]}]}, {"background": "Cholesterol has been implicated in heart disease for decades. Atherosclerosis is a disorder of the arteries in which cholesterol and other materials are deposited on the interior of the arterial wall. These deposits lead to the formation of plaques that can restrict or even block the flow of blood through these blood vessels (see Figure below ). A decrease in the flow of blood can lead to high blood pressure and a lowered oxygen supply to the heart muscle. A complete blockage of blood flow to parts of the heart (a heart attack) can cause significant damage due to oxygen deprivation, in some cases leading to death.", "situation": "Worried about their cholesterol levels, Bob and Pauline have labs drawn to see if they need to make any lifestyle changes. Pauline's cholesterol levels are determined to be within normal limits. However, Bob learns that his LDL cholesterol level is too high. To further assess Bob's health, his doctor orders a series of tests and it is determined that Bob has atherosclerosis. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Bob or Pauline least likely to develop heart disease?", "id": "1210351191", "answers": [{"text": "Pauline"}]}]}, {"background": "Cholesterol has been implicated in heart disease for decades. Atherosclerosis is a disorder of the arteries in which cholesterol and other materials are deposited on the interior of the arterial wall. These deposits lead to the formation of plaques that can restrict or even block the flow of blood through these blood vessels (see Figure below ). A decrease in the flow of blood can lead to high blood pressure and a lowered oxygen supply to the heart muscle. A complete blockage of blood flow to parts of the heart (a heart attack) can cause significant damage due to oxygen deprivation, in some cases leading to death.", "situation": "Worried about their cholesterol levels, Bob and Pauline have labs drawn to see if they need to make any lifestyle changes. Pauline's cholesterol levels are determined to be within normal limits. However, Bob learns that his LDL cholesterol level is too high. To further assess Bob's health, his doctor orders a series of tests and it is determined that Bob has atherosclerosis. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Bob or Pauline least likely to experience a reduced oxygen supply to the heart?", "id": "2714994682", "answers": [{"text": "Pauline"}]}]}, {"background": "Cholesterol has been implicated in heart disease for decades. Atherosclerosis is a disorder of the arteries in which cholesterol and other materials are deposited on the interior of the arterial wall. These deposits lead to the formation of plaques that can restrict or even block the flow of blood through these blood vessels (see Figure below ). A decrease in the flow of blood can lead to high blood pressure and a lowered oxygen supply to the heart muscle. A complete blockage of blood flow to parts of the heart (a heart attack) can cause significant damage due to oxygen deprivation, in some cases leading to death.", "situation": "Worried about their cholesterol levels, Bob and Pauline have labs drawn to see if they need to make any lifestyle changes. Pauline's cholesterol levels are determined to be within normal limits. However, Bob learns that his LDL cholesterol level is too high. To further assess Bob's health, his doctor orders a series of tests and it is determined that Bob has atherosclerosis. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Bob or Pauline more likely to experience a reduced oxygen supply to the heart?", "id": "408782740", "answers": [{"text": "Bob"}]}]}, {"background": "The strength of acids and bases is measured on a scale called the pH scale, which is shown in the Figure below . By definition, pH represents the acidity , or hydrogen ion (H + ) concentration, of a solution. Pure water, which is neutral, has a pH of 7. With a higher the concentration of hydrogen ions, a solution is more acidic and has a lower pH. Acids have a pH less than 7, and the strongest acids have a pH close to zero. Bases have a pH greater than 7, and the strongest bases have a pH close to 14. It\u2019s important to realize that the pH scale is based on powers of ten. For example, a solution with a pH of 8 is 10 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7, and a solution with a pH of 9 is 100 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7.", "situation": "Sally is taking a college chemistry class. She is trying to determine whether her test substances are an acid or a base. After using test strips to determine the concentration of hydrogen ions in each substance, she learns that Substance A has a pH of 1, Substance B has a pH of 3, Substance C has a pH of 7, Substance D has a pH of 10, and Substance E has a pH of 13.   ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Substance A an acid, base, or neutral?", "id": "4241855045", "answers": [{"text": "acid"}]}]}, {"background": "The strength of acids and bases is measured on a scale called the pH scale, which is shown in the Figure below . By definition, pH represents the acidity , or hydrogen ion (H + ) concentration, of a solution. Pure water, which is neutral, has a pH of 7. With a higher the concentration of hydrogen ions, a solution is more acidic and has a lower pH. Acids have a pH less than 7, and the strongest acids have a pH close to zero. Bases have a pH greater than 7, and the strongest bases have a pH close to 14. It\u2019s important to realize that the pH scale is based on powers of ten. For example, a solution with a pH of 8 is 10 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7, and a solution with a pH of 9 is 100 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7.", "situation": "Sally is taking a college chemistry class. She is trying to determine whether her test substances are an acid or a base. After using test strips to determine the concentration of hydrogen ions in each substance, she learns that Substance A has a pH of 1, Substance B has a pH of 3, Substance C has a pH of 7, Substance D has a pH of 10, and Substance E has a pH of 13.   ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Substance B an acid, base, or neutral?", "id": "4243690054", "answers": [{"text": "acid"}]}]}, {"background": "The strength of acids and bases is measured on a scale called the pH scale, which is shown in the Figure below . By definition, pH represents the acidity , or hydrogen ion (H + ) concentration, of a solution. Pure water, which is neutral, has a pH of 7. With a higher the concentration of hydrogen ions, a solution is more acidic and has a lower pH. Acids have a pH less than 7, and the strongest acids have a pH close to zero. Bases have a pH greater than 7, and the strongest bases have a pH close to 14. It\u2019s important to realize that the pH scale is based on powers of ten. For example, a solution with a pH of 8 is 10 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7, and a solution with a pH of 9 is 100 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7.", "situation": "Sally is taking a college chemistry class. She is trying to determine whether her test substances are an acid or a base. After using test strips to determine the concentration of hydrogen ions in each substance, she learns that Substance A has a pH of 1, Substance B has a pH of 3, Substance C has a pH of 7, Substance D has a pH of 10, and Substance E has a pH of 13.   ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Substance C an acid, base, or neutral?", "id": "4245525063", "answers": [{"text": "neutral"}]}]}, {"background": "The strength of acids and bases is measured on a scale called the pH scale, which is shown in the Figure below . By definition, pH represents the acidity , or hydrogen ion (H + ) concentration, of a solution. Pure water, which is neutral, has a pH of 7. With a higher the concentration of hydrogen ions, a solution is more acidic and has a lower pH. Acids have a pH less than 7, and the strongest acids have a pH close to zero. Bases have a pH greater than 7, and the strongest bases have a pH close to 14. It\u2019s important to realize that the pH scale is based on powers of ten. For example, a solution with a pH of 8 is 10 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7, and a solution with a pH of 9 is 100 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7.", "situation": "Sally is taking a college chemistry class. She is trying to determine whether her test substances are an acid or a base. After using test strips to determine the concentration of hydrogen ions in each substance, she learns that Substance A has a pH of 1, Substance B has a pH of 3, Substance C has a pH of 7, Substance D has a pH of 10, and Substance E has a pH of 13.   ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Substance D an acid, base, or neutral?", "id": "4247360072", "answers": [{"text": "base"}]}]}, {"background": "The strength of acids and bases is measured on a scale called the pH scale, which is shown in the Figure below . By definition, pH represents the acidity , or hydrogen ion (H + ) concentration, of a solution. Pure water, which is neutral, has a pH of 7. With a higher the concentration of hydrogen ions, a solution is more acidic and has a lower pH. Acids have a pH less than 7, and the strongest acids have a pH close to zero. Bases have a pH greater than 7, and the strongest bases have a pH close to 14. It\u2019s important to realize that the pH scale is based on powers of ten. For example, a solution with a pH of 8 is 10 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7, and a solution with a pH of 9 is 100 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7.", "situation": "Sally is taking a college chemistry class. She is trying to determine whether her test substances are an acid or a base. After using test strips to determine the concentration of hydrogen ions in each substance, she learns that Substance A has a pH of 1, Substance B has a pH of 3, Substance C has a pH of 7, Substance D has a pH of 10, and Substance E has a pH of 13.   ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Substance E an acid, base, or neutral?", "id": "4249195081", "answers": [{"text": "base"}]}]}, {"background": "The strength of acids and bases is measured on a scale called the pH scale, which is shown in the Figure below . By definition, pH represents the acidity , or hydrogen ion (H + ) concentration, of a solution. Pure water, which is neutral, has a pH of 7. With a higher the concentration of hydrogen ions, a solution is more acidic and has a lower pH. Acids have a pH less than 7, and the strongest acids have a pH close to zero. Bases have a pH greater than 7, and the strongest bases have a pH close to 14. It\u2019s important to realize that the pH scale is based on powers of ten. For example, a solution with a pH of 8 is 10 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7, and a solution with a pH of 9 is 100 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7.", "situation": "Sally is taking a college chemistry class. She is trying to determine whether her test substances are an acid or a base. After using test strips to determine the concentration of hydrogen ions in each substance, she learns that Substance A has a pH of 1, Substance B has a pH of 3, Substance C has a pH of 7, Substance D has a pH of 10, and Substance E has a pH of 13.   ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Substance A a stronger or weaker acid than Substance B?", "id": "56858833", "answers": [{"text": "stronger"}]}]}, {"background": "The strength of acids and bases is measured on a scale called the pH scale, which is shown in the Figure below . By definition, pH represents the acidity , or hydrogen ion (H + ) concentration, of a solution. Pure water, which is neutral, has a pH of 7. With a higher the concentration of hydrogen ions, a solution is more acidic and has a lower pH. Acids have a pH less than 7, and the strongest acids have a pH close to zero. Bases have a pH greater than 7, and the strongest bases have a pH close to 14. It\u2019s important to realize that the pH scale is based on powers of ten. For example, a solution with a pH of 8 is 10 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7, and a solution with a pH of 9 is 100 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7.", "situation": "Sally is taking a college chemistry class. She is trying to determine whether her test substances are an acid or a base. After using test strips to determine the concentration of hydrogen ions in each substance, she learns that Substance A has a pH of 1, Substance B has a pH of 3, Substance C has a pH of 7, Substance D has a pH of 10, and Substance E has a pH of 13.   ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Substance B a stronger or weaker acid than Substance A?", "id": "59676881", "answers": [{"text": "weaker"}]}]}, {"background": "The strength of acids and bases is measured on a scale called the pH scale, which is shown in the Figure below . By definition, pH represents the acidity , or hydrogen ion (H + ) concentration, of a solution. Pure water, which is neutral, has a pH of 7. With a higher the concentration of hydrogen ions, a solution is more acidic and has a lower pH. Acids have a pH less than 7, and the strongest acids have a pH close to zero. Bases have a pH greater than 7, and the strongest bases have a pH close to 14. It\u2019s important to realize that the pH scale is based on powers of ten. For example, a solution with a pH of 8 is 10 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7, and a solution with a pH of 9 is 100 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7.", "situation": "Sally is taking a college chemistry class. She is trying to determine whether her test substances are an acid or a base. After using test strips to determine the concentration of hydrogen ions in each substance, she learns that Substance A has a pH of 1, Substance B has a pH of 3, Substance C has a pH of 7, Substance D has a pH of 10, and Substance E has a pH of 13.   ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Substance D a stronger or weaker base than Substance E?", "id": "79141089", "answers": [{"text": "weaker"}]}]}, {"background": "The strength of acids and bases is measured on a scale called the pH scale, which is shown in the Figure below . By definition, pH represents the acidity , or hydrogen ion (H + ) concentration, of a solution. Pure water, which is neutral, has a pH of 7. With a higher the concentration of hydrogen ions, a solution is more acidic and has a lower pH. Acids have a pH less than 7, and the strongest acids have a pH close to zero. Bases have a pH greater than 7, and the strongest bases have a pH close to 14. It\u2019s important to realize that the pH scale is based on powers of ten. For example, a solution with a pH of 8 is 10 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7, and a solution with a pH of 9 is 100 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7.", "situation": "Sally is taking a college chemistry class. She is trying to determine whether her test substances are an acid or a base. After using test strips to determine the concentration of hydrogen ions in each substance, she learns that Substance A has a pH of 1, Substance B has a pH of 3, Substance C has a pH of 7, Substance D has a pH of 10, and Substance E has a pH of 13.   ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Substance E a stronger or weaker base than Substance D?", "id": "81959137", "answers": [{"text": "stronger"}]}]}, {"background": "The strength of acids and bases is measured on a scale called the pH scale, which is shown in the Figure below . By definition, pH represents the acidity , or hydrogen ion (H + ) concentration, of a solution. Pure water, which is neutral, has a pH of 7. With a higher the concentration of hydrogen ions, a solution is more acidic and has a lower pH. Acids have a pH less than 7, and the strongest acids have a pH close to zero. Bases have a pH greater than 7, and the strongest bases have a pH close to 14. It\u2019s important to realize that the pH scale is based on powers of ten. For example, a solution with a pH of 8 is 10 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7, and a solution with a pH of 9 is 100 times more basic than a solution with a pH of 7.", "situation": "Sally is taking a college chemistry class. She is trying to determine whether her test substances are an acid or a base. After using test strips to determine the concentration of hydrogen ions in each substance, she learns that Substance A has a pH of 1, Substance B has a pH of 3, Substance C has a pH of 7, Substance D has a pH of 10, and Substance E has a pH of 13.   ", "qas": [{"question": "Of all the substances, which substance is most likely to be water?", "id": "3928464472", "answers": [{"text": "Substance C"}]}]}, {"background": "Similar to light zonation, thermal stratification or thermal zonation is a way of grouping parts of the water body within an aquatic system based on the temperature of different lake layers. The less turbid the water, the more light is able to penetrate, and thus heat is conveyed deeper in the water. Heating declines exponentially with depth in the water column, so the water will be warmest near the surface but progressively cooler as moving downwards. There are three main sections that define thermal stratification in a lake. The epilimnion is closest to the water surface and absorbs long- and shortwave radiation to warm the water surface. During cooler months, wind shear can contribute to cooling of the water surface. The thermocline is an area within the water column where water temperatures rapidly decrease. The bottom layer is the hypolimnion, which tends to have the coldest water because its depth restricts sunlight from reaching it.  In temperate lakes, fall-season cooling of surface water results in turnover of the water column, where the thermocline is disrupted, and the lake temperature profile becomes more uniform.", "situation": "Boris is deploying a camera probe in a lake to observe the different kinds of fish species that reside in each layer during the summer. In order to make sure he is at the right depth and thus in a different layer each time he makes observations, he needs to measure the water temperature. The temperature for Measurement A reads 75 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement B reads 55 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement C reads 40 degrees Fahrenheit. ", "qas": [{"question": "For which measurement is Boris most likely in the epilimnion?", "id": "1337681848", "answers": [{"text": "Measurement A"}]}]}, {"background": "Similar to light zonation, thermal stratification or thermal zonation is a way of grouping parts of the water body within an aquatic system based on the temperature of different lake layers. The less turbid the water, the more light is able to penetrate, and thus heat is conveyed deeper in the water. Heating declines exponentially with depth in the water column, so the water will be warmest near the surface but progressively cooler as moving downwards. There are three main sections that define thermal stratification in a lake. The epilimnion is closest to the water surface and absorbs long- and shortwave radiation to warm the water surface. During cooler months, wind shear can contribute to cooling of the water surface. The thermocline is an area within the water column where water temperatures rapidly decrease. The bottom layer is the hypolimnion, which tends to have the coldest water because its depth restricts sunlight from reaching it.  In temperate lakes, fall-season cooling of surface water results in turnover of the water column, where the thermocline is disrupted, and the lake temperature profile becomes more uniform.", "situation": "Boris is deploying a camera probe in a lake to observe the different kinds of fish species that reside in each layer during the summer. In order to make sure he is at the right depth and thus in a different layer each time he makes observations, he needs to measure the water temperature. The temperature for Measurement A reads 75 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement B reads 55 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement C reads 40 degrees Fahrenheit. ", "qas": [{"question": "For which measurement is Boris most likely in the thermocline?", "id": "3091949598", "answers": [{"text": "Measurement B"}]}]}, {"background": "Similar to light zonation, thermal stratification or thermal zonation is a way of grouping parts of the water body within an aquatic system based on the temperature of different lake layers. The less turbid the water, the more light is able to penetrate, and thus heat is conveyed deeper in the water. Heating declines exponentially with depth in the water column, so the water will be warmest near the surface but progressively cooler as moving downwards. There are three main sections that define thermal stratification in a lake. The epilimnion is closest to the water surface and absorbs long- and shortwave radiation to warm the water surface. During cooler months, wind shear can contribute to cooling of the water surface. The thermocline is an area within the water column where water temperatures rapidly decrease. The bottom layer is the hypolimnion, which tends to have the coldest water because its depth restricts sunlight from reaching it.  In temperate lakes, fall-season cooling of surface water results in turnover of the water column, where the thermocline is disrupted, and the lake temperature profile becomes more uniform.", "situation": "Boris is deploying a camera probe in a lake to observe the different kinds of fish species that reside in each layer during the summer. In order to make sure he is at the right depth and thus in a different layer each time he makes observations, he needs to measure the water temperature. The temperature for Measurement A reads 75 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement B reads 55 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement C reads 40 degrees Fahrenheit. ", "qas": [{"question": "For which measurement is Boris most likely in the hypolimnion?", "id": "3102894138", "answers": [{"text": "Measurement C"}]}]}, {"background": "Similar to light zonation, thermal stratification or thermal zonation is a way of grouping parts of the water body within an aquatic system based on the temperature of different lake layers. The less turbid the water, the more light is able to penetrate, and thus heat is conveyed deeper in the water. Heating declines exponentially with depth in the water column, so the water will be warmest near the surface but progressively cooler as moving downwards. There are three main sections that define thermal stratification in a lake. The epilimnion is closest to the water surface and absorbs long- and shortwave radiation to warm the water surface. During cooler months, wind shear can contribute to cooling of the water surface. The thermocline is an area within the water column where water temperatures rapidly decrease. The bottom layer is the hypolimnion, which tends to have the coldest water because its depth restricts sunlight from reaching it.  In temperate lakes, fall-season cooling of surface water results in turnover of the water column, where the thermocline is disrupted, and the lake temperature profile becomes more uniform.", "situation": "Boris is deploying a camera probe in a lake to observe the different kinds of fish species that reside in each layer during the summer. In order to make sure he is at the right depth and thus in a different layer each time he makes observations, he needs to measure the water temperature. The temperature for Measurement A reads 75 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement B reads 55 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement C reads 40 degrees Fahrenheit. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which layer was Measurement A most likely taken, the epilimnion, thermocline or hypolimnion?", "id": "3570365499", "answers": [{"text": "epilimnion"}]}]}, {"background": "Similar to light zonation, thermal stratification or thermal zonation is a way of grouping parts of the water body within an aquatic system based on the temperature of different lake layers. The less turbid the water, the more light is able to penetrate, and thus heat is conveyed deeper in the water. Heating declines exponentially with depth in the water column, so the water will be warmest near the surface but progressively cooler as moving downwards. There are three main sections that define thermal stratification in a lake. The epilimnion is closest to the water surface and absorbs long- and shortwave radiation to warm the water surface. During cooler months, wind shear can contribute to cooling of the water surface. The thermocline is an area within the water column where water temperatures rapidly decrease. The bottom layer is the hypolimnion, which tends to have the coldest water because its depth restricts sunlight from reaching it.  In temperate lakes, fall-season cooling of surface water results in turnover of the water column, where the thermocline is disrupted, and the lake temperature profile becomes more uniform.", "situation": "Boris is deploying a camera probe in a lake to observe the different kinds of fish species that reside in each layer during the summer. In order to make sure he is at the right depth and thus in a different layer each time he makes observations, he needs to measure the water temperature. The temperature for Measurement A reads 75 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement B reads 55 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement C reads 40 degrees Fahrenheit. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which layer was Measurement B most likely taken, the epilimnion, thermocline or hypolimnion?", "id": "3574559804", "answers": [{"text": "thermocline"}]}]}, {"background": "Similar to light zonation, thermal stratification or thermal zonation is a way of grouping parts of the water body within an aquatic system based on the temperature of different lake layers. The less turbid the water, the more light is able to penetrate, and thus heat is conveyed deeper in the water. Heating declines exponentially with depth in the water column, so the water will be warmest near the surface but progressively cooler as moving downwards. There are three main sections that define thermal stratification in a lake. The epilimnion is closest to the water surface and absorbs long- and shortwave radiation to warm the water surface. During cooler months, wind shear can contribute to cooling of the water surface. The thermocline is an area within the water column where water temperatures rapidly decrease. The bottom layer is the hypolimnion, which tends to have the coldest water because its depth restricts sunlight from reaching it.  In temperate lakes, fall-season cooling of surface water results in turnover of the water column, where the thermocline is disrupted, and the lake temperature profile becomes more uniform.", "situation": "Boris is deploying a camera probe in a lake to observe the different kinds of fish species that reside in each layer during the summer. In order to make sure he is at the right depth and thus in a different layer each time he makes observations, he needs to measure the water temperature. The temperature for Measurement A reads 75 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement B reads 55 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement C reads 40 degrees Fahrenheit. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which layer was Measurement C most likely taken, the epilimnion, thermocline or hypolimnion?", "id": "3578754109", "answers": [{"text": "hypolimnion"}]}]}, {"background": "Similar to light zonation, thermal stratification or thermal zonation is a way of grouping parts of the water body within an aquatic system based on the temperature of different lake layers. The less turbid the water, the more light is able to penetrate, and thus heat is conveyed deeper in the water. Heating declines exponentially with depth in the water column, so the water will be warmest near the surface but progressively cooler as moving downwards. There are three main sections that define thermal stratification in a lake. The epilimnion is closest to the water surface and absorbs long- and shortwave radiation to warm the water surface. During cooler months, wind shear can contribute to cooling of the water surface. The thermocline is an area within the water column where water temperatures rapidly decrease. The bottom layer is the hypolimnion, which tends to have the coldest water because its depth restricts sunlight from reaching it.  In temperate lakes, fall-season cooling of surface water results in turnover of the water column, where the thermocline is disrupted, and the lake temperature profile becomes more uniform.", "situation": "Boris is deploying a camera probe in a lake to observe the different kinds of fish species that reside in each layer during the summer. In order to make sure he is at the right depth and thus in a different layer each time he makes observations, he needs to measure the water temperature. The temperature for Measurement A reads 75 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement B reads 55 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement C reads 40 degrees Fahrenheit. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Measurement A or Measurement B most likely the epilimnion?", "id": "986146642", "answers": [{"text": "Measurement A"}]}]}, {"background": "Similar to light zonation, thermal stratification or thermal zonation is a way of grouping parts of the water body within an aquatic system based on the temperature of different lake layers. The less turbid the water, the more light is able to penetrate, and thus heat is conveyed deeper in the water. Heating declines exponentially with depth in the water column, so the water will be warmest near the surface but progressively cooler as moving downwards. There are three main sections that define thermal stratification in a lake. The epilimnion is closest to the water surface and absorbs long- and shortwave radiation to warm the water surface. During cooler months, wind shear can contribute to cooling of the water surface. The thermocline is an area within the water column where water temperatures rapidly decrease. The bottom layer is the hypolimnion, which tends to have the coldest water because its depth restricts sunlight from reaching it.  In temperate lakes, fall-season cooling of surface water results in turnover of the water column, where the thermocline is disrupted, and the lake temperature profile becomes more uniform.", "situation": "Boris is deploying a camera probe in a lake to observe the different kinds of fish species that reside in each layer during the summer. In order to make sure he is at the right depth and thus in a different layer each time he makes observations, he needs to measure the water temperature. The temperature for Measurement A reads 75 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement B reads 55 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement C reads 40 degrees Fahrenheit. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Measurement A or Measurement B most likely the thermocline?", "id": "2733729720", "answers": [{"text": "Measurement B"}]}]}, {"background": "Similar to light zonation, thermal stratification or thermal zonation is a way of grouping parts of the water body within an aquatic system based on the temperature of different lake layers. The less turbid the water, the more light is able to penetrate, and thus heat is conveyed deeper in the water. Heating declines exponentially with depth in the water column, so the water will be warmest near the surface but progressively cooler as moving downwards. There are three main sections that define thermal stratification in a lake. The epilimnion is closest to the water surface and absorbs long- and shortwave radiation to warm the water surface. During cooler months, wind shear can contribute to cooling of the water surface. The thermocline is an area within the water column where water temperatures rapidly decrease. The bottom layer is the hypolimnion, which tends to have the coldest water because its depth restricts sunlight from reaching it.  In temperate lakes, fall-season cooling of surface water results in turnover of the water column, where the thermocline is disrupted, and the lake temperature profile becomes more uniform.", "situation": "Boris is deploying a camera probe in a lake to observe the different kinds of fish species that reside in each layer during the summer. In order to make sure he is at the right depth and thus in a different layer each time he makes observations, he needs to measure the water temperature. The temperature for Measurement A reads 75 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement B reads 55 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement C reads 40 degrees Fahrenheit. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Measurement A or Measurement C most likely the hypolimnion?", "id": "2746640341", "answers": [{"text": "Measurement C"}]}]}, {"background": "Similar to light zonation, thermal stratification or thermal zonation is a way of grouping parts of the water body within an aquatic system based on the temperature of different lake layers. The less turbid the water, the more light is able to penetrate, and thus heat is conveyed deeper in the water. Heating declines exponentially with depth in the water column, so the water will be warmest near the surface but progressively cooler as moving downwards. There are three main sections that define thermal stratification in a lake. The epilimnion is closest to the water surface and absorbs long- and shortwave radiation to warm the water surface. During cooler months, wind shear can contribute to cooling of the water surface. The thermocline is an area within the water column where water temperatures rapidly decrease. The bottom layer is the hypolimnion, which tends to have the coldest water because its depth restricts sunlight from reaching it.  In temperate lakes, fall-season cooling of surface water results in turnover of the water column, where the thermocline is disrupted, and the lake temperature profile becomes more uniform.", "situation": "Boris is deploying a camera probe in a lake to observe the different kinds of fish species that reside in each layer during the summer. In order to make sure he is at the right depth and thus in a different layer each time he makes observations, he needs to measure the water temperature. The temperature for Measurement A reads 75 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement B reads 55 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperature for Measurement C reads 40 degrees Fahrenheit. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Measurement B or Measurement C most likely the hypolimnion?", "id": "2749720534", "answers": [{"text": "Measurement C"}]}]}, {"background": "Habitat destruction has played a key role in extinctions, especially in relation to tropical forest destruction. Factors contributing to habitat loss include: overconsumption, overpopulation, land use change, deforestation, pollution (air pollution, water pollution, soil contamination) and global warming or climate change.Habitat size and numbers of species are systematically related. Physically larger species and those living at lower latitudes or in forests or oceans are more sensitive to reduction in habitat area. Conversion to \"trivial\" standardized ecosystems (e.g., monoculture following deforestation) effectively destroys habitat for the more diverse species that preceded the conversion. Even the simplest forms of agriculture affect diversity \u2013 through clearing/draining land, discouraging weeds and \"pests\", and encouraging just a limited set of domesticated plant and animal species. In some countries lack of property rights or lax law/regulatory enforcement necessarily leads to biodiversity loss (degradation costs having to be supported by the community).A 2007 study conducted by the National Science Foundation found that biodiversity and genetic diversity are codependent\u2014that diversity among species requires diversity within a species and vice versa. \"If any one type is removed from the system, the cycle can break down and the community becomes dominated by a single species.\"", "situation": "Sam is curious about the effects of human population on natural animal habitats in tropical forests. In order to study this, he has taken observations from two tropical forest regions. Tropical Forest A is a natural habitat that has been largely untouched by humans. Tropical Forest B is an area that used to be a large natural habitat but has recently been greatly reduced in size due to an increase of humans settling in and developing the area. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which tropical forest is the extinction of an animal species more likely?", "id": "4260809924", "answers": [{"text": "Tropical Forest B"}]}]}, {"background": "Habitat destruction has played a key role in extinctions, especially in relation to tropical forest destruction. Factors contributing to habitat loss include: overconsumption, overpopulation, land use change, deforestation, pollution (air pollution, water pollution, soil contamination) and global warming or climate change.Habitat size and numbers of species are systematically related. Physically larger species and those living at lower latitudes or in forests or oceans are more sensitive to reduction in habitat area. Conversion to \"trivial\" standardized ecosystems (e.g., monoculture following deforestation) effectively destroys habitat for the more diverse species that preceded the conversion. Even the simplest forms of agriculture affect diversity \u2013 through clearing/draining land, discouraging weeds and \"pests\", and encouraging just a limited set of domesticated plant and animal species. In some countries lack of property rights or lax law/regulatory enforcement necessarily leads to biodiversity loss (degradation costs having to be supported by the community).A 2007 study conducted by the National Science Foundation found that biodiversity and genetic diversity are codependent\u2014that diversity among species requires diversity within a species and vice versa. \"If any one type is removed from the system, the cycle can break down and the community becomes dominated by a single species.\"", "situation": "Sam is curious about the effects of human population on natural animal habitats in tropical forests. In order to study this, he has taken observations from two tropical forest regions. Tropical Forest A is a natural habitat that has been largely untouched by humans. Tropical Forest B is an area that used to be a large natural habitat but has recently been greatly reduced in size due to an increase of humans settling in and developing the area. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which tropical forest is the extinction of an animal species less likely?", "id": "4261727432", "answers": [{"text": "Tropical Forest A"}]}]}, {"background": "Habitat destruction has played a key role in extinctions, especially in relation to tropical forest destruction. Factors contributing to habitat loss include: overconsumption, overpopulation, land use change, deforestation, pollution (air pollution, water pollution, soil contamination) and global warming or climate change.Habitat size and numbers of species are systematically related. Physically larger species and those living at lower latitudes or in forests or oceans are more sensitive to reduction in habitat area. Conversion to \"trivial\" standardized ecosystems (e.g., monoculture following deforestation) effectively destroys habitat for the more diverse species that preceded the conversion. Even the simplest forms of agriculture affect diversity \u2013 through clearing/draining land, discouraging weeds and \"pests\", and encouraging just a limited set of domesticated plant and animal species. In some countries lack of property rights or lax law/regulatory enforcement necessarily leads to biodiversity loss (degradation costs having to be supported by the community).A 2007 study conducted by the National Science Foundation found that biodiversity and genetic diversity are codependent\u2014that diversity among species requires diversity within a species and vice versa. \"If any one type is removed from the system, the cycle can break down and the community becomes dominated by a single species.\"", "situation": "Sam is curious about the effects of human population on natural animal habitats in tropical forests. In order to study this, he has taken observations from two tropical forest regions. Tropical Forest A is a natural habitat that has been largely untouched by humans. Tropical Forest B is an area that used to be a large natural habitat but has recently been greatly reduced in size due to an increase of humans settling in and developing the area. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which tropical forest will the number of species be lower?", "id": "633915158", "answers": [{"text": "Tropical Forest B"}]}]}, {"background": "Habitat destruction has played a key role in extinctions, especially in relation to tropical forest destruction. Factors contributing to habitat loss include: overconsumption, overpopulation, land use change, deforestation, pollution (air pollution, water pollution, soil contamination) and global warming or climate change.Habitat size and numbers of species are systematically related. Physically larger species and those living at lower latitudes or in forests or oceans are more sensitive to reduction in habitat area. Conversion to \"trivial\" standardized ecosystems (e.g., monoculture following deforestation) effectively destroys habitat for the more diverse species that preceded the conversion. Even the simplest forms of agriculture affect diversity \u2013 through clearing/draining land, discouraging weeds and \"pests\", and encouraging just a limited set of domesticated plant and animal species. In some countries lack of property rights or lax law/regulatory enforcement necessarily leads to biodiversity loss (degradation costs having to be supported by the community).A 2007 study conducted by the National Science Foundation found that biodiversity and genetic diversity are codependent\u2014that diversity among species requires diversity within a species and vice versa. \"If any one type is removed from the system, the cycle can break down and the community becomes dominated by a single species.\"", "situation": "Sam is curious about the effects of human population on natural animal habitats in tropical forests. In order to study this, he has taken observations from two tropical forest regions. Tropical Forest A is a natural habitat that has been largely untouched by humans. Tropical Forest B is an area that used to be a large natural habitat but has recently been greatly reduced in size due to an increase of humans settling in and developing the area. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which tropical forest will the number of species be higher?", "id": "3973629796", "answers": [{"text": "Tropical Forest A"}]}]}, {"background": "Habitat destruction has played a key role in extinctions, especially in relation to tropical forest destruction. Factors contributing to habitat loss include: overconsumption, overpopulation, land use change, deforestation, pollution (air pollution, water pollution, soil contamination) and global warming or climate change.Habitat size and numbers of species are systematically related. Physically larger species and those living at lower latitudes or in forests or oceans are more sensitive to reduction in habitat area. Conversion to \"trivial\" standardized ecosystems (e.g., monoculture following deforestation) effectively destroys habitat for the more diverse species that preceded the conversion. Even the simplest forms of agriculture affect diversity \u2013 through clearing/draining land, discouraging weeds and \"pests\", and encouraging just a limited set of domesticated plant and animal species. In some countries lack of property rights or lax law/regulatory enforcement necessarily leads to biodiversity loss (degradation costs having to be supported by the community).A 2007 study conducted by the National Science Foundation found that biodiversity and genetic diversity are codependent\u2014that diversity among species requires diversity within a species and vice versa. \"If any one type is removed from the system, the cycle can break down and the community becomes dominated by a single species.\"", "situation": "Sam is curious about the effects of human population on natural animal habitats in tropical forests. In order to study this, he has taken observations from two tropical forest regions. Tropical Forest A is a natural habitat that has been largely untouched by humans. Tropical Forest B is an area that used to be a large natural habitat but has recently been greatly reduced in size due to an increase of humans settling in and developing the area. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the number of species in Tropical Forest A be larger or smaller than the number of species in Tropical Forest B?", "id": "3303791241", "answers": [{"text": "larger"}]}]}, {"background": "Habitat destruction has played a key role in extinctions, especially in relation to tropical forest destruction. Factors contributing to habitat loss include: overconsumption, overpopulation, land use change, deforestation, pollution (air pollution, water pollution, soil contamination) and global warming or climate change.Habitat size and numbers of species are systematically related. Physically larger species and those living at lower latitudes or in forests or oceans are more sensitive to reduction in habitat area. Conversion to \"trivial\" standardized ecosystems (e.g., monoculture following deforestation) effectively destroys habitat for the more diverse species that preceded the conversion. Even the simplest forms of agriculture affect diversity \u2013 through clearing/draining land, discouraging weeds and \"pests\", and encouraging just a limited set of domesticated plant and animal species. In some countries lack of property rights or lax law/regulatory enforcement necessarily leads to biodiversity loss (degradation costs having to be supported by the community).A 2007 study conducted by the National Science Foundation found that biodiversity and genetic diversity are codependent\u2014that diversity among species requires diversity within a species and vice versa. \"If any one type is removed from the system, the cycle can break down and the community becomes dominated by a single species.\"", "situation": "Sam is curious about the effects of human population on natural animal habitats in tropical forests. In order to study this, he has taken observations from two tropical forest regions. Tropical Forest A is a natural habitat that has been largely untouched by humans. Tropical Forest B is an area that used to be a large natural habitat but has recently been greatly reduced in size due to an increase of humans settling in and developing the area. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the number of species in Tropical Forest B be larger or smaller than the number of species in Tropical Forest A?", "id": "3308313225", "answers": [{"text": "smaller"}]}]}, {"background": "Habitat destruction has played a key role in extinctions, especially in relation to tropical forest destruction. Factors contributing to habitat loss include: overconsumption, overpopulation, land use change, deforestation, pollution (air pollution, water pollution, soil contamination) and global warming or climate change.Habitat size and numbers of species are systematically related. Physically larger species and those living at lower latitudes or in forests or oceans are more sensitive to reduction in habitat area. Conversion to \"trivial\" standardized ecosystems (e.g., monoculture following deforestation) effectively destroys habitat for the more diverse species that preceded the conversion. Even the simplest forms of agriculture affect diversity \u2013 through clearing/draining land, discouraging weeds and \"pests\", and encouraging just a limited set of domesticated plant and animal species. In some countries lack of property rights or lax law/regulatory enforcement necessarily leads to biodiversity loss (degradation costs having to be supported by the community).A 2007 study conducted by the National Science Foundation found that biodiversity and genetic diversity are codependent\u2014that diversity among species requires diversity within a species and vice versa. \"If any one type is removed from the system, the cycle can break down and the community becomes dominated by a single species.\"", "situation": "Sam is curious about the effects of human population on natural animal habitats in tropical forests. In order to study this, he has taken observations from two tropical forest regions. Tropical Forest A is a natural habitat that has been largely untouched by humans. Tropical Forest B is an area that used to be a large natural habitat but has recently been greatly reduced in size due to an increase of humans settling in and developing the area. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which tropical forest will biodiversity and genetic diversity of species be higher?", "id": "781045996", "answers": [{"text": "Tropical Forest A"}]}]}, {"background": "Habitat destruction has played a key role in extinctions, especially in relation to tropical forest destruction. Factors contributing to habitat loss include: overconsumption, overpopulation, land use change, deforestation, pollution (air pollution, water pollution, soil contamination) and global warming or climate change.Habitat size and numbers of species are systematically related. Physically larger species and those living at lower latitudes or in forests or oceans are more sensitive to reduction in habitat area. Conversion to \"trivial\" standardized ecosystems (e.g., monoculture following deforestation) effectively destroys habitat for the more diverse species that preceded the conversion. Even the simplest forms of agriculture affect diversity \u2013 through clearing/draining land, discouraging weeds and \"pests\", and encouraging just a limited set of domesticated plant and animal species. In some countries lack of property rights or lax law/regulatory enforcement necessarily leads to biodiversity loss (degradation costs having to be supported by the community).A 2007 study conducted by the National Science Foundation found that biodiversity and genetic diversity are codependent\u2014that diversity among species requires diversity within a species and vice versa. \"If any one type is removed from the system, the cycle can break down and the community becomes dominated by a single species.\"", "situation": "Sam is curious about the effects of human population on natural animal habitats in tropical forests. In order to study this, he has taken observations from two tropical forest regions. Tropical Forest A is a natural habitat that has been largely untouched by humans. Tropical Forest B is an area that used to be a large natural habitat but has recently been greatly reduced in size due to an increase of humans settling in and developing the area. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which tropical forest will biodiversity and genetic diversity of species be lower?", "id": "1575407774", "answers": [{"text": "Tropical Forest B"}]}]}, {"background": "Habitat destruction has played a key role in extinctions, especially in relation to tropical forest destruction. Factors contributing to habitat loss include: overconsumption, overpopulation, land use change, deforestation, pollution (air pollution, water pollution, soil contamination) and global warming or climate change.Habitat size and numbers of species are systematically related. Physically larger species and those living at lower latitudes or in forests or oceans are more sensitive to reduction in habitat area. Conversion to \"trivial\" standardized ecosystems (e.g., monoculture following deforestation) effectively destroys habitat for the more diverse species that preceded the conversion. Even the simplest forms of agriculture affect diversity \u2013 through clearing/draining land, discouraging weeds and \"pests\", and encouraging just a limited set of domesticated plant and animal species. In some countries lack of property rights or lax law/regulatory enforcement necessarily leads to biodiversity loss (degradation costs having to be supported by the community).A 2007 study conducted by the National Science Foundation found that biodiversity and genetic diversity are codependent\u2014that diversity among species requires diversity within a species and vice versa. \"If any one type is removed from the system, the cycle can break down and the community becomes dominated by a single species.\"", "situation": "Sam is curious about the effects of human population on natural animal habitats in tropical forests. In order to study this, he has taken observations from two tropical forest regions. Tropical Forest A is a natural habitat that has been largely untouched by humans. Tropical Forest B is an area that used to be a large natural habitat but has recently been greatly reduced in size due to an increase of humans settling in and developing the area. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the biodiversity and genetic diversity of species in Tropical Forest A be higher or lower than in Tropical Forest B?", "id": "2148981914", "answers": [{"text": "higher"}]}]}, {"background": "Habitat destruction has played a key role in extinctions, especially in relation to tropical forest destruction. Factors contributing to habitat loss include: overconsumption, overpopulation, land use change, deforestation, pollution (air pollution, water pollution, soil contamination) and global warming or climate change.Habitat size and numbers of species are systematically related. Physically larger species and those living at lower latitudes or in forests or oceans are more sensitive to reduction in habitat area. Conversion to \"trivial\" standardized ecosystems (e.g., monoculture following deforestation) effectively destroys habitat for the more diverse species that preceded the conversion. Even the simplest forms of agriculture affect diversity \u2013 through clearing/draining land, discouraging weeds and \"pests\", and encouraging just a limited set of domesticated plant and animal species. In some countries lack of property rights or lax law/regulatory enforcement necessarily leads to biodiversity loss (degradation costs having to be supported by the community).A 2007 study conducted by the National Science Foundation found that biodiversity and genetic diversity are codependent\u2014that diversity among species requires diversity within a species and vice versa. \"If any one type is removed from the system, the cycle can break down and the community becomes dominated by a single species.\"", "situation": "Sam is curious about the effects of human population on natural animal habitats in tropical forests. In order to study this, he has taken observations from two tropical forest regions. Tropical Forest A is a natural habitat that has been largely untouched by humans. Tropical Forest B is an area that used to be a large natural habitat but has recently been greatly reduced in size due to an increase of humans settling in and developing the area. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the biodiversity and genetic diversity of species in Tropical Forest B be higher or lower than in Tropical Forest A?", "id": "2151931034", "answers": [{"text": "lower"}]}]}, {"background": "Flexibility stems from phenotypic plasticity, the ability of an organism with a given genotype to change its phenotype in response to changes in its habitat, or to move to a different habitat. The degree of flexibility is inherited, and varies between individuals. A highly specialized animal or plant lives only in a well-defined habitat, eats a specific type of food, and cannot survive if its needs are not met. Many herbivores are like this; extreme examples are koalas which depend on Eucalyptus, and giant pandas which require bamboo. A generalist, on the other hand, eats a range of food, and can survive in many different conditions. Examples are humans, rats, crabs and many carnivores. The tendency to behave in a specialized or exploratory manner is inherited\u2014it is an adaptation. Rather different is developmental flexibility: \"An animal or plant is developmentally flexible if when it is raised in or transferred to new conditions, it changes in structure so that it is better fitted to survive in the new environment,\" writes evolutionary biologist John Maynard Smith.If humans move to a higher altitude, respiration and physical exertion become a problem, but after spending time in high altitude conditions they acclimatize to the reduced partial pressure of oxygen, such as by producing more red blood cells. The ability to acclimatize is an adaptation, but the acclimatization itself is not. Fecundity goes down, but deaths from some tropical diseases also go down. Over a longer period of time, some people are better able to reproduce at high altitudes than others. They contribute more heavily to later generations, and gradually by natural selection the whole population becomes adapted to the new conditions. This has demonstrably occurred, as the observed performance of long-term communities at higher altitude is significantly better than the performance of new arrivals, even when the new arrivals have had time to acclimatize.", "situation": "Aaron has discovered two new species of birds living in the Amazon rainforest, Species A and Species B. He is curious as to how flexible these animals are in regards to living in different habitats. To study this, he has tagged two birds of each of the species: For Species A he tagged the birds as A1 and A2, and for Species B he tagged the birds as B1 and B2. He left Bird A1 and Bird B1 in their natural habitat and moved Bird A2 and Bird B2 to another habitat and then observed how well each bird thrived. He learned that while Bird A2 adapted to the new environment quickly and with no decrease in function, Bird B2 was unable to find suitable food and shelter to meet its basic needs.", "qas": [{"question": "Which bird species exhibits greater flexibility, Species A or Species B?", "id": "718068006", "answers": [{"text": "Species A"}]}]}, {"background": "Flexibility stems from phenotypic plasticity, the ability of an organism with a given genotype to change its phenotype in response to changes in its habitat, or to move to a different habitat. The degree of flexibility is inherited, and varies between individuals. A highly specialized animal or plant lives only in a well-defined habitat, eats a specific type of food, and cannot survive if its needs are not met. Many herbivores are like this; extreme examples are koalas which depend on Eucalyptus, and giant pandas which require bamboo. A generalist, on the other hand, eats a range of food, and can survive in many different conditions. Examples are humans, rats, crabs and many carnivores. The tendency to behave in a specialized or exploratory manner is inherited\u2014it is an adaptation. Rather different is developmental flexibility: \"An animal or plant is developmentally flexible if when it is raised in or transferred to new conditions, it changes in structure so that it is better fitted to survive in the new environment,\" writes evolutionary biologist John Maynard Smith.If humans move to a higher altitude, respiration and physical exertion become a problem, but after spending time in high altitude conditions they acclimatize to the reduced partial pressure of oxygen, such as by producing more red blood cells. The ability to acclimatize is an adaptation, but the acclimatization itself is not. Fecundity goes down, but deaths from some tropical diseases also go down. Over a longer period of time, some people are better able to reproduce at high altitudes than others. They contribute more heavily to later generations, and gradually by natural selection the whole population becomes adapted to the new conditions. This has demonstrably occurred, as the observed performance of long-term communities at higher altitude is significantly better than the performance of new arrivals, even when the new arrivals have had time to acclimatize.", "situation": "Aaron has discovered two new species of birds living in the Amazon rainforest, Species A and Species B. He is curious as to how flexible these animals are in regards to living in different habitats. To study this, he has tagged two birds of each of the species: For Species A he tagged the birds as A1 and A2, and for Species B he tagged the birds as B1 and B2. He left Bird A1 and Bird B1 in their natural habitat and moved Bird A2 and Bird B2 to another habitat and then observed how well each bird thrived. He learned that while Bird A2 adapted to the new environment quickly and with no decrease in function, Bird B2 was unable to find suitable food and shelter to meet its basic needs.", "qas": [{"question": "Does bird Species A exhibit greater or lower flexibility than Species B?", "id": "270326055", "answers": [{"text": "greater"}]}]}, {"background": "Flexibility stems from phenotypic plasticity, the ability of an organism with a given genotype to change its phenotype in response to changes in its habitat, or to move to a different habitat. The degree of flexibility is inherited, and varies between individuals. A highly specialized animal or plant lives only in a well-defined habitat, eats a specific type of food, and cannot survive if its needs are not met. Many herbivores are like this; extreme examples are koalas which depend on Eucalyptus, and giant pandas which require bamboo. A generalist, on the other hand, eats a range of food, and can survive in many different conditions. Examples are humans, rats, crabs and many carnivores. The tendency to behave in a specialized or exploratory manner is inherited\u2014it is an adaptation. Rather different is developmental flexibility: \"An animal or plant is developmentally flexible if when it is raised in or transferred to new conditions, it changes in structure so that it is better fitted to survive in the new environment,\" writes evolutionary biologist John Maynard Smith.If humans move to a higher altitude, respiration and physical exertion become a problem, but after spending time in high altitude conditions they acclimatize to the reduced partial pressure of oxygen, such as by producing more red blood cells. The ability to acclimatize is an adaptation, but the acclimatization itself is not. Fecundity goes down, but deaths from some tropical diseases also go down. Over a longer period of time, some people are better able to reproduce at high altitudes than others. They contribute more heavily to later generations, and gradually by natural selection the whole population becomes adapted to the new conditions. This has demonstrably occurred, as the observed performance of long-term communities at higher altitude is significantly better than the performance of new arrivals, even when the new arrivals have had time to acclimatize.", "situation": "Aaron has discovered two new species of birds living in the Amazon rainforest, Species A and Species B. He is curious as to how flexible these animals are in regards to living in different habitats. To study this, he has tagged two birds of each of the species: For Species A he tagged the birds as A1 and A2, and for Species B he tagged the birds as B1 and B2. He left Bird A1 and Bird B1 in their natural habitat and moved Bird A2 and Bird B2 to another habitat and then observed how well each bird thrived. He learned that while Bird A2 adapted to the new environment quickly and with no decrease in function, Bird B2 was unable to find suitable food and shelter to meet its basic needs.", "qas": [{"question": "Does bird Species B exhibit greater or lower flexibility than Species A?", "id": "273733927", "answers": [{"text": "lower"}]}]}, {"background": "Flexibility stems from phenotypic plasticity, the ability of an organism with a given genotype to change its phenotype in response to changes in its habitat, or to move to a different habitat. The degree of flexibility is inherited, and varies between individuals. A highly specialized animal or plant lives only in a well-defined habitat, eats a specific type of food, and cannot survive if its needs are not met. Many herbivores are like this; extreme examples are koalas which depend on Eucalyptus, and giant pandas which require bamboo. A generalist, on the other hand, eats a range of food, and can survive in many different conditions. Examples are humans, rats, crabs and many carnivores. The tendency to behave in a specialized or exploratory manner is inherited\u2014it is an adaptation. Rather different is developmental flexibility: \"An animal or plant is developmentally flexible if when it is raised in or transferred to new conditions, it changes in structure so that it is better fitted to survive in the new environment,\" writes evolutionary biologist John Maynard Smith.If humans move to a higher altitude, respiration and physical exertion become a problem, but after spending time in high altitude conditions they acclimatize to the reduced partial pressure of oxygen, such as by producing more red blood cells. The ability to acclimatize is an adaptation, but the acclimatization itself is not. Fecundity goes down, but deaths from some tropical diseases also go down. Over a longer period of time, some people are better able to reproduce at high altitudes than others. They contribute more heavily to later generations, and gradually by natural selection the whole population becomes adapted to the new conditions. This has demonstrably occurred, as the observed performance of long-term communities at higher altitude is significantly better than the performance of new arrivals, even when the new arrivals have had time to acclimatize.", "situation": "Aaron has discovered two new species of birds living in the Amazon rainforest, Species A and Species B. He is curious as to how flexible these animals are in regards to living in different habitats. To study this, he has tagged two birds of each of the species: For Species A he tagged the birds as A1 and A2, and for Species B he tagged the birds as B1 and B2. He left Bird A1 and Bird B1 in their natural habitat and moved Bird A2 and Bird B2 to another habitat and then observed how well each bird thrived. He learned that while Bird A2 adapted to the new environment quickly and with no decrease in function, Bird B2 was unable to find suitable food and shelter to meet its basic needs.", "qas": [{"question": "Which bird species is more specialized, Species A or Species B?", "id": "2087703891", "answers": [{"text": "Species B"}]}]}, {"background": "Flexibility stems from phenotypic plasticity, the ability of an organism with a given genotype to change its phenotype in response to changes in its habitat, or to move to a different habitat. The degree of flexibility is inherited, and varies between individuals. A highly specialized animal or plant lives only in a well-defined habitat, eats a specific type of food, and cannot survive if its needs are not met. Many herbivores are like this; extreme examples are koalas which depend on Eucalyptus, and giant pandas which require bamboo. A generalist, on the other hand, eats a range of food, and can survive in many different conditions. Examples are humans, rats, crabs and many carnivores. The tendency to behave in a specialized or exploratory manner is inherited\u2014it is an adaptation. Rather different is developmental flexibility: \"An animal or plant is developmentally flexible if when it is raised in or transferred to new conditions, it changes in structure so that it is better fitted to survive in the new environment,\" writes evolutionary biologist John Maynard Smith.If humans move to a higher altitude, respiration and physical exertion become a problem, but after spending time in high altitude conditions they acclimatize to the reduced partial pressure of oxygen, such as by producing more red blood cells. The ability to acclimatize is an adaptation, but the acclimatization itself is not. Fecundity goes down, but deaths from some tropical diseases also go down. Over a longer period of time, some people are better able to reproduce at high altitudes than others. They contribute more heavily to later generations, and gradually by natural selection the whole population becomes adapted to the new conditions. This has demonstrably occurred, as the observed performance of long-term communities at higher altitude is significantly better than the performance of new arrivals, even when the new arrivals have had time to acclimatize.", "situation": "Aaron has discovered two new species of birds living in the Amazon rainforest, Species A and Species B. He is curious as to how flexible these animals are in regards to living in different habitats. To study this, he has tagged two birds of each of the species: For Species A he tagged the birds as A1 and A2, and for Species B he tagged the birds as B1 and B2. He left Bird A1 and Bird B1 in their natural habitat and moved Bird A2 and Bird B2 to another habitat and then observed how well each bird thrived. He learned that while Bird A2 adapted to the new environment quickly and with no decrease in function, Bird B2 was unable to find suitable food and shelter to meet its basic needs.", "qas": [{"question": "Which bird species is more generalist, Species A or Species B?", "id": "2776618228", "answers": [{"text": "Species A"}]}]}, {"background": "Flexibility stems from phenotypic plasticity, the ability of an organism with a given genotype to change its phenotype in response to changes in its habitat, or to move to a different habitat. The degree of flexibility is inherited, and varies between individuals. A highly specialized animal or plant lives only in a well-defined habitat, eats a specific type of food, and cannot survive if its needs are not met. Many herbivores are like this; extreme examples are koalas which depend on Eucalyptus, and giant pandas which require bamboo. A generalist, on the other hand, eats a range of food, and can survive in many different conditions. Examples are humans, rats, crabs and many carnivores. The tendency to behave in a specialized or exploratory manner is inherited\u2014it is an adaptation. Rather different is developmental flexibility: \"An animal or plant is developmentally flexible if when it is raised in or transferred to new conditions, it changes in structure so that it is better fitted to survive in the new environment,\" writes evolutionary biologist John Maynard Smith.If humans move to a higher altitude, respiration and physical exertion become a problem, but after spending time in high altitude conditions they acclimatize to the reduced partial pressure of oxygen, such as by producing more red blood cells. The ability to acclimatize is an adaptation, but the acclimatization itself is not. Fecundity goes down, but deaths from some tropical diseases also go down. Over a longer period of time, some people are better able to reproduce at high altitudes than others. They contribute more heavily to later generations, and gradually by natural selection the whole population becomes adapted to the new conditions. This has demonstrably occurred, as the observed performance of long-term communities at higher altitude is significantly better than the performance of new arrivals, even when the new arrivals have had time to acclimatize.", "situation": "Aaron has discovered two new species of birds living in the Amazon rainforest, Species A and Species B. He is curious as to how flexible these animals are in regards to living in different habitats. To study this, he has tagged two birds of each of the species: For Species A he tagged the birds as A1 and A2, and for Species B he tagged the birds as B1 and B2. He left Bird A1 and Bird B1 in their natural habitat and moved Bird A2 and Bird B2 to another habitat and then observed how well each bird thrived. He learned that while Bird A2 adapted to the new environment quickly and with no decrease in function, Bird B2 was unable to find suitable food and shelter to meet its basic needs.", "qas": [{"question": "Which bird species exhibits lower flexibility, Species A or Species B?", "id": "1993398373", "answers": [{"text": "Species B"}]}]}, {"background": "Flexibility stems from phenotypic plasticity, the ability of an organism with a given genotype to change its phenotype in response to changes in its habitat, or to move to a different habitat. The degree of flexibility is inherited, and varies between individuals. A highly specialized animal or plant lives only in a well-defined habitat, eats a specific type of food, and cannot survive if its needs are not met. Many herbivores are like this; extreme examples are koalas which depend on Eucalyptus, and giant pandas which require bamboo. A generalist, on the other hand, eats a range of food, and can survive in many different conditions. Examples are humans, rats, crabs and many carnivores. The tendency to behave in a specialized or exploratory manner is inherited\u2014it is an adaptation. Rather different is developmental flexibility: \"An animal or plant is developmentally flexible if when it is raised in or transferred to new conditions, it changes in structure so that it is better fitted to survive in the new environment,\" writes evolutionary biologist John Maynard Smith.If humans move to a higher altitude, respiration and physical exertion become a problem, but after spending time in high altitude conditions they acclimatize to the reduced partial pressure of oxygen, such as by producing more red blood cells. The ability to acclimatize is an adaptation, but the acclimatization itself is not. Fecundity goes down, but deaths from some tropical diseases also go down. Over a longer period of time, some people are better able to reproduce at high altitudes than others. They contribute more heavily to later generations, and gradually by natural selection the whole population becomes adapted to the new conditions. This has demonstrably occurred, as the observed performance of long-term communities at higher altitude is significantly better than the performance of new arrivals, even when the new arrivals have had time to acclimatize.", "situation": "Aaron has discovered two new species of birds living in the Amazon rainforest, Species A and Species B. He is curious as to how flexible these animals are in regards to living in different habitats. To study this, he has tagged two birds of each of the species: For Species A he tagged the birds as A1 and A2, and for Species B he tagged the birds as B1 and B2. He left Bird A1 and Bird B1 in their natural habitat and moved Bird A2 and Bird B2 to another habitat and then observed how well each bird thrived. He learned that while Bird A2 adapted to the new environment quickly and with no decrease in function, Bird B2 was unable to find suitable food and shelter to meet its basic needs.", "qas": [{"question": "Which bird species is less specialized, Species A or Species B?", "id": "2096223575", "answers": [{"text": "Species A"}]}]}, {"background": "Flexibility stems from phenotypic plasticity, the ability of an organism with a given genotype to change its phenotype in response to changes in its habitat, or to move to a different habitat. The degree of flexibility is inherited, and varies between individuals. A highly specialized animal or plant lives only in a well-defined habitat, eats a specific type of food, and cannot survive if its needs are not met. Many herbivores are like this; extreme examples are koalas which depend on Eucalyptus, and giant pandas which require bamboo. A generalist, on the other hand, eats a range of food, and can survive in many different conditions. Examples are humans, rats, crabs and many carnivores. The tendency to behave in a specialized or exploratory manner is inherited\u2014it is an adaptation. Rather different is developmental flexibility: \"An animal or plant is developmentally flexible if when it is raised in or transferred to new conditions, it changes in structure so that it is better fitted to survive in the new environment,\" writes evolutionary biologist John Maynard Smith.If humans move to a higher altitude, respiration and physical exertion become a problem, but after spending time in high altitude conditions they acclimatize to the reduced partial pressure of oxygen, such as by producing more red blood cells. The ability to acclimatize is an adaptation, but the acclimatization itself is not. Fecundity goes down, but deaths from some tropical diseases also go down. Over a longer period of time, some people are better able to reproduce at high altitudes than others. They contribute more heavily to later generations, and gradually by natural selection the whole population becomes adapted to the new conditions. This has demonstrably occurred, as the observed performance of long-term communities at higher altitude is significantly better than the performance of new arrivals, even when the new arrivals have had time to acclimatize.", "situation": "Aaron has discovered two new species of birds living in the Amazon rainforest, Species A and Species B. He is curious as to how flexible these animals are in regards to living in different habitats. To study this, he has tagged two birds of each of the species: For Species A he tagged the birds as A1 and A2, and for Species B he tagged the birds as B1 and B2. He left Bird A1 and Bird B1 in their natural habitat and moved Bird A2 and Bird B2 to another habitat and then observed how well each bird thrived. He learned that while Bird A2 adapted to the new environment quickly and with no decrease in function, Bird B2 was unable to find suitable food and shelter to meet its basic needs.", "qas": [{"question": "Which bird species is not a generalist species, Species A or Species B?", "id": "874698783", "answers": [{"text": "Species B"}]}]}, {"background": "Flexibility stems from phenotypic plasticity, the ability of an organism with a given genotype to change its phenotype in response to changes in its habitat, or to move to a different habitat. The degree of flexibility is inherited, and varies between individuals. A highly specialized animal or plant lives only in a well-defined habitat, eats a specific type of food, and cannot survive if its needs are not met. Many herbivores are like this; extreme examples are koalas which depend on Eucalyptus, and giant pandas which require bamboo. A generalist, on the other hand, eats a range of food, and can survive in many different conditions. Examples are humans, rats, crabs and many carnivores. The tendency to behave in a specialized or exploratory manner is inherited\u2014it is an adaptation. Rather different is developmental flexibility: \"An animal or plant is developmentally flexible if when it is raised in or transferred to new conditions, it changes in structure so that it is better fitted to survive in the new environment,\" writes evolutionary biologist John Maynard Smith.If humans move to a higher altitude, respiration and physical exertion become a problem, but after spending time in high altitude conditions they acclimatize to the reduced partial pressure of oxygen, such as by producing more red blood cells. The ability to acclimatize is an adaptation, but the acclimatization itself is not. Fecundity goes down, but deaths from some tropical diseases also go down. Over a longer period of time, some people are better able to reproduce at high altitudes than others. They contribute more heavily to later generations, and gradually by natural selection the whole population becomes adapted to the new conditions. This has demonstrably occurred, as the observed performance of long-term communities at higher altitude is significantly better than the performance of new arrivals, even when the new arrivals have had time to acclimatize.", "situation": "Aaron has discovered two new species of birds living in the Amazon rainforest, Species A and Species B. He is curious as to how flexible these animals are in regards to living in different habitats. To study this, he has tagged two birds of each of the species: For Species A he tagged the birds as A1 and A2, and for Species B he tagged the birds as B1 and B2. He left Bird A1 and Bird B1 in their natural habitat and moved Bird A2 and Bird B2 to another habitat and then observed how well each bird thrived. He learned that while Bird A2 adapted to the new environment quickly and with no decrease in function, Bird B2 was unable to find suitable food and shelter to meet its basic needs.", "qas": [{"question": "Which bird species is not a specialized species, Species A or Species B?", "id": "237623422", "answers": [{"text": "Species A"}]}]}, {"background": "Flexibility stems from phenotypic plasticity, the ability of an organism with a given genotype to change its phenotype in response to changes in its habitat, or to move to a different habitat. The degree of flexibility is inherited, and varies between individuals. A highly specialized animal or plant lives only in a well-defined habitat, eats a specific type of food, and cannot survive if its needs are not met. Many herbivores are like this; extreme examples are koalas which depend on Eucalyptus, and giant pandas which require bamboo. A generalist, on the other hand, eats a range of food, and can survive in many different conditions. Examples are humans, rats, crabs and many carnivores. The tendency to behave in a specialized or exploratory manner is inherited\u2014it is an adaptation. Rather different is developmental flexibility: \"An animal or plant is developmentally flexible if when it is raised in or transferred to new conditions, it changes in structure so that it is better fitted to survive in the new environment,\" writes evolutionary biologist John Maynard Smith.If humans move to a higher altitude, respiration and physical exertion become a problem, but after spending time in high altitude conditions they acclimatize to the reduced partial pressure of oxygen, such as by producing more red blood cells. The ability to acclimatize is an adaptation, but the acclimatization itself is not. Fecundity goes down, but deaths from some tropical diseases also go down. Over a longer period of time, some people are better able to reproduce at high altitudes than others. They contribute more heavily to later generations, and gradually by natural selection the whole population becomes adapted to the new conditions. This has demonstrably occurred, as the observed performance of long-term communities at higher altitude is significantly better than the performance of new arrivals, even when the new arrivals have had time to acclimatize.", "situation": "Aaron has discovered two new species of birds living in the Amazon rainforest, Species A and Species B. He is curious as to how flexible these animals are in regards to living in different habitats. To study this, he has tagged two birds of each of the species: For Species A he tagged the birds as A1 and A2, and for Species B he tagged the birds as B1 and B2. He left Bird A1 and Bird B1 in their natural habitat and moved Bird A2 and Bird B2 to another habitat and then observed how well each bird thrived. He learned that while Bird A2 adapted to the new environment quickly and with no decrease in function, Bird B2 was unable to find suitable food and shelter to meet its basic needs.", "qas": [{"question": "Does bird Species A exhibit more or less specialization than Species B?", "id": "863426744", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Taking a moment to consider the validity of this equation can help to clarify what it means. Imagine a yo-yo. Instead of using it normally, let it fall to the end of the string, and then spin it around above your head. If we were to increase the speed at which we rotate our hand, we increase the velocity of the yo-yo - it is spinning faster. As it spins faster, it also changes direction faster. The acceleration increases. Now let's think about the bottom of the equation: the radius. If we halve the length of the yo-yo string (bring the yo-yo closer to us), we make the yo-yo's velocity greater. Again, it moves faster, which increases the acceleration. If we make the string longer again, this decreases the acceleration. We now understand why the relationship between the radius and the acceleration is an inverse relationship - as we decrease the radius, the acceleration increases, and visa versa.", "situation": "Hazel is at the circus with her children and they are watching the performers ride motorcycles in a circular cage. They notice that the motorcycles are going different speeds and are curious as to why. They observe that Cage A is larger than Cage B and has a larger radius while Cage B is smaller than Cage A and has a smaller radius. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which cage will the motorcycle be accelerating faster?", "id": "4090286353", "answers": [{"text": "Cage B"}]}]}, {"background": "Taking a moment to consider the validity of this equation can help to clarify what it means. Imagine a yo-yo. Instead of using it normally, let it fall to the end of the string, and then spin it around above your head. If we were to increase the speed at which we rotate our hand, we increase the velocity of the yo-yo - it is spinning faster. As it spins faster, it also changes direction faster. The acceleration increases. Now let's think about the bottom of the equation: the radius. If we halve the length of the yo-yo string (bring the yo-yo closer to us), we make the yo-yo's velocity greater. Again, it moves faster, which increases the acceleration. If we make the string longer again, this decreases the acceleration. We now understand why the relationship between the radius and the acceleration is an inverse relationship - as we decrease the radius, the acceleration increases, and visa versa.", "situation": "Hazel is at the circus with her children and they are watching the performers ride motorcycles in a circular cage. They notice that the motorcycles are going different speeds and are curious as to why. They observe that Cage A is larger than Cage B and has a larger radius while Cage B is smaller than Cage A and has a smaller radius. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which cage will the motorcycle be accelerating slower?", "id": "4100051240", "answers": [{"text": "Cage A"}]}]}, {"background": "Taking a moment to consider the validity of this equation can help to clarify what it means. Imagine a yo-yo. Instead of using it normally, let it fall to the end of the string, and then spin it around above your head. If we were to increase the speed at which we rotate our hand, we increase the velocity of the yo-yo - it is spinning faster. As it spins faster, it also changes direction faster. The acceleration increases. Now let's think about the bottom of the equation: the radius. If we halve the length of the yo-yo string (bring the yo-yo closer to us), we make the yo-yo's velocity greater. Again, it moves faster, which increases the acceleration. If we make the string longer again, this decreases the acceleration. We now understand why the relationship between the radius and the acceleration is an inverse relationship - as we decrease the radius, the acceleration increases, and visa versa.", "situation": "Hazel is at the circus with her children and they are watching the performers ride motorcycles in a circular cage. They notice that the motorcycles are going different speeds and are curious as to why. They observe that Cage A is larger than Cage B and has a larger radius while Cage B is smaller than Cage A and has a smaller radius. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the motorcycle in Cage A be accelerating faster or slower than the motorcycle in Cage B?", "id": "981851474", "answers": [{"text": "slower"}]}]}, {"background": "Taking a moment to consider the validity of this equation can help to clarify what it means. Imagine a yo-yo. Instead of using it normally, let it fall to the end of the string, and then spin it around above your head. If we were to increase the speed at which we rotate our hand, we increase the velocity of the yo-yo - it is spinning faster. As it spins faster, it also changes direction faster. The acceleration increases. Now let's think about the bottom of the equation: the radius. If we halve the length of the yo-yo string (bring the yo-yo closer to us), we make the yo-yo's velocity greater. Again, it moves faster, which increases the acceleration. If we make the string longer again, this decreases the acceleration. We now understand why the relationship between the radius and the acceleration is an inverse relationship - as we decrease the radius, the acceleration increases, and visa versa.", "situation": "Hazel is at the circus with her children and they are watching the performers ride motorcycles in a circular cage. They notice that the motorcycles are going different speeds and are curious as to why. They observe that Cage A is larger than Cage B and has a larger radius while Cage B is smaller than Cage A and has a smaller radius. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the motorcycle in Cage B be accelerating faster or slower than the motorcycle in Cage B?", "id": "986111315", "answers": [{"text": "faster"}]}]}, {"background": "Taking a moment to consider the validity of this equation can help to clarify what it means. Imagine a yo-yo. Instead of using it normally, let it fall to the end of the string, and then spin it around above your head. If we were to increase the speed at which we rotate our hand, we increase the velocity of the yo-yo - it is spinning faster. As it spins faster, it also changes direction faster. The acceleration increases. Now let's think about the bottom of the equation: the radius. If we halve the length of the yo-yo string (bring the yo-yo closer to us), we make the yo-yo's velocity greater. Again, it moves faster, which increases the acceleration. If we make the string longer again, this decreases the acceleration. We now understand why the relationship between the radius and the acceleration is an inverse relationship - as we decrease the radius, the acceleration increases, and visa versa.", "situation": "Hazel is at the circus with her children and they are watching the performers ride motorcycles in a circular cage. They notice that the motorcycles are going different speeds and are curious as to why. They observe that Cage A is larger than Cage B and has a larger radius while Cage B is smaller than Cage A and has a smaller radius. ", "qas": [{"question": "If the radius of Cage A is decreased, will the motorcycle accelerate faster or slower?", "id": "113367802", "answers": [{"text": "faster"}]}]}, {"background": "Taking a moment to consider the validity of this equation can help to clarify what it means. Imagine a yo-yo. Instead of using it normally, let it fall to the end of the string, and then spin it around above your head. If we were to increase the speed at which we rotate our hand, we increase the velocity of the yo-yo - it is spinning faster. As it spins faster, it also changes direction faster. The acceleration increases. Now let's think about the bottom of the equation: the radius. If we halve the length of the yo-yo string (bring the yo-yo closer to us), we make the yo-yo's velocity greater. Again, it moves faster, which increases the acceleration. If we make the string longer again, this decreases the acceleration. We now understand why the relationship between the radius and the acceleration is an inverse relationship - as we decrease the radius, the acceleration increases, and visa versa.", "situation": "Hazel is at the circus with her children and they are watching the performers ride motorcycles in a circular cage. They notice that the motorcycles are going different speeds and are curious as to why. They observe that Cage A is larger than Cage B and has a larger radius while Cage B is smaller than Cage A and has a smaller radius. ", "qas": [{"question": "If the radius of Cage B is increased, will the motorcycle accelerate faster or slower?", "id": "171105033", "answers": [{"text": "slower"}]}]}, {"background": "When you add sugar to a cold drink, you may stir it to help the sugar dissolve. If you don\u2019t stir, the sugar may eventually dissolve, but it will take much longer. Stirring is one of several factors that affect how fast a solute dissolves in a solvent. Temperature is another factor. A solid solute dissolves faster at a higher temperature. For example, sugar dissolves faster in hot tea than in ice tea. A third factor that affects the rate of dissolving is the surface area of the solute. For example, if you put granulated sugar in a glass of ice tea, it will dissolve more quickly than the same amount of sugar in a cube. That\u2019s because granulated sugar has much more surface area than a cube of sugar. You can see videos of all three factors at these URLs", "situation": "To demonstrate solubility to her class, Professor Johnson shows her students several examples of salt dissolving in water. In one experiment, she is showing her students how salt dissolves differently when added to water of differing temperatures. Glass A is filled with ice water and Glass B is filled with hot water. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which glass will the salt dissolve faster?", "id": "3632634533", "answers": [{"text": "Glass B"}]}]}, {"background": "When you add sugar to a cold drink, you may stir it to help the sugar dissolve. If you don\u2019t stir, the sugar may eventually dissolve, but it will take much longer. Stirring is one of several factors that affect how fast a solute dissolves in a solvent. Temperature is another factor. A solid solute dissolves faster at a higher temperature. For example, sugar dissolves faster in hot tea than in ice tea. A third factor that affects the rate of dissolving is the surface area of the solute. For example, if you put granulated sugar in a glass of ice tea, it will dissolve more quickly than the same amount of sugar in a cube. That\u2019s because granulated sugar has much more surface area than a cube of sugar. You can see videos of all three factors at these URLs", "situation": "To demonstrate solubility to her class, Professor Johnson shows her students several examples of salt dissolving in water. In one experiment, she is showing her students how salt dissolves differently when added to water of differing temperatures. Glass A is filled with ice water and Glass B is filled with hot water. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which glass will the salt dissolve slower?", "id": "3642399420", "answers": [{"text": "Glass A"}]}]}, {"background": "When you add sugar to a cold drink, you may stir it to help the sugar dissolve. If you don\u2019t stir, the sugar may eventually dissolve, but it will take much longer. Stirring is one of several factors that affect how fast a solute dissolves in a solvent. Temperature is another factor. A solid solute dissolves faster at a higher temperature. For example, sugar dissolves faster in hot tea than in ice tea. A third factor that affects the rate of dissolving is the surface area of the solute. For example, if you put granulated sugar in a glass of ice tea, it will dissolve more quickly than the same amount of sugar in a cube. That\u2019s because granulated sugar has much more surface area than a cube of sugar. You can see videos of all three factors at these URLs", "situation": "To demonstrate solubility to her class, Professor Johnson shows her students several examples of salt dissolving in water. In one experiment, she is showing her students how salt dissolves differently when added to water of differing temperatures. Glass A is filled with ice water and Glass B is filled with hot water. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the salt in Glass A dissolve faster or slower than the salt in Glass B?", "id": "754033891", "answers": [{"text": "slower"}]}]}, {"background": "When you add sugar to a cold drink, you may stir it to help the sugar dissolve. If you don\u2019t stir, the sugar may eventually dissolve, but it will take much longer. Stirring is one of several factors that affect how fast a solute dissolves in a solvent. Temperature is another factor. A solid solute dissolves faster at a higher temperature. For example, sugar dissolves faster in hot tea than in ice tea. A third factor that affects the rate of dissolving is the surface area of the solute. For example, if you put granulated sugar in a glass of ice tea, it will dissolve more quickly than the same amount of sugar in a cube. That\u2019s because granulated sugar has much more surface area than a cube of sugar. You can see videos of all three factors at these URLs", "situation": "To demonstrate solubility to her class, Professor Johnson shows her students several examples of salt dissolving in water. In one experiment, she is showing her students how salt dissolves differently when added to water of differing temperatures. Glass A is filled with ice water and Glass B is filled with hot water. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the salt in Glass B dissolve faster or slower than the salt in Glass A?", "id": "757376227", "answers": [{"text": "faster"}]}]}, {"background": "In the U.S., the majority of electricity is produced by burning coal or other fossil fuels. This causes air pollution that harms the health of living things. The air pollution also causes acid rain and contributes to global warming. In addition, fossil fuels are nonrenewable resources, so if we keep using them, they will eventually run out. The main advantage of nuclear energy is that it doesn\u2019t release air pollution or cause the other environmental problems associated with the burning of fossil fuels. On the other other hand, radioactive elements are nonrenewable like fossil fuels and could eventually be used up.", "situation": "Valley City and Mountain City recently voted on whether to continue to use coal and fossil fuels for electricity or to change to nuclear energy. Valley City decided to continue using coal and fossil fuels to produce electricity. Mountain City decided to switch to nuclear energy to produce electricity.  ", "qas": [{"question": "After the change in power source, which city is more likely to experience a decrease in air pollution?", "id": "494697069", "answers": [{"text": "Mountain City"}]}]}, {"background": "In the U.S., the majority of electricity is produced by burning coal or other fossil fuels. This causes air pollution that harms the health of living things. The air pollution also causes acid rain and contributes to global warming. In addition, fossil fuels are nonrenewable resources, so if we keep using them, they will eventually run out. The main advantage of nuclear energy is that it doesn\u2019t release air pollution or cause the other environmental problems associated with the burning of fossil fuels. On the other other hand, radioactive elements are nonrenewable like fossil fuels and could eventually be used up.", "situation": "Valley City and Mountain City recently voted on whether to continue to use coal and fossil fuels for electricity or to change to nuclear energy. Valley City decided to continue using coal and fossil fuels to produce electricity. Mountain City decided to switch to nuclear energy to produce electricity.  ", "qas": [{"question": "After the change in power source, which city is more likely to experience an increase in air pollution?", "id": "2606791401", "answers": [{"text": "Valley City"}]}]}, {"background": "In the U.S., the majority of electricity is produced by burning coal or other fossil fuels. This causes air pollution that harms the health of living things. The air pollution also causes acid rain and contributes to global warming. In addition, fossil fuels are nonrenewable resources, so if we keep using them, they will eventually run out. The main advantage of nuclear energy is that it doesn\u2019t release air pollution or cause the other environmental problems associated with the burning of fossil fuels. On the other other hand, radioactive elements are nonrenewable like fossil fuels and could eventually be used up.", "situation": "Valley City and Mountain City recently voted on whether to continue to use coal and fossil fuels for electricity or to change to nuclear energy. Valley City decided to continue using coal and fossil fuels to produce electricity. Mountain City decided to switch to nuclear energy to produce electricity.  ", "qas": [{"question": "After the change in power source, will Valley City likely have more or less acid rain than Mountain City?", "id": "2206104328", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "In the U.S., the majority of electricity is produced by burning coal or other fossil fuels. This causes air pollution that harms the health of living things. The air pollution also causes acid rain and contributes to global warming. In addition, fossil fuels are nonrenewable resources, so if we keep using them, they will eventually run out. The main advantage of nuclear energy is that it doesn\u2019t release air pollution or cause the other environmental problems associated with the burning of fossil fuels. On the other other hand, radioactive elements are nonrenewable like fossil fuels and could eventually be used up.", "situation": "Valley City and Mountain City recently voted on whether to continue to use coal and fossil fuels for electricity or to change to nuclear energy. Valley City decided to continue using coal and fossil fuels to produce electricity. Mountain City decided to switch to nuclear energy to produce electricity.  ", "qas": [{"question": "After the change in power source, will Mountain City likely have more or less acid rain than Valley City?", "id": "2337045256", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "In the U.S., the majority of electricity is produced by burning coal or other fossil fuels. This causes air pollution that harms the health of living things. The air pollution also causes acid rain and contributes to global warming. In addition, fossil fuels are nonrenewable resources, so if we keep using them, they will eventually run out. The main advantage of nuclear energy is that it doesn\u2019t release air pollution or cause the other environmental problems associated with the burning of fossil fuels. On the other other hand, radioactive elements are nonrenewable like fossil fuels and could eventually be used up.", "situation": "Valley City and Mountain City recently voted on whether to continue to use coal and fossil fuels for electricity or to change to nuclear energy. Valley City decided to continue using coal and fossil fuels to produce electricity. Mountain City decided to switch to nuclear energy to produce electricity.  ", "qas": [{"question": "After the change in power source, which city is more likely to experience a decrease in environmental problems?", "id": "2197782065", "answers": [{"text": "Mountain City"}]}]}, {"background": "Saturated hydrocarbons are given the general name of alkanes . The name of specific alkanes always ends in \u2013 ane . The first part of the name indicates how many carbon atoms each molecule of the alkane has. The smallest alkane is methane. It has just one carbon atom. The next largest is ethane with two carbon atoms. The chemical formulas and properties of methane, ethane, and other small alkanes are listed in the Table below . The boiling and melting points of alkanes are determined mainly by the number of carbon atoms they have. Alkanes with more carbon atoms generally boil and melt at higher temperatures.", "situation": "Joy is learning about alkanes in her chemistry class. She is testing the boiling and melting points of different alkanes to determine their size and order them appropriately. From her experiments, Joy learned that: Alkane A has a boiling point of -162 Celsius and a melting point of -183 Celsius; Alkane B has a boiling point of -89 Celsius and a melting point of -172 Celsius; and Alkane C has a boiling point of -42 Celsius and a melting point of -188 Celsius. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Alkane A smaller or larger than Alkane B?", "id": "1649643259", "answers": [{"text": "smaller"}]}]}, {"background": "Saturated hydrocarbons are given the general name of alkanes . The name of specific alkanes always ends in \u2013 ane . The first part of the name indicates how many carbon atoms each molecule of the alkane has. The smallest alkane is methane. It has just one carbon atom. The next largest is ethane with two carbon atoms. The chemical formulas and properties of methane, ethane, and other small alkanes are listed in the Table below . The boiling and melting points of alkanes are determined mainly by the number of carbon atoms they have. Alkanes with more carbon atoms generally boil and melt at higher temperatures.", "situation": "Joy is learning about alkanes in her chemistry class. She is testing the boiling and melting points of different alkanes to determine their size and order them appropriately. From her experiments, Joy learned that: Alkane A has a boiling point of -162 Celsius and a melting point of -183 Celsius; Alkane B has a boiling point of -89 Celsius and a melting point of -172 Celsius; and Alkane C has a boiling point of -42 Celsius and a melting point of -188 Celsius. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Alkane B smaller or larger than Alkane C?", "id": "1652002557", "answers": [{"text": "smaller"}]}]}, {"background": "Saturated hydrocarbons are given the general name of alkanes . The name of specific alkanes always ends in \u2013 ane . The first part of the name indicates how many carbon atoms each molecule of the alkane has. The smallest alkane is methane. It has just one carbon atom. The next largest is ethane with two carbon atoms. The chemical formulas and properties of methane, ethane, and other small alkanes are listed in the Table below . The boiling and melting points of alkanes are determined mainly by the number of carbon atoms they have. Alkanes with more carbon atoms generally boil and melt at higher temperatures.", "situation": "Joy is learning about alkanes in her chemistry class. She is testing the boiling and melting points of different alkanes to determine their size and order them appropriately. From her experiments, Joy learned that: Alkane A has a boiling point of -162 Celsius and a melting point of -183 Celsius; Alkane B has a boiling point of -89 Celsius and a melting point of -172 Celsius; and Alkane C has a boiling point of -42 Celsius and a melting point of -188 Celsius. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Alkane B smaller or larger than Alkane A?", "id": "1651740411", "answers": [{"text": "larger"}]}]}, {"background": "Saturated hydrocarbons are given the general name of alkanes . The name of specific alkanes always ends in \u2013 ane . The first part of the name indicates how many carbon atoms each molecule of the alkane has. The smallest alkane is methane. It has just one carbon atom. The next largest is ethane with two carbon atoms. The chemical formulas and properties of methane, ethane, and other small alkanes are listed in the Table below . The boiling and melting points of alkanes are determined mainly by the number of carbon atoms they have. Alkanes with more carbon atoms generally boil and melt at higher temperatures.", "situation": "Joy is learning about alkanes in her chemistry class. She is testing the boiling and melting points of different alkanes to determine their size and order them appropriately. From her experiments, Joy learned that: Alkane A has a boiling point of -162 Celsius and a melting point of -183 Celsius; Alkane B has a boiling point of -89 Celsius and a melting point of -172 Celsius; and Alkane C has a boiling point of -42 Celsius and a melting point of -188 Celsius. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Alkane C smaller or larger than Alkane A?", "id": "1653968636", "answers": [{"text": "larger"}]}]}, {"background": "Saturated hydrocarbons are given the general name of alkanes . The name of specific alkanes always ends in \u2013 ane . The first part of the name indicates how many carbon atoms each molecule of the alkane has. The smallest alkane is methane. It has just one carbon atom. The next largest is ethane with two carbon atoms. The chemical formulas and properties of methane, ethane, and other small alkanes are listed in the Table below . The boiling and melting points of alkanes are determined mainly by the number of carbon atoms they have. Alkanes with more carbon atoms generally boil and melt at higher temperatures.", "situation": "Joy is learning about alkanes in her chemistry class. She is testing the boiling and melting points of different alkanes to determine their size and order them appropriately. From her experiments, Joy learned that: Alkane A has a boiling point of -162 Celsius and a melting point of -183 Celsius; Alkane B has a boiling point of -89 Celsius and a melting point of -172 Celsius; and Alkane C has a boiling point of -42 Celsius and a melting point of -188 Celsius. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Alkane A smaller or larger than Alkane C?", "id": "1649774332", "answers": [{"text": "smaller"}]}]}, {"background": "Saturated hydrocarbons are given the general name of alkanes . The name of specific alkanes always ends in \u2013 ane . The first part of the name indicates how many carbon atoms each molecule of the alkane has. The smallest alkane is methane. It has just one carbon atom. The next largest is ethane with two carbon atoms. The chemical formulas and properties of methane, ethane, and other small alkanes are listed in the Table below . The boiling and melting points of alkanes are determined mainly by the number of carbon atoms they have. Alkanes with more carbon atoms generally boil and melt at higher temperatures.", "situation": "Joy is learning about alkanes in her chemistry class. She is testing the boiling and melting points of different alkanes to determine their size and order them appropriately. From her experiments, Joy learned that: Alkane A has a boiling point of -162 Celsius and a melting point of -183 Celsius; Alkane B has a boiling point of -89 Celsius and a melting point of -172 Celsius; and Alkane C has a boiling point of -42 Celsius and a melting point of -188 Celsius. ", "qas": [{"question": "Does Alkane A have more or less carbon atoms than Alkane B?", "id": "4097545316", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Saturated hydrocarbons are given the general name of alkanes . The name of specific alkanes always ends in \u2013 ane . The first part of the name indicates how many carbon atoms each molecule of the alkane has. The smallest alkane is methane. It has just one carbon atom. The next largest is ethane with two carbon atoms. The chemical formulas and properties of methane, ethane, and other small alkanes are listed in the Table below . The boiling and melting points of alkanes are determined mainly by the number of carbon atoms they have. Alkanes with more carbon atoms generally boil and melt at higher temperatures.", "situation": "Joy is learning about alkanes in her chemistry class. She is testing the boiling and melting points of different alkanes to determine their size and order them appropriately. From her experiments, Joy learned that: Alkane A has a boiling point of -162 Celsius and a melting point of -183 Celsius; Alkane B has a boiling point of -89 Celsius and a melting point of -172 Celsius; and Alkane C has a boiling point of -42 Celsius and a melting point of -188 Celsius. ", "qas": [{"question": "Does Alkane B have more or less carbon atoms than Alkane C?", "id": "4100756582", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Saturated hydrocarbons are given the general name of alkanes . The name of specific alkanes always ends in \u2013 ane . The first part of the name indicates how many carbon atoms each molecule of the alkane has. The smallest alkane is methane. It has just one carbon atom. The next largest is ethane with two carbon atoms. The chemical formulas and properties of methane, ethane, and other small alkanes are listed in the Table below . The boiling and melting points of alkanes are determined mainly by the number of carbon atoms they have. Alkanes with more carbon atoms generally boil and melt at higher temperatures.", "situation": "Joy is learning about alkanes in her chemistry class. She is testing the boiling and melting points of different alkanes to determine their size and order them appropriately. From her experiments, Joy learned that: Alkane A has a boiling point of -162 Celsius and a melting point of -183 Celsius; Alkane B has a boiling point of -89 Celsius and a melting point of -172 Celsius; and Alkane C has a boiling point of -42 Celsius and a melting point of -188 Celsius. ", "qas": [{"question": "Does Alkane A have more or less carbon atoms than Alkane C?", "id": "4097676389", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Saturated hydrocarbons are given the general name of alkanes . The name of specific alkanes always ends in \u2013 ane . The first part of the name indicates how many carbon atoms each molecule of the alkane has. The smallest alkane is methane. It has just one carbon atom. The next largest is ethane with two carbon atoms. The chemical formulas and properties of methane, ethane, and other small alkanes are listed in the Table below . The boiling and melting points of alkanes are determined mainly by the number of carbon atoms they have. Alkanes with more carbon atoms generally boil and melt at higher temperatures.", "situation": "Joy is learning about alkanes in her chemistry class. She is testing the boiling and melting points of different alkanes to determine their size and order them appropriately. From her experiments, Joy learned that: Alkane A has a boiling point of -162 Celsius and a melting point of -183 Celsius; Alkane B has a boiling point of -89 Celsius and a melting point of -172 Celsius; and Alkane C has a boiling point of -42 Celsius and a melting point of -188 Celsius. ", "qas": [{"question": "Does Alkane C have more or less carbon atoms than Alkane A?", "id": "4103574629", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Saturated hydrocarbons are given the general name of alkanes . The name of specific alkanes always ends in \u2013 ane . The first part of the name indicates how many carbon atoms each molecule of the alkane has. The smallest alkane is methane. It has just one carbon atom. The next largest is ethane with two carbon atoms. The chemical formulas and properties of methane, ethane, and other small alkanes are listed in the Table below . The boiling and melting points of alkanes are determined mainly by the number of carbon atoms they have. Alkanes with more carbon atoms generally boil and melt at higher temperatures.", "situation": "Joy is learning about alkanes in her chemistry class. She is testing the boiling and melting points of different alkanes to determine their size and order them appropriately. From her experiments, Joy learned that: Alkane A has a boiling point of -162 Celsius and a melting point of -183 Celsius; Alkane B has a boiling point of -89 Celsius and a melting point of -172 Celsius; and Alkane C has a boiling point of -42 Celsius and a melting point of -188 Celsius. ", "qas": [{"question": "Does Alkane B have more or less carbon atoms than Alkane A?", "id": "4100494436", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Trees can benefit fauna. The most common examples are silvopasture where cattle, goats, or sheep browse on grasses grown under trees. In hot climates, the animals are less stressed and put on weight faster when grazing in a cooler, shaded environment. The leaves of trees or shrubs can also serve as fodder.", "situation": "Wyatt and Earl both own cattle ranches in Texas. Wyatt's ranch is open and sunny with very few trees for shade. Earl's ranch has a mix of open, sunny areas as well as areas with a lot of trees and shade. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the cattle on Wyatt's farm be more or less stressed than the cattle on Earl's farm?", "id": "722851542", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Trees can benefit fauna. The most common examples are silvopasture where cattle, goats, or sheep browse on grasses grown under trees. In hot climates, the animals are less stressed and put on weight faster when grazing in a cooler, shaded environment. The leaves of trees or shrubs can also serve as fodder.", "situation": "Wyatt and Earl both own cattle ranches in Texas. Wyatt's ranch is open and sunny with very few trees for shade. Earl's ranch has a mix of open, sunny areas as well as areas with a lot of trees and shade. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the cattle on Earl's farm be more or less stressed than the cattle on Wyatt's farm?", "id": "510056150", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Trees can benefit fauna. The most common examples are silvopasture where cattle, goats, or sheep browse on grasses grown under trees. In hot climates, the animals are less stressed and put on weight faster when grazing in a cooler, shaded environment. The leaves of trees or shrubs can also serve as fodder.", "situation": "Wyatt and Earl both own cattle ranches in Texas. Wyatt's ranch is open and sunny with very few trees for shade. Earl's ranch has a mix of open, sunny areas as well as areas with a lot of trees and shade. ", "qas": [{"question": "Whose cattle will be less stressed, Wyatt's or Earl's?", "id": "1885915845", "answers": [{"text": "Earl's"}]}]}, {"background": "Trees can benefit fauna. The most common examples are silvopasture where cattle, goats, or sheep browse on grasses grown under trees. In hot climates, the animals are less stressed and put on weight faster when grazing in a cooler, shaded environment. The leaves of trees or shrubs can also serve as fodder.", "situation": "Wyatt and Earl both own cattle ranches in Texas. Wyatt's ranch is open and sunny with very few trees for shade. Earl's ranch has a mix of open, sunny areas as well as areas with a lot of trees and shade. ", "qas": [{"question": "Whose cattle will be more stressed, Wyatt's or Earl's?", "id": "1879493313", "answers": [{"text": "Wyatt's"}]}]}, {"background": "Trees can benefit fauna. The most common examples are silvopasture where cattle, goats, or sheep browse on grasses grown under trees. In hot climates, the animals are less stressed and put on weight faster when grazing in a cooler, shaded environment. The leaves of trees or shrubs can also serve as fodder.", "situation": "Wyatt and Earl both own cattle ranches in Texas. Wyatt's ranch is open and sunny with very few trees for shade. Earl's ranch has a mix of open, sunny areas as well as areas with a lot of trees and shade. ", "qas": [{"question": "Whose cattle will put on weight faster, Wyatt's or Earl's?", "id": "2736376893", "answers": [{"text": "Earl's"}]}]}, {"background": "Trees can benefit fauna. The most common examples are silvopasture where cattle, goats, or sheep browse on grasses grown under trees. In hot climates, the animals are less stressed and put on weight faster when grazing in a cooler, shaded environment. The leaves of trees or shrubs can also serve as fodder.", "situation": "Wyatt and Earl both own cattle ranches in Texas. Wyatt's ranch is open and sunny with very few trees for shade. Earl's ranch has a mix of open, sunny areas as well as areas with a lot of trees and shade. ", "qas": [{"question": "Whose cattle will put on weight slower, Wyatt's or Earl's?", "id": "2774781012", "answers": [{"text": "Wyatt's"}]}]}, {"background": "Trees can benefit fauna. The most common examples are silvopasture where cattle, goats, or sheep browse on grasses grown under trees. In hot climates, the animals are less stressed and put on weight faster when grazing in a cooler, shaded environment. The leaves of trees or shrubs can also serve as fodder.", "situation": "Wyatt and Earl both own cattle ranches in Texas. Wyatt's ranch is open and sunny with very few trees for shade. Earl's ranch has a mix of open, sunny areas as well as areas with a lot of trees and shade. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Wyatt's cattle gain weight faster or slower than Earl's cattle?", "id": "3005272120", "answers": [{"text": "slower"}]}]}, {"background": "Trees can benefit fauna. The most common examples are silvopasture where cattle, goats, or sheep browse on grasses grown under trees. In hot climates, the animals are less stressed and put on weight faster when grazing in a cooler, shaded environment. The leaves of trees or shrubs can also serve as fodder.", "situation": "Wyatt and Earl both own cattle ranches in Texas. Wyatt's ranch is open and sunny with very few trees for shade. Earl's ranch has a mix of open, sunny areas as well as areas with a lot of trees and shade. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Earl's cattle gain weight faster or slower than Wyatt's's cattle?", "id": "1225183442", "answers": [{"text": "faster"}]}]}, {"background": "Anemophilous pollen grains are light and non-sticky, so that they can be transported by air currents. They are typically 20\u201360 micrometres (0.0008\u20130.0024 in) in diameter, although the pollen grains of Pinus species can be much larger and much less dense. Anemophilous plants possess well-exposed stamens so that the pollens are exposed to wind currents and also have large and feathery stigma to easily trap airborne pollen grains. Pollen from anemophilous plants tends to be smaller and lighter than pollen from entomophilous ones, with very low nutritional value to insects. However, insects sometimes gather pollen from staminate anemophilous flowers at times when higher-protein pollens from entomophilous flowers are scarce. Anemophilous pollens may also be inadvertently captured by bees' electrostatic field. This may explain why, though bees are not observed to visit ragweed flowers, its pollen is often found in honey made during the ragweed floral bloom. Other flowers that are generally anemophilous are observed to be actively worked by bees, with solitary bees often visiting grass flowers, and the larger honeybees and bumblebees frequently gathering pollen from corn tassels and other grains.", "situation": "Henry is a botanist and has recently discovered two new flowers in a region previously unexplored by humans. He is studying the properties of each plant in order to correctly classify them. So far, he has observed that the pollen from Flower A is smaller and lower in protein than the pollen from Flower B. ", "qas": [{"question": "Which flower is an anemophilous plant?", "id": "2696888055", "answers": [{"text": "Flower A"}]}]}, {"background": "Anemophilous pollen grains are light and non-sticky, so that they can be transported by air currents. They are typically 20\u201360 micrometres (0.0008\u20130.0024 in) in diameter, although the pollen grains of Pinus species can be much larger and much less dense. Anemophilous plants possess well-exposed stamens so that the pollens are exposed to wind currents and also have large and feathery stigma to easily trap airborne pollen grains. Pollen from anemophilous plants tends to be smaller and lighter than pollen from entomophilous ones, with very low nutritional value to insects. However, insects sometimes gather pollen from staminate anemophilous flowers at times when higher-protein pollens from entomophilous flowers are scarce. Anemophilous pollens may also be inadvertently captured by bees' electrostatic field. This may explain why, though bees are not observed to visit ragweed flowers, its pollen is often found in honey made during the ragweed floral bloom. Other flowers that are generally anemophilous are observed to be actively worked by bees, with solitary bees often visiting grass flowers, and the larger honeybees and bumblebees frequently gathering pollen from corn tassels and other grains.", "situation": "Henry is a botanist and has recently discovered two new flowers in a region previously unexplored by humans. He is studying the properties of each plant in order to correctly classify them. So far, he has observed that the pollen from Flower A is smaller and lower in protein than the pollen from Flower B. ", "qas": [{"question": "Which flower is an entomophilous plant?", "id": "3793043321", "answers": [{"text": "Flower B"}]}]}, {"background": "Anemophilous pollen grains are light and non-sticky, so that they can be transported by air currents. They are typically 20\u201360 micrometres (0.0008\u20130.0024 in) in diameter, although the pollen grains of Pinus species can be much larger and much less dense. Anemophilous plants possess well-exposed stamens so that the pollens are exposed to wind currents and also have large and feathery stigma to easily trap airborne pollen grains. Pollen from anemophilous plants tends to be smaller and lighter than pollen from entomophilous ones, with very low nutritional value to insects. However, insects sometimes gather pollen from staminate anemophilous flowers at times when higher-protein pollens from entomophilous flowers are scarce. Anemophilous pollens may also be inadvertently captured by bees' electrostatic field. This may explain why, though bees are not observed to visit ragweed flowers, its pollen is often found in honey made during the ragweed floral bloom. Other flowers that are generally anemophilous are observed to be actively worked by bees, with solitary bees often visiting grass flowers, and the larger honeybees and bumblebees frequently gathering pollen from corn tassels and other grains.", "situation": "Henry is a botanist and has recently discovered two new flowers in a region previously unexplored by humans. He is studying the properties of each plant in order to correctly classify them. So far, he has observed that the pollen from Flower A is smaller and lower in protein than the pollen from Flower B. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is flower A an entomophilous or anemophilous plant?", "id": "3977397212", "answers": [{"text": "anemophilous "}]}]}, {"background": "Anemophilous pollen grains are light and non-sticky, so that they can be transported by air currents. They are typically 20\u201360 micrometres (0.0008\u20130.0024 in) in diameter, although the pollen grains of Pinus species can be much larger and much less dense. Anemophilous plants possess well-exposed stamens so that the pollens are exposed to wind currents and also have large and feathery stigma to easily trap airborne pollen grains. Pollen from anemophilous plants tends to be smaller and lighter than pollen from entomophilous ones, with very low nutritional value to insects. However, insects sometimes gather pollen from staminate anemophilous flowers at times when higher-protein pollens from entomophilous flowers are scarce. Anemophilous pollens may also be inadvertently captured by bees' electrostatic field. This may explain why, though bees are not observed to visit ragweed flowers, its pollen is often found in honey made during the ragweed floral bloom. Other flowers that are generally anemophilous are observed to be actively worked by bees, with solitary bees often visiting grass flowers, and the larger honeybees and bumblebees frequently gathering pollen from corn tassels and other grains.", "situation": "Henry is a botanist and has recently discovered two new flowers in a region previously unexplored by humans. He is studying the properties of each plant in order to correctly classify them. So far, he has observed that the pollen from Flower A is smaller and lower in protein than the pollen from Flower B. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is flower B an entomophilous or anemophilous plant?", "id": "3980084189", "answers": [{"text": "entomophilous"}]}]}, {"background": "Anemophilous pollen grains are light and non-sticky, so that they can be transported by air currents. They are typically 20\u201360 micrometres (0.0008\u20130.0024 in) in diameter, although the pollen grains of Pinus species can be much larger and much less dense. Anemophilous plants possess well-exposed stamens so that the pollens are exposed to wind currents and also have large and feathery stigma to easily trap airborne pollen grains. Pollen from anemophilous plants tends to be smaller and lighter than pollen from entomophilous ones, with very low nutritional value to insects. However, insects sometimes gather pollen from staminate anemophilous flowers at times when higher-protein pollens from entomophilous flowers are scarce. Anemophilous pollens may also be inadvertently captured by bees' electrostatic field. This may explain why, though bees are not observed to visit ragweed flowers, its pollen is often found in honey made during the ragweed floral bloom. Other flowers that are generally anemophilous are observed to be actively worked by bees, with solitary bees often visiting grass flowers, and the larger honeybees and bumblebees frequently gathering pollen from corn tassels and other grains.", "situation": "Henry is a botanist and has recently discovered two new flowers in a region previously unexplored by humans. He is studying the properties of each plant in order to correctly classify them. So far, he has observed that the pollen from Flower A is smaller and lower in protein than the pollen from Flower B. ", "qas": [{"question": "Are bees more likely to pollinate flower A or flower B?", "id": "4152247384", "answers": [{"text": "Flower B"}]}]}, {"background": "Anemophilous pollen grains are light and non-sticky, so that they can be transported by air currents. They are typically 20\u201360 micrometres (0.0008\u20130.0024 in) in diameter, although the pollen grains of Pinus species can be much larger and much less dense. Anemophilous plants possess well-exposed stamens so that the pollens are exposed to wind currents and also have large and feathery stigma to easily trap airborne pollen grains. Pollen from anemophilous plants tends to be smaller and lighter than pollen from entomophilous ones, with very low nutritional value to insects. However, insects sometimes gather pollen from staminate anemophilous flowers at times when higher-protein pollens from entomophilous flowers are scarce. Anemophilous pollens may also be inadvertently captured by bees' electrostatic field. This may explain why, though bees are not observed to visit ragweed flowers, its pollen is often found in honey made during the ragweed floral bloom. Other flowers that are generally anemophilous are observed to be actively worked by bees, with solitary bees often visiting grass flowers, and the larger honeybees and bumblebees frequently gathering pollen from corn tassels and other grains.", "situation": "Henry is a botanist and has recently discovered two new flowers in a region previously unexplored by humans. He is studying the properties of each plant in order to correctly classify them. So far, he has observed that the pollen from Flower A is smaller and lower in protein than the pollen from Flower B. ", "qas": [{"question": "Are bees less likely to pollinate flower A or flower B?", "id": "4162077788", "answers": [{"text": "Flower A"}]}]}, {"background": "Anemophilous pollen grains are light and non-sticky, so that they can be transported by air currents. They are typically 20\u201360 micrometres (0.0008\u20130.0024 in) in diameter, although the pollen grains of Pinus species can be much larger and much less dense. Anemophilous plants possess well-exposed stamens so that the pollens are exposed to wind currents and also have large and feathery stigma to easily trap airborne pollen grains. Pollen from anemophilous plants tends to be smaller and lighter than pollen from entomophilous ones, with very low nutritional value to insects. However, insects sometimes gather pollen from staminate anemophilous flowers at times when higher-protein pollens from entomophilous flowers are scarce. Anemophilous pollens may also be inadvertently captured by bees' electrostatic field. This may explain why, though bees are not observed to visit ragweed flowers, its pollen is often found in honey made during the ragweed floral bloom. Other flowers that are generally anemophilous are observed to be actively worked by bees, with solitary bees often visiting grass flowers, and the larger honeybees and bumblebees frequently gathering pollen from corn tassels and other grains.", "situation": "Henry is a botanist and has recently discovered two new flowers in a region previously unexplored by humans. He is studying the properties of each plant in order to correctly classify them. So far, he has observed that the pollen from Flower A is smaller and lower in protein than the pollen from Flower B. ", "qas": [{"question": "Are bees more or less likely to pollinate flower A than flower B?", "id": "3061991418", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Anemophilous pollen grains are light and non-sticky, so that they can be transported by air currents. They are typically 20\u201360 micrometres (0.0008\u20130.0024 in) in diameter, although the pollen grains of Pinus species can be much larger and much less dense. Anemophilous plants possess well-exposed stamens so that the pollens are exposed to wind currents and also have large and feathery stigma to easily trap airborne pollen grains. Pollen from anemophilous plants tends to be smaller and lighter than pollen from entomophilous ones, with very low nutritional value to insects. However, insects sometimes gather pollen from staminate anemophilous flowers at times when higher-protein pollens from entomophilous flowers are scarce. Anemophilous pollens may also be inadvertently captured by bees' electrostatic field. This may explain why, though bees are not observed to visit ragweed flowers, its pollen is often found in honey made during the ragweed floral bloom. Other flowers that are generally anemophilous are observed to be actively worked by bees, with solitary bees often visiting grass flowers, and the larger honeybees and bumblebees frequently gathering pollen from corn tassels and other grains.", "situation": "Henry is a botanist and has recently discovered two new flowers in a region previously unexplored by humans. He is studying the properties of each plant in order to correctly classify them. So far, he has observed that the pollen from Flower A is smaller and lower in protein than the pollen from Flower B. ", "qas": [{"question": "Are bees more or less likely to pollinate flower B than flower A?", "id": "3062908922", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Abiotic stress, as a natural part of every ecosystem, will affect organisms in a variety of ways. Although these effects may be either beneficial or detrimental, the location of the area is crucial in determining the extent of the impact that abiotic stress will have. The higher the latitude of the area affected, the greater the impact of abiotic stress will be on that area. So, a taiga or boreal forest is at the mercy of whatever abiotic stress factors may come along, while tropical zones are much less susceptible to such stressors.", "situation": "Ralph is studying the effects of climate change on crop production in order to determine the effects of abiotic stress in different regions. He is studying two farms: Farm A is located in the United States and Farm B is locate in Mexico.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Farm A experience more or less abiotic stress than Farm B?", "id": "1441345459", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Abiotic stress, as a natural part of every ecosystem, will affect organisms in a variety of ways. Although these effects may be either beneficial or detrimental, the location of the area is crucial in determining the extent of the impact that abiotic stress will have. The higher the latitude of the area affected, the greater the impact of abiotic stress will be on that area. So, a taiga or boreal forest is at the mercy of whatever abiotic stress factors may come along, while tropical zones are much less susceptible to such stressors.", "situation": "Ralph is studying the effects of climate change on crop production in order to determine the effects of abiotic stress in different regions. He is studying two farms: Farm A is located in the United States and Farm B is locate in Mexico.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Farm B experience more or less abiotic stress than Farm A?", "id": "1444687795", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Abiotic stress, as a natural part of every ecosystem, will affect organisms in a variety of ways. Although these effects may be either beneficial or detrimental, the location of the area is crucial in determining the extent of the impact that abiotic stress will have. The higher the latitude of the area affected, the greater the impact of abiotic stress will be on that area. So, a taiga or boreal forest is at the mercy of whatever abiotic stress factors may come along, while tropical zones are much less susceptible to such stressors.", "situation": "Ralph is studying the effects of climate change on crop production in order to determine the effects of abiotic stress in different regions. He is studying two farms: Farm A is located in the United States and Farm B is locate in Mexico.", "qas": [{"question": "Which farm will experience more abiotic stress?", "id": "2481203962", "answers": [{"text": "Farm A"}]}]}, {"background": "Abiotic stress, as a natural part of every ecosystem, will affect organisms in a variety of ways. Although these effects may be either beneficial or detrimental, the location of the area is crucial in determining the extent of the impact that abiotic stress will have. The higher the latitude of the area affected, the greater the impact of abiotic stress will be on that area. So, a taiga or boreal forest is at the mercy of whatever abiotic stress factors may come along, while tropical zones are much less susceptible to such stressors.", "situation": "Ralph is studying the effects of climate change on crop production in order to determine the effects of abiotic stress in different regions. He is studying two farms: Farm A is located in the United States and Farm B is locate in Mexico.", "qas": [{"question": "Which farm will experience less abiotic stress?", "id": "2484218622", "answers": [{"text": "Farm B"}]}]}, {"background": "Emission is the opposite of absorption, it is when an object emits radiation. Objects tend to emit amounts and wavelengths of radiation depending on their \"black body\" emission curves, therefore hotter objects tend to emit more radiation, with shorter wavelengths. Colder objects emit less radiation, with longer wavelengths. For example, the Sun is approximately 6,000 K (5,730 \u00b0C; 10,340 \u00b0F), its radiation peaks near 500 nm, and is visible to the human eye. Earth is approximately 290 K (17 \u00b0C; 62 \u00b0F), so its radiation peaks near 10,000 nm, and is much too long to be visible to humans. The light that is observed on photographs of earth from space and with the naked eye is only reflected visible light.", "situation": "Sarah is an astrophysicist studying the properties of two newly discovered stars: Star S and Star T. Not much is known about the stars other than the temperature, and Sarah only knows that Star S is much hotter than Star T. ", "qas": [{"question": "Which star will emit more radiation?", "id": "1553226385", "answers": [{"text": "Star S"}]}]}, {"background": "Emission is the opposite of absorption, it is when an object emits radiation. Objects tend to emit amounts and wavelengths of radiation depending on their \"black body\" emission curves, therefore hotter objects tend to emit more radiation, with shorter wavelengths. Colder objects emit less radiation, with longer wavelengths. For example, the Sun is approximately 6,000 K (5,730 \u00b0C; 10,340 \u00b0F), its radiation peaks near 500 nm, and is visible to the human eye. Earth is approximately 290 K (17 \u00b0C; 62 \u00b0F), so its radiation peaks near 10,000 nm, and is much too long to be visible to humans. The light that is observed on photographs of earth from space and with the naked eye is only reflected visible light.", "situation": "Sarah is an astrophysicist studying the properties of two newly discovered stars: Star S and Star T. Not much is known about the stars other than the temperature, and Sarah only knows that Star S is much hotter than Star T. ", "qas": [{"question": "Which star will emit less radiation?", "id": "1554930325", "answers": [{"text": "Star T"}]}]}, {"background": "Emission is the opposite of absorption, it is when an object emits radiation. Objects tend to emit amounts and wavelengths of radiation depending on their \"black body\" emission curves, therefore hotter objects tend to emit more radiation, with shorter wavelengths. Colder objects emit less radiation, with longer wavelengths. For example, the Sun is approximately 6,000 K (5,730 \u00b0C; 10,340 \u00b0F), its radiation peaks near 500 nm, and is visible to the human eye. Earth is approximately 290 K (17 \u00b0C; 62 \u00b0F), so its radiation peaks near 10,000 nm, and is much too long to be visible to humans. The light that is observed on photographs of earth from space and with the naked eye is only reflected visible light.", "situation": "Sarah is an astrophysicist studying the properties of two newly discovered stars: Star S and Star T. Not much is known about the stars other than the temperature, and Sarah only knows that Star S is much hotter than Star T. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Star S emit more or less radiation than Star T?", "id": "550002562", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Emission is the opposite of absorption, it is when an object emits radiation. Objects tend to emit amounts and wavelengths of radiation depending on their \"black body\" emission curves, therefore hotter objects tend to emit more radiation, with shorter wavelengths. Colder objects emit less radiation, with longer wavelengths. For example, the Sun is approximately 6,000 K (5,730 \u00b0C; 10,340 \u00b0F), its radiation peaks near 500 nm, and is visible to the human eye. Earth is approximately 290 K (17 \u00b0C; 62 \u00b0F), so its radiation peaks near 10,000 nm, and is much too long to be visible to humans. The light that is observed on photographs of earth from space and with the naked eye is only reflected visible light.", "situation": "Sarah is an astrophysicist studying the properties of two newly discovered stars: Star S and Star T. Not much is known about the stars other than the temperature, and Sarah only knows that Star S is much hotter than Star T. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Star T emit more or less radiation than Star S?", "id": "552624002", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Emission is the opposite of absorption, it is when an object emits radiation. Objects tend to emit amounts and wavelengths of radiation depending on their \"black body\" emission curves, therefore hotter objects tend to emit more radiation, with shorter wavelengths. Colder objects emit less radiation, with longer wavelengths. For example, the Sun is approximately 6,000 K (5,730 \u00b0C; 10,340 \u00b0F), its radiation peaks near 500 nm, and is visible to the human eye. Earth is approximately 290 K (17 \u00b0C; 62 \u00b0F), so its radiation peaks near 10,000 nm, and is much too long to be visible to humans. The light that is observed on photographs of earth from space and with the naked eye is only reflected visible light.", "situation": "Sarah is an astrophysicist studying the properties of two newly discovered stars: Star S and Star T. Not much is known about the stars other than the temperature, and Sarah only knows that Star S is much hotter than Star T. ", "qas": [{"question": "Which star will emit longer wavelengths of radiation?", "id": "2651611426", "answers": [{"text": "Star T"}]}]}, {"background": "Emission is the opposite of absorption, it is when an object emits radiation. Objects tend to emit amounts and wavelengths of radiation depending on their \"black body\" emission curves, therefore hotter objects tend to emit more radiation, with shorter wavelengths. Colder objects emit less radiation, with longer wavelengths. For example, the Sun is approximately 6,000 K (5,730 \u00b0C; 10,340 \u00b0F), its radiation peaks near 500 nm, and is visible to the human eye. Earth is approximately 290 K (17 \u00b0C; 62 \u00b0F), so its radiation peaks near 10,000 nm, and is much too long to be visible to humans. The light that is observed on photographs of earth from space and with the naked eye is only reflected visible light.", "situation": "Sarah is an astrophysicist studying the properties of two newly discovered stars: Star S and Star T. Not much is known about the stars other than the temperature, and Sarah only knows that Star S is much hotter than Star T. ", "qas": [{"question": "Which star will emit shorter wavelengths of radiation?", "id": "52650402", "answers": [{"text": "Star S"}]}]}, {"background": "Wind causes the generation of sound. The movement of air causes movements of parts of natural objects, such as leaves or grass. These objects will produce sound if they touch each other. Even a soft wind will cause a low level of environmental noise. If the wind is blowing harder, it may produce howling sounds of varying frequencies. This may be caused by the wind blowing over cavities, or by vortices created in the air downstream of an object. Especially on high buildings, many structural parts may be a cause of annoying noise at certain wind conditions. Examples of these parts are balconies, ventilation openings, roof openings or cables.", "situation": "Ashley is relocating to Chicago for a new job. She is currently looking for a place to live and is considering two different apartment buildings, Suncrest Villas and Highland Heights. The apartment at Suncrest Villas is on the first floor of the building and the apartment at Highland Heights is on the top floor of the building. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which apartment will the environmental noise from the wind be louder?", "id": "1194819090", "answers": [{"text": "Highland Heights"}]}]}, {"background": "Wind causes the generation of sound. The movement of air causes movements of parts of natural objects, such as leaves or grass. These objects will produce sound if they touch each other. Even a soft wind will cause a low level of environmental noise. If the wind is blowing harder, it may produce howling sounds of varying frequencies. This may be caused by the wind blowing over cavities, or by vortices created in the air downstream of an object. Especially on high buildings, many structural parts may be a cause of annoying noise at certain wind conditions. Examples of these parts are balconies, ventilation openings, roof openings or cables.", "situation": "Ashley is relocating to Chicago for a new job. She is currently looking for a place to live and is considering two different apartment buildings, Suncrest Villas and Highland Heights. The apartment at Suncrest Villas is on the first floor of the building and the apartment at Highland Heights is on the top floor of the building. ", "qas": [{"question": "In which apartment will the environmental noise from the wind be quieter?", "id": "3323100806", "answers": [{"text": "Suncrest Villas"}]}]}, {"background": "Wind causes the generation of sound. The movement of air causes movements of parts of natural objects, such as leaves or grass. These objects will produce sound if they touch each other. Even a soft wind will cause a low level of environmental noise. If the wind is blowing harder, it may produce howling sounds of varying frequencies. This may be caused by the wind blowing over cavities, or by vortices created in the air downstream of an object. Especially on high buildings, many structural parts may be a cause of annoying noise at certain wind conditions. Examples of these parts are balconies, ventilation openings, roof openings or cables.", "situation": "Ashley is relocating to Chicago for a new job. She is currently looking for a place to live and is considering two different apartment buildings, Suncrest Villas and Highland Heights. The apartment at Suncrest Villas is on the first floor of the building and the apartment at Highland Heights is on the top floor of the building. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the noise from the wind in the Suncrest Villas apartment be louder or softer than the Highland Heights apartment?", "id": "1183288983", "answers": [{"text": "softer"}]}]}, {"background": "Wind causes the generation of sound. The movement of air causes movements of parts of natural objects, such as leaves or grass. These objects will produce sound if they touch each other. Even a soft wind will cause a low level of environmental noise. If the wind is blowing harder, it may produce howling sounds of varying frequencies. This may be caused by the wind blowing over cavities, or by vortices created in the air downstream of an object. Especially on high buildings, many structural parts may be a cause of annoying noise at certain wind conditions. Examples of these parts are balconies, ventilation openings, roof openings or cables.", "situation": "Ashley is relocating to Chicago for a new job. She is currently looking for a place to live and is considering two different apartment buildings, Suncrest Villas and Highland Heights. The apartment at Suncrest Villas is on the first floor of the building and the apartment at Highland Heights is on the top floor of the building. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will the noise from the wind in the Highland Heights apartment be louder or softer than the Suncrest Villas apartment?", "id": "989236887", "answers": [{"text": "louder"}]}]}, {"background": "Windbreaks reduce wind velocity over and around crops. This increases yields through reduced drying of the crop and/or by preventing the crop from toppling in strong wind gusts.", "situation": "Hap and Hal are both farmers in Kansas. Hap recently built a windbreak on his farm, but Hal is trying to save money and did not build a windbreak. ", "qas": [{"question": "Whose farm is most likely to have an increase in crop production, Hap or Hal?", "id": "1067028713", "answers": [{"text": "Hap"}]}]}, {"background": "Windbreaks reduce wind velocity over and around crops. This increases yields through reduced drying of the crop and/or by preventing the crop from toppling in strong wind gusts.", "situation": "Hap and Hal are both farmers in Kansas. Hap recently built a windbreak on his farm, but Hal is trying to save money and did not build a windbreak. ", "qas": [{"question": "Whose farm is least likely to have an increase in crop production, Hap or Hal?", "id": "3482161471", "answers": [{"text": "Hal"}]}]}, {"background": "Windbreaks reduce wind velocity over and around crops. This increases yields through reduced drying of the crop and/or by preventing the crop from toppling in strong wind gusts.", "situation": "Hap and Hal are both farmers in Kansas. Hap recently built a windbreak on his farm, but Hal is trying to save money and did not build a windbreak. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Hap's farm produce more or less crops than Hal's farm?", "id": "800623164", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Windbreaks reduce wind velocity over and around crops. This increases yields through reduced drying of the crop and/or by preventing the crop from toppling in strong wind gusts.", "situation": "Hap and Hal are both farmers in Kansas. Hap recently built a windbreak on his farm, but Hal is trying to save money and did not build a windbreak. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Hal's farm produce more or less crops than Hap's farm?", "id": "789350972", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Windbreaks reduce wind velocity over and around crops. This increases yields through reduced drying of the crop and/or by preventing the crop from toppling in strong wind gusts.", "situation": "Hap and Hal are both farmers in Kansas. Hap recently built a windbreak on his farm, but Hal is trying to save money and did not build a windbreak. ", "qas": [{"question": "Whose crops are more likely to topple in strong wind gusts, Hap or Hal?", "id": "3950415607", "answers": [{"text": "Hal"}]}]}, {"background": "Windbreaks reduce wind velocity over and around crops. This increases yields through reduced drying of the crop and/or by preventing the crop from toppling in strong wind gusts.", "situation": "Hap and Hal are both farmers in Kansas. Hap recently built a windbreak on his farm, but Hal is trying to save money and did not build a windbreak. ", "qas": [{"question": "Whose crops are least likely to topple in strong wind gusts, Hap or Hal?", "id": "2095550301", "answers": [{"text": "Hap"}]}]}, {"background": "Windbreaks reduce wind velocity over and around crops. This increases yields through reduced drying of the crop and/or by preventing the crop from toppling in strong wind gusts.", "situation": "Hap and Hal are both farmers in Kansas. Hap recently built a windbreak on his farm, but Hal is trying to save money and did not build a windbreak. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Hap more or less likely than Hal to experience reduced drying of crops?", "id": "1989906465", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Windbreaks reduce wind velocity over and around crops. This increases yields through reduced drying of the crop and/or by preventing the crop from toppling in strong wind gusts.", "situation": "Hap and Hal are both farmers in Kansas. Hap recently built a windbreak on his farm, but Hal is trying to save money and did not build a windbreak. ", "qas": [{"question": "Is Hal more or less likely than Hap to experience reduced drying of crops?", "id": "1982304289", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Windbreaks reduce wind velocity over and around crops. This increases yields through reduced drying of the crop and/or by preventing the crop from toppling in strong wind gusts.", "situation": "Hap and Hal are both farmers in Kansas. Hap recently built a windbreak on his farm, but Hal is trying to save money and did not build a windbreak. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Hap's farm experience more or less wind velocity on their crops than Hal's farm?", "id": "3553006604", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Windbreaks reduce wind velocity over and around crops. This increases yields through reduced drying of the crop and/or by preventing the crop from toppling in strong wind gusts.", "situation": "Hap and Hal are both farmers in Kansas. Hap recently built a windbreak on his farm, but Hal is trying to save money and did not build a windbreak. ", "qas": [{"question": "Will Hal's farm experience more or less wind velocity on their crops than Hap's farm?", "id": "3534918668", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u00e2\u20ac\u201c the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Beth grabbed her container of chili from he fridge and tossed in the microwave for 4 minutes. However, she forgot to vent the lid and after several minutes the dish exploded spraying chili all over the inside of the microwave.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the temperature of the gas increasing or staying constant?", "id": "2916445236", "answers": [{"text": "increasing"}]}]}, {"background": "We discussed earlier some basic principles about the behavior of gases called the kinetic-molecular theory. Among other things, this theory suggests that gas molecules are in constant motion, and the average speed of the individual gas particles is dependent upon temperature \u00e2\u20ac\u201c the higher the temperature, the faster the molecules move. It is not just gas particles that are in constant motion. The molecules and ions that make up liquids and solutions are also continually moving in nearly random directions. As a result, molecules and ions in a solution will collide with one another fairly frequently. As with gases, a temperature increase will produce an increase in the average particle speed.", "situation": "Beth grabbed her container of chili from he fridge and tossed in the microwave for 4 minutes. However, she forgot to vent the lid and after several minutes the dish exploded spraying chili all over the inside of the microwave.", "qas": [{"question": "Were molecules in the dish colliding more or less frequently than in the fridge", "id": "284979772", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "A vapor light also produces visible light by electroluminescence The bulb contains a small amount of solid sodium or mercury as well as a mixture of neon and argon gases. When an electric current passes through the gases, it causes the solid sodium or mercury to change to a gas and emit visible light. Sodium vapor lights, like the streetlight pictured in the Figure below , produce yellowish light. Mercury vapor lights produce bluish light. In addition to lighting city streets, vapor lights are used to light highways and stadiums. The bulbs are very bright and long lasting so they are a good choice for these places.", "situation": "The local high school built a new stadium and wanted to be able to play night games. They decided to check into vapor lights. Eventually decided on Mercury vapor lights rather than Sodium vapor lights.", "qas": [{"question": "Which type of vapor light makes a bluish light?", "id": "3872079177", "answers": [{"text": "Mercury vapor"}]}]}, {"background": "A vapor light also produces visible light by electroluminescence The bulb contains a small amount of solid sodium or mercury as well as a mixture of neon and argon gases. When an electric current passes through the gases, it causes the solid sodium or mercury to change to a gas and emit visible light. Sodium vapor lights, like the streetlight pictured in the Figure below , produce yellowish light. Mercury vapor lights produce bluish light. In addition to lighting city streets, vapor lights are used to light highways and stadiums. The bulbs are very bright and long lasting so they are a good choice for these places.", "situation": "The local high school built a new stadium and wanted to be able to play night games. They decided to check into vapor lights. Eventually decided on Mercury vapor lights rather than Sodium vapor lights.", "qas": [{"question": "Which type of vapor light makes a yellowish light?", "id": "2748989090", "answers": [{"text": "Sodium"}]}]}, {"background": "A vapor light also produces visible light by electroluminescence The bulb contains a small amount of solid sodium or mercury as well as a mixture of neon and argon gases. When an electric current passes through the gases, it causes the solid sodium or mercury to change to a gas and emit visible light. Sodium vapor lights, like the streetlight pictured in the Figure below , produce yellowish light. Mercury vapor lights produce bluish light. In addition to lighting city streets, vapor lights are used to light highways and stadiums. The bulbs are very bright and long lasting so they are a good choice for these places.", "situation": "The local high school built a new stadium and wanted to be able to play night games. They decided to check into vapor lights. Eventually decided on Mercury vapor lights rather than Sodium vapor lights.", "qas": [{"question": "What kind of light is works by passing an electric current through gas?", "id": "294864464", "answers": [{"text": "vapor lights"}]}]}, {"background": "A vapor light also produces visible light by electroluminescence The bulb contains a small amount of solid sodium or mercury as well as a mixture of neon and argon gases. When an electric current passes through the gases, it causes the solid sodium or mercury to change to a gas and emit visible light. Sodium vapor lights, like the streetlight pictured in the Figure below , produce yellowish light. Mercury vapor lights produce bluish light. In addition to lighting city streets, vapor lights are used to light highways and stadiums. The bulbs are very bright and long lasting so they are a good choice for these places.", "situation": "The local high school built a new stadium and wanted to be able to play night games. They decided to check into vapor lights. Eventually decided on Mercury vapor lights rather than Sodium vapor lights.", "qas": [{"question": "What lights are bight and long lasting?", "id": "97598056", "answers": [{"text": "vapor lights"}]}]}, {"background": "A vapor light also produces visible light by electroluminescence The bulb contains a small amount of solid sodium or mercury as well as a mixture of neon and argon gases. When an electric current passes through the gases, it causes the solid sodium or mercury to change to a gas and emit visible light. Sodium vapor lights, like the streetlight pictured in the Figure below , produce yellowish light. Mercury vapor lights produce bluish light. In addition to lighting city streets, vapor lights are used to light highways and stadiums. The bulbs are very bright and long lasting so they are a good choice for these places.", "situation": "The high school wanted to play night games for football and baseball. After some discussion the school board decided that they needed a type of light that was bright and long lasting. Sodium vapor and mercury vapor lights where the two final choices and they decided to vote fo9r the final choice.", "qas": [{"question": "Which lights are bright and long lasting?", "id": "3094568469", "answers": [{"text": "Sodium vapor and mercury vapor lights"}]}]}, {"background": "A vapor light also produces visible light by electroluminescence The bulb contains a small amount of solid sodium or mercury as well as a mixture of neon and argon gases. When an electric current passes through the gases, it causes the solid sodium or mercury to change to a gas and emit visible light. Sodium vapor lights, like the streetlight pictured in the Figure below , produce yellowish light. Mercury vapor lights produce bluish light. In addition to lighting city streets, vapor lights are used to light highways and stadiums. The bulbs are very bright and long lasting so they are a good choice for these places.", "situation": "The high school wanted to play night games for football and baseball. After some discussion the school board decided that they needed a type of light that was bright and long lasting. Sodium vapor and mercury vapor lights where the two final choices and they decided to vote fo9r the final choice.", "qas": [{"question": "Which lights are bluish?", "id": "2887473127", "answers": [{"text": "mercury vapor"}]}]}, {"background": "A vapor light also produces visible light by electroluminescence The bulb contains a small amount of solid sodium or mercury as well as a mixture of neon and argon gases. When an electric current passes through the gases, it causes the solid sodium or mercury to change to a gas and emit visible light. Sodium vapor lights, like the streetlight pictured in the Figure below , produce yellowish light. Mercury vapor lights produce bluish light. In addition to lighting city streets, vapor lights are used to light highways and stadiums. The bulbs are very bright and long lasting so they are a good choice for these places.", "situation": "The high school wanted to play night games for football and baseball. After some discussion the school board decided that they needed a type of light that was bright and long lasting. Sodium vapor and mercury vapor lights where the two final choices and they decided to vote fo9r the final choice.", "qas": [{"question": "Which lights are yellowish?", "id": "3080083776", "answers": [{"text": "Sodium vapor"}]}]}, {"background": "A vapor light also produces visible light by electroluminescence The bulb contains a small amount of solid sodium or mercury as well as a mixture of neon and argon gases. When an electric current passes through the gases, it causes the solid sodium or mercury to change to a gas and emit visible light. Sodium vapor lights, like the streetlight pictured in the Figure below , produce yellowish light. Mercury vapor lights produce bluish light. In addition to lighting city streets, vapor lights are used to light highways and stadiums. The bulbs are very bright and long lasting so they are a good choice for these places.", "situation": "The high school wanted to play night games for football and baseball. After some discussion the school board decided that they needed a type of light that was bright and long lasting. Sodium vapor and mercury vapor lights where the two final choices and they decided to vote fo9r the final choice.", "qas": [{"question": "Which contain neon and argon gas?", "id": "3538639614", "answers": [{"text": "Sodium vapor and mercury vapor lights"}]}]}, {"background": "Many mutations have no effect on the proteins they encode. These mutations are considered neutral. Occasionally, a mutation may make a protein even better than it was before. Or the protein might help the organism adapt to a new environment. These mutations are considered beneficial. An example is a mutation that helps bacteria resist antibiotics. Bacteria with the mutation increase in numbers, so the mutation becomes more common. Other mutations are harmful. They may even be deadly. Harmful mutations often result in a protein that no longer can do its job. Some harmful mutations cause cancer or other genetic disorders.", "situation": "Mike was siting on his porch watching an albino squirrel and a regular grey squirrel run across the road when suddenly a birds swooped down and grabbed the albino squirrel. Mike new it was a mutation that made the squirrel an albino but he thought it was very pretty and was sad to see it die.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the albino squirrel have an advantage or a disadvantage?", "id": "1928226398", "answers": [{"text": "a disadvantage"}]}]}, {"background": "Many mutations have no effect on the proteins they encode. These mutations are considered neutral. Occasionally, a mutation may make a protein even better than it was before. Or the protein might help the organism adapt to a new environment. These mutations are considered beneficial. An example is a mutation that helps bacteria resist antibiotics. Bacteria with the mutation increase in numbers, so the mutation becomes more common. Other mutations are harmful. They may even be deadly. Harmful mutations often result in a protein that no longer can do its job. Some harmful mutations cause cancer or other genetic disorders.", "situation": "Mike was siting on his porch watching an albino squirrel and a regular grey squirrel run across the road when suddenly a birds swooped down and grabbed the albino squirrel. Mike new it was a mutation that made the squirrel an albino but he thought it was very pretty and was sad to see it die.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the grey squirrel have an advantage or a disadvantage?", "id": "2792383904", "answers": [{"text": "an advantage"}]}]}, {"background": "Many mutations have no effect on the proteins they encode. These mutations are considered neutral. Occasionally, a mutation may make a protein even better than it was before. Or the protein might help the organism adapt to a new environment. These mutations are considered beneficial. An example is a mutation that helps bacteria resist antibiotics. Bacteria with the mutation increase in numbers, so the mutation becomes more common. Other mutations are harmful. They may even be deadly. Harmful mutations often result in a protein that no longer can do its job. Some harmful mutations cause cancer or other genetic disorders.", "situation": "Mike was siting on his porch watching an albino squirrel and a regular grey squirrel run across the road and was struck by how different their colors were when suddenly a birds swooped down and grabbed the albino squirrel. Mike new it was a mutation that made the squirrel an albino but he thought it was very pretty and was sad to see it die.", "qas": [{"question": "Will there be more or less albino squirrels in the future", "id": "3055384613", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Many mutations have no effect on the proteins they encode. These mutations are considered neutral. Occasionally, a mutation may make a protein even better than it was before. Or the protein might help the organism adapt to a new environment. These mutations are considered beneficial. An example is a mutation that helps bacteria resist antibiotics. Bacteria with the mutation increase in numbers, so the mutation becomes more common. Other mutations are harmful. They may even be deadly. Harmful mutations often result in a protein that no longer can do its job. Some harmful mutations cause cancer or other genetic disorders.", "situation": "Mike was siting on his porch watching an albino squirrel and a regular grey squirrel run across the road and was struck by how different their colors were when suddenly a birds swooped down and grabbed the albino squirrel. Mike new it was a mutation that made the squirrel an albino but he thought it was very pretty and was sad to see it die.", "qas": [{"question": "Will there be more or less grey squirrels in the future", "id": "3328145255", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "The frequency of sound waves is measured in hertz (Hz), or the number of waves that pass a fixed point in a second. Human beings can normally hear sounds with a frequency between about 20 Hz and 20,000 Hz. Sounds with frequencies below 20 hertz are called infrasound . Sounds with frequencies above 20,000 hertz are called ultrasound . Some other animals can hear sounds in the ultrasound range. For example, dogs can hear sounds with frequencies as high as 50,000 Hz. You may have seen special whistles that dogs but not people can hear. The whistles produce a sound with a frequency too high for the human ear to detect. Other animals can hear even higher-frequency sounds. Bats, for example, can hear sounds with frequencies higher than 100,000 Hz.", "situation": "Mike saw his neighbors son playing with a whistle outside. Mike thought the whistle must be broken because the kid was blowing really hard but there was no sound coming out. The dog across the street was barking like crazy though.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the whistle making a sound above or below 20 hertz?", "id": "3641078014", "answers": [{"text": "below"}]}]}, {"background": "The frequency of sound waves is measured in hertz (Hz), or the number of waves that pass a fixed point in a second. Human beings can normally hear sounds with a frequency between about 20 Hz and 20,000 Hz. Sounds with frequencies below 20 hertz are called infrasound . Sounds with frequencies above 20,000 hertz are called ultrasound . Some other animals can hear sounds in the ultrasound range. For example, dogs can hear sounds with frequencies as high as 50,000 Hz. You may have seen special whistles that dogs but not people can hear. The whistles produce a sound with a frequency too high for the human ear to detect. Other animals can hear even higher-frequency sounds. Bats, for example, can hear sounds with frequencies higher than 100,000 Hz.", "situation": "Mike saw his neighbors son playing with a whistle outside. Mike thought the whistle must be broken because the kid was blowing really hard but there was no sound coming out. The dog across the street was barking like crazy though.", "qas": [{"question": "Who could hear the whistle?", "id": "4235945825", "answers": [{"text": "The dog"}]}]}, {"background": "The frequency of sound waves is measured in hertz (Hz), or the number of waves that pass a fixed point in a second. Human beings can normally hear sounds with a frequency between about 20 Hz and 20,000 Hz. Sounds with frequencies below 20 hertz are called infrasound . Sounds with frequencies above 20,000 hertz are called ultrasound . Some other animals can hear sounds in the ultrasound range. For example, dogs can hear sounds with frequencies as high as 50,000 Hz. You may have seen special whistles that dogs but not people can hear. The whistles produce a sound with a frequency too high for the human ear to detect. Other animals can hear even higher-frequency sounds. Bats, for example, can hear sounds with frequencies higher than 100,000 Hz.", "situation": "Mike saw his neighbors son playing with a whistle outside. Mike thought the whistle must be broken because the kid was blowing really hard but there was no sound coming out. The dog across the street was barking like crazy though.", "qas": [{"question": "Who could not hear the whistle?", "id": "2636867794", "answers": [{"text": "Mike"}]}]}, {"background": "The frequency of sound waves is measured in hertz (Hz), or the number of waves that pass a fixed point in a second. Human beings can normally hear sounds with a frequency between about 20 Hz and 20,000 Hz. Sounds with frequencies below 20 hertz are called infrasound . Sounds with frequencies above 20,000 hertz are called ultrasound . Some other animals can hear sounds in the ultrasound range. For example, dogs can hear sounds with frequencies as high as 50,000 Hz. You may have seen special whistles that dogs but not people can hear. The whistles produce a sound with a frequency too high for the human ear to detect. Other animals can hear even higher-frequency sounds. Bats, for example, can hear sounds with frequencies higher than 100,000 Hz.", "situation": "Mike saw his neighbors son playing with a whistle outside. Mike thought the whistle must be broken because the kid was blowing really hard but there was no sound coming out. The dog across the street was barking like crazy though.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the whistle making an infrasound or ultrasound?", "id": "596013240", "answers": [{"text": "ultrasound"}]}]}, {"background": "The frequency of sound waves is measured in hertz (Hz), or the number of waves that pass a fixed point in a second. Human beings can normally hear sounds with a frequency between about 20 Hz and 20,000 Hz. Sounds with frequencies below 20 hertz are called infrasound . Sounds with frequencies above 20,000 hertz are called ultrasound . Some other animals can hear sounds in the ultrasound range. For example, dogs can hear sounds with frequencies as high as 50,000 Hz. You may have seen special whistles that dogs but not people can hear. The whistles produce a sound with a frequency too high for the human ear to detect. Other animals can hear even higher-frequency sounds. Bats, for example, can hear sounds with frequencies higher than 100,000 Hz.", "situation": "Mike saw his neighbors son playing with a whistle outside. Mike thought the whistle must be broken because the kid was blowing really hard but there was no sound coming out. The dog across the street was barking like crazy though.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the whistle making a sound too high or too low for Mike to hear?", "id": "3137959343", "answers": [{"text": "too high"}]}]}, {"background": "Abrasion is another type of mechanical weathering. With abrasion, one rock bumps against another rock. Gravity causes abrasion as a rock tumbles down a slope. Moving water causes abrasion it moves rocks so that they bump against one another ( Figure below ). Strong winds cause abrasion by blasting sand against rock surfaces. Finally, the ice in glaciers cause abrasion. Pieces of rock embedded in ice at the bottom of a glacier scrape against the rock below. If you have ever collected beach glass or pebbles from a stream, you have witnessed the work of abrasion.", "situation": "John liked to walk by the creek near his house. His favorite thing about exploring the creek was looking for pebbles to add to his collection. John liked watching the water pass over the rocks. Sometimes the rocks rolled into each other.", "qas": [{"question": "Are johns pepples rough or smooth?", "id": "2481663855", "answers": [{"text": "smooth"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "The turkey was almost done cooking. Beth pulled it out of the oven to baste one last time. She picked up her turkey baster and squeezed the bulb . She the inserted the open stem end into the turkey broth while releasing the bulb and watched as the liquid was pulled inside. As she squeezing the bulb again the broth was pushed out of the opening and onto the turkey.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the volume of the baster increase or decrease when Beth squeezed the bulb?", "id": "566265942", "answers": [{"text": "decrease"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "The turkey was almost done cooking. Beth pulled it out of the oven to baste one last time. She picked up her turkey baster and squeezed the bulb . She the inserted the open stem end into the turkey broth while releasing the bulb and watched as the liquid was pulled inside. As she squeezing the bulb again the broth was pushed out of the opening and onto the turkey.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the volume of the baster increase or decrease when Beth relesed the bulb?", "id": "2536474580", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "The turkey was almost done cooking. Beth pulled it out of the oven to baste one last time. She picked up her turkey baster and squeezed the bulb . She the inserted the open stem end into the turkey broth while releasing the bulb and watched as the liquid was pulled inside. As she squeezing the bulb again the broth was pushed out of the opening and onto the turkey.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the air pressure of the baster increase or decrease when Beth squeezed the bulb the first time?", "id": "2826866699", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "The turkey was almost done cooking. Beth pulled it out of the oven to baste one last time. She picked up her turkey baster and squeezed the bulb . She the inserted the open stem end into the turkey broth while releasing the bulb and watched as the liquid was pulled inside. As she squeezing the bulb again the broth was pushed out of the opening and onto the turkey.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the air pressure inside and outside the baster equal before or after squeezing the bulb?", "id": "3652357627", "answers": [{"text": "before"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "The turkey was almost done cooking. Beth pulled it out of the oven to baste one last time. She picked up her turkey baster and squeezed the bulb . She the inserted the open stem end into the turkey broth while releasing the bulb and watched as the liquid was pulled inside. As she squeezing the bulb again the broth was pushed out of the opening and onto the turkey.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the air pressure inside and outside the baster unequal before or after squeezing the bulb?", "id": "4243492574", "answers": [{"text": "after"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "The turkey was almost done cooking. Beth pulled it out of the oven to baste one last time. She picked up her turkey baster and squeezed the bulb . She the inserted the open stem end into the turkey broth while releasing the bulb and watched as the liquid was pulled inside. As she squeezing the bulb again the broth was pushed out of the opening and onto the turkey.", "qas": [{"question": "When the bulb was released did the inside pressure increase or decrease", "id": "1980466756", "answers": [{"text": "decrease"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "The turkey was almost done cooking. Beth pulled it out of the oven to baste one last time. She picked up her turkey baster and squeezed the bulb . She the inserted the open stem end into the turkey broth while releasing the bulb and watched as the liquid was pulled inside. As she squeezing the bulb again the broth was pushed out of the opening and onto the turkey.", "qas": [{"question": "When the bulb was released did the inside volume increase or decrease", "id": "1728939363", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "The turkey was almost done cooking. Beth pulled it out of the oven to baste one last time. She picked up her turkey baster and squeezed the bulb . She the inserted the open stem end into the turkey broth while releasing the bulb and watched as the liquid was pulled inside. As she squeezing the bulb again the broth was pushed out of the opening and onto the turkey.", "qas": [{"question": "Where the air molecules closer together when the bulb was squeezed or not squeezed?", "id": "4103244537", "answers": [{"text": "squeezed"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "The turkey was almost done cooking. Beth pulled it out of the oven to baste one last time. She picked up her turkey baster and squeezed the bulb . She the inserted the open stem end into the turkey broth while releasing the bulb and watched as the liquid was pulled inside. As she squeezing the bulb again the broth was pushed out of the opening and onto the turkey.", "qas": [{"question": "Where the air molecules farther apart when the bulb was squeezed or not squeezed?", "id": "3613166099", "answers": [{"text": "not squeezed"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Mike wanted to know what would happen if he heated up an egg in the microwave. Mike place a whole egg shell and all in the microwave and turned it on. At first nothing seemed to be happening the egg was just going around on the turntable. Then suddenly after about 45 seconds the egg exploded. The shell cracked and yolk splattered every where. Sam could see steam coming of the egg so he waited a minute for it to cool down before he cleaned it up.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the kinetic energy higher or lower before heating the egg?", "id": "1322294981", "answers": [{"text": "lower"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Mike wanted to know what would happen if he heated up an egg in the microwave. Mike place a whole egg shell and all in the microwave and turned it on. At first nothing seemed to be happening the egg was just going around on the turntable. Then suddenly after about 45 seconds the egg exploded. The shell cracked and yolk splattered every where. Sam could see steam coming of the egg so he waited a minute for it to cool down before he cleaned it up.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the kinetic energy higher or lower while heating the egg?", "id": "2959122027", "answers": [{"text": "higher"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Mike wanted to know what would happen if he heated up an egg in the microwave. Mike place a whole egg shell and all in the microwave and turned it on. At first nothing seemed to be happening the egg was just going around on the turntable. Then suddenly after about 45 seconds the egg exploded. The shell cracked and yolk splattered every where. Sam could see steam coming of the egg so he waited a minute for it to cool down before he cleaned it up.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the pressure inside the egg higher or lower before heating the egg??", "id": "2543231548", "answers": [{"text": "lower"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Mike wanted to know what would happen if he heated up an egg in the microwave. Mike place a whole egg shell and all in the microwave and turned it on. At first nothing seemed to be happening the egg was just going around on the turntable. Then suddenly after about 45 seconds the egg exploded. The shell cracked and yolk splattered every where. Sam could see steam coming of the egg so he waited a minute for it to cool down before he cleaned it up.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the pressure inside the egg higher or lower while heating the egg??", "id": "4120158690", "answers": [{"text": "higher"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Mike wanted to know what would happen if he heated up an egg in the microwave. Mike place a whole egg shell and all in the microwave and turned it on. At first nothing seemed to be happening the egg was just going around on the turntable. Then suddenly after about 45 seconds the egg exploded. The shell cracked and yolk splattered every where. Sam could see steam coming of the egg so he waited a minute for it to cool down before he cleaned it up.", "qas": [{"question": "Where the molecules inside the egg moving faster or slower while heating the egg??", "id": "303932979", "answers": [{"text": "faster"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Mike wanted to know what would happen if he heated up an egg in the microwave. Mike place a whole egg shell and all in the microwave and turned it on. At first nothing seemed to be happening the egg was just going around on the turntable. Then suddenly after about 45 seconds the egg exploded. The shell cracked and yolk splattered every where. Sam could see steam coming of the egg so he waited a minute for it to cool down before he cleaned it up.", "qas": [{"question": "Where the molecules inside the egg moving faster or slower before heating the egg??", "id": "3093407373", "answers": [{"text": "slower"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Mike wanted to know what would happen if he heated up an egg in the microwave. Mike place a whole egg shell and all in the microwave and turned it on. At first nothing seemed to be happening the egg was just going around on the turntable. Then suddenly after about 45 seconds the egg exploded. The shell cracked and yolk splattered every where. Sam could see steam coming of the egg so he waited a minute for it to cool down before he cleaned it up.", "qas": [{"question": "Was gas pressure higher or lower before heating the egg??", "id": "1003068646", "answers": [{"text": "higher"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Mike wanted to know what would happen if he heated up an egg in the microwave. Mike place a whole egg shell and all in the microwave and turned it on. At first nothing seemed to be happening the egg was just going around on the turntable. Then suddenly after about 45 seconds the egg exploded. The shell cracked and yolk splattered every where. Sam could see steam coming of the egg so he waited a minute for it to cool down before he cleaned it up.", "qas": [{"question": "Was gas pressure higher or lower while heating the egg??", "id": "2669517964", "answers": [{"text": "lower"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Mike wanted to know what would happen if he heated up an egg in the microwave. Mike place a whole egg shell and all in the microwave and turned it on. At first nothing seemed to be happening the egg was just going around on the turntable. Then suddenly after about 45 seconds the egg exploded. The shell cracked and yolk splattered every where. Sam could see steam coming of the egg so he waited a minute for it to cool down before he cleaned it up.", "qas": [{"question": "Where molecules impacting the inside of the shell more ore less often before heating the egg??", "id": "13216381", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Mike wanted to know what would happen if he heated up an egg in the microwave. Mike place a whole egg shell and all in the microwave and turned it on. At first nothing seemed to be happening the egg was just going around on the turntable. Then suddenly after about 45 seconds the egg exploded. The shell cracked and yolk splattered every where. Sam could see steam coming of the egg so he waited a minute for it to cool down before he cleaned it up.", "qas": [{"question": "Where molecules impacting the inside of the shell more ore less often while heating the egg??", "id": "1451665955", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Beth grabbed her container of chili from he fridge and tossed in the microwave for 4 minutes. However, she forgot to vent the lid and after several minutes the dish exploded spraying chili all over the inside of the microwave.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the movement air molecules inside the dish increase or decrease?", "id": "2374390579", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Beth grabbed her container of chili from he fridge and tossed in the microwave for 4 minutes. However, she forgot to vent the lid and after several minutes the dish exploded spraying chili all over the inside of the microwave.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the kinetic energy of theair molecules inside the dish increase or decrease?", "id": "558585807", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Beth grabbed her container of chili from he fridge and tossed in the microwave for 4 minutes. However, she forgot to vent the lid and after several minutes the dish exploded spraying chili all over the inside of the microwave.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the liquid molecules speed up or slow down inside themolecules inside the dish increase or decrease?", "id": "3910033646", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Beth grabbed her container of chili from he fridge and tossed in the microwave for 4 minutes. However, she forgot to vent the lid and after several minutes the dish exploded spraying chili all over the inside of the microwave.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the liqued increase or decrease the pressure inside the dish??", "id": "3792261696", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Beth grabbed her container of chili from he fridge and tossed in the microwave for 4 minutes. However, she forgot to vent the lid and after several minutes the dish exploded spraying chili all over the inside of the microwave.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the amount of gas in the bowl increase or decrease?", "id": "1502629326", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Beth grabbed her container of chili from he fridge and tossed in the microwave for 4 minutes. However, she forgot to vent the lid and after several minutes the dish exploded spraying chili all over the inside of the microwave.", "qas": [{"question": "Did kinetic energy make molecules move faster or slower?", "id": "3276820231", "answers": [{"text": "faster"}]}]}, {"background": "It would be very unadvisable to place a can of soup over a campfire without venting the can. As the can heats up, it may explode. The kinetic-molecular theory explains why. The air inside the rigid can of soup is given more kinetic energy by the heat coming from the campfire. The kinetic energy causes the air molecules to move faster and they impact the container walls more frequently and with more force. The increase in pressure inside may eventually exceed the strength of the can and it will explode. An additional factor is that the soup may begin boiling which will then aid even more gas and more pressure to the inside of the can.", "situation": "Beth grabbed her container of chili from he fridge and tossed in the microwave for 4 minutes. However, she forgot to vent the lid and after several minutes the dish exploded spraying chili all over the inside of the microwave.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the kinetic energy of the liqued increase or decrease?", "id": "1400917833", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Beth was having a great time at the ski resort but after a day of skiing on the mountains but she head a headache now and was feeling light headed. Maybe she would feel better when they went to the village in the valley tomorrow.", "qas": [{"question": "was the air pressure higher on the mountain or in the valley?", "id": "2808115729", "answers": [{"text": "in the valley"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Beth was having a great time at the ski resort but after a day of skiing on the mountains but she head a headache now and was feeling light headed. Maybe she would feel better when they went to the village in the valley tomorrow.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the air pressure lower on the mountain or in the valley?", "id": "805597603", "answers": [{"text": "in the valley"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Beth was having a great time at the ski resort but after a day of skiing on the mountains but she head a headache now and was feeling light headed. Maybe she would feel better when they went to the village in the valley tomorrow.", "qas": [{"question": "Does the air pressure decrease more quickly on the mountain or in the valley?", "id": "4247681035", "answers": [{"text": "in the valley"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Beth was having a great time at the ski resort but after a day of skiing on the mountains but she head a headache now and was feeling light headed. Maybe she would feel better when they went to the village in the valley tomorrow.", "qas": [{"question": "Does the air pressure decrease slower on the mountain or in the valley?", "id": "832009682", "answers": [{"text": "on the mountain"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Beth was having a great time at the ski resort but after a day of skiing on the mountains but she head a headache now and was feeling light headed. Maybe she would feel better when they went to the village in the valley tomorrow.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the depth of the atmosphere higher on the mountain or in the valley?", "id": "474969456", "answers": [{"text": "in the valley"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Beth was having a great time at the ski resort but after a day of skiing on the mountains but she head a headache now and was feeling light headed. Maybe she would feel better when they went to the village in the valley tomorrow.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the depth of the atmosphere lower on the mountain or in the valley?", "id": "2835707170", "answers": [{"text": "on the mountain"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Beth was having a great time at the ski resort but after a day of skiing on the mountains but she head a headache now and was feeling light headed. Maybe she would feel better when they went to the village in the valley tomorrow.", "qas": [{"question": "Is easier to breath on the mountain or in the valley?", "id": "281571015", "answers": [{"text": "in the valley"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Beth was having a great time at the ski resort but after a day of skiing on the mountains but she head a headache now and was feeling light headed. Maybe she would feel better when they went to the village in the valley tomorrow.", "qas": [{"question": "Is harder to breath on the mountain or in the valley?", "id": "272854724", "answers": [{"text": "on the mountain"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Beth was having a great time at the ski resort but after a day of skiing on the mountains but she head a headache now and was feeling light headed. Maybe she would feel better when they went to the village in the valley tomorrow.", "qas": [{"question": "Is easier to get enough oxygen on the mountain or in the valley?", "id": "4058084081", "answers": [{"text": "in the valley"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Beth was having a great time at the ski resort but after a day of skiing on the mountains but she head a headache now and was feeling light headed. Maybe she would feel better when they went to the village in the valley tomorrow.", "qas": [{"question": "Is harder to get enough oxygen on the mountain or in the valley?", "id": "4047205102", "answers": [{"text": "on the mountain"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Mark had looked forward to climbing Mt. Denalit for years. Today he would complete the last leg and be on top op the mountain more than 20,000 miles above sea level. As the day went on Mark often had to slow down as he was getting light headed and tired.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the air pressure higher or lower when Mark started the last leg?", "id": "3028908856", "answers": [{"text": "higher"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Mark had looked forward to climbing Mt. Denalit for years. Today he would complete the last leg and be on top op the mountain more than 20,000 miles above sea level. As the day went on Mark often had to slow down as he was getting light headed and tired.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the air pressure higher or lower when Mark was at the base of the mountain?", "id": "206339825", "answers": [{"text": "higher"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Mark had looked forward to climbing Mt. Denalit for years. Today he would complete the last leg and be on top op the mountain more than 20,000 miles above sea level. As the day went on Mark often had to slow down as he was getting light headed and tired.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the air pressure higher or lower when Mark was at the sumit??", "id": "1058568678", "answers": [{"text": "lower"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Mark had looked forward to climbing Mt. Denalit for years. Today he would complete the last leg and be on top op the mountain more than 20,000 miles above sea level. As the day went on Mark often had to slow down as he was getting light headed and tired.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the air pressure increasing or decreasing as Mark climbed??", "id": "1450408317", "answers": [{"text": "decreasing"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Mat loved being outside and being physically active. So he took every opportunity to go mountain climbing. Last year he went on two climbs. The first A was challenging but lots of fun. On his second climb B he had some trouble though. Near the top of the mountain he was having trouble breathing he got very light headed and was not able to continue.", "qas": [{"question": "Which mountain is closest to sea level?", "id": "1328584128", "answers": [{"text": "A"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Mat loved being outside and being physically active. So he took every opportunity to go mountain climbing. Last year he went on two climbs. The first A was challenging but lots of fun. On his second climb B he had some trouble though. Near the top of the mountain he was having trouble breathing he got very light headed and was not able to continue.", "qas": [{"question": "Which mountain is highest from sea level?", "id": "2078512768", "answers": [{"text": "B"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Beth had been practicing for this climb for a long time. She had started out at the base a few days ago and would reach the summit before night.She had had to slow down as she moved up the mountain because she found it harder to breath but overall it had been a good experience.", "qas": [{"question": "is the air pressure higher or lower at the top of the mountain?", "id": "727483311", "answers": [{"text": "lower"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Beth had been practicing for this climb for a long time. She had started out at the base a few days ago and would reach the summit before night.She had had to slow down as she moved up the mountain because she found it harder to breath but overall it had been a good experience.", "qas": [{"question": "is the air pressure higher or lower at the base of the mountain?", "id": "2913764343", "answers": [{"text": "higher"}]}]}, {"background": "Like water in the ocean, air in the atmosphere exerts pressure that increases with depth. Most gas molecules in the atmosphere are pulled close to Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s surface by gravity. As a result, air pressure decreases quickly at lower altitudes and then more slowly at higher altitudes. This is illustrated in Figure below . Air pressure is greatest at sea level, where the depth of the atmosphere is greatest. At higher altitudes, the pressure is less because the depth of the atmosphere is less. For example, on top of Mount Everest, the tallest mountain on Earth, air pressure is only about one-third of the pressure at sea level. At such high altitudes, low air pressure makes it hard to breathe and is dangerous to human health.", "situation": "Beth had been practicing for this climb for a long time. She had started out at the base a few days ago and would reach the summit before night.She had had to slow down as she moved up the mountain because she found it harder to breath but overall it had been a good experience.", "qas": [{"question": "Does the depth of the atmosphere increase or decrease as Beth climbs the mountain?", "id": "832211621", "answers": [{"text": "decrease"}]}]}, {"background": "One possible answer is that helping others often means helping close relatives. Close relatives share many of the same genes that they inherited from their common ancestor. As a result, helping a close relative may actually increase the chances that copies of one\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s own genes will be passed to the next generation. In this way, a behavior that puts oneself at risk could actually increase through natural selection. This form of natural selection is called kin selection .", "situation": "Prairie dogs have an elaborate alarm system where some members of the group will bark out warnings when they see predators. The warnings alert other members of the group to take cover.", "qas": [{"question": "When a Prairie dogs gives a warning who directly benefits?", "id": "544933857", "answers": [{"text": "other members of the group"}]}]}, {"background": "One possible answer is that helping others often means helping close relatives. Close relatives share many of the same genes that they inherited from their common ancestor. As a result, helping a close relative may actually increase the chances that copies of one\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s own genes will be passed to the next generation. In this way, a behavior that puts oneself at risk could actually increase through natural selection. This form of natural selection is called kin selection .", "situation": "Prairie dogs have an elaborate alarm system where some members of the group will bark out warnings when they see predators. The warnings alert other members of the group to take cover.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the watchers related or unrelated to the rest of the group?", "id": "1527187879", "answers": [{"text": "related"}]}]}, {"background": "One possible answer is that helping others often means helping close relatives. Close relatives share many of the same genes that they inherited from their common ancestor. As a result, helping a close relative may actually increase the chances that copies of one\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s own genes will be passed to the next generation. In this way, a behavior that puts oneself at risk could actually increase through natural selection. This form of natural selection is called kin selection .", "situation": "Prairie dogs have an elaborate alarm system where some members of the group will bark out warnings when they see predators. The warnings alert other members of the group to take cover.", "qas": [{"question": "What are the watchers doing that is dangerous?", "id": "3842573206", "answers": [{"text": "warning"}]}]}, {"background": "One possible answer is that helping others often means helping close relatives. Close relatives share many of the same genes that they inherited from their common ancestor. As a result, helping a close relative may actually increase the chances that copies of one\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s own genes will be passed to the next generation. In this way, a behavior that puts oneself at risk could actually increase through natural selection. This form of natural selection is called kin selection .", "situation": "Prairie dogs have an elaborate alarm system where some members of the group will bark out warnings when they see predators. The warnings alert other members of the group to take cover.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the watchers passing on or not passing on their genes?", "id": "1022101600", "answers": [{"text": "passing on"}]}]}, {"background": "One possible answer is that helping others often means helping close relatives. Close relatives share many of the same genes that they inherited from their common ancestor. As a result, helping a close relative may actually increase the chances that copies of one\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s own genes will be passed to the next generation. In this way, a behavior that puts oneself at risk could actually increase through natural selection. This form of natural selection is called kin selection .", "situation": "Prairie dogs have an elaborate alarm system where some members of the group will bark out warnings when they see predators. The warnings alert other members of the group to take cover.", "qas": [{"question": "Are watchers looking out for themselves or the group?", "id": "377489020", "answers": [{"text": "group"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "The tree frogs range covers 2 different habitats, One has a lot of trees and the other a lot of tall green grass with few if any trees. Tree frogs can either be green or brown.", "qas": [{"question": "Which color tree frog has an advantage living in grass?", "id": "2994269464", "answers": [{"text": "green"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "The tree frogs range covers 2 different habitats, One has a lot of trees and the other a lot of tall green grass with few if any trees. Tree frogs can either be green or brown.", "qas": [{"question": "Which color tree frog has an advantage living in trees?", "id": "2997677339", "answers": [{"text": "brown"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "The tree frogs range covers 2 different habitats, One has a lot of trees and the other a lot of tall green grass with few if any trees. Tree frogs can either be green or brown.", "qas": [{"question": "Which color tree frog is easier for predators to spot on trees in trees?", "id": "2966614901", "answers": [{"text": "green"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "The tree frogs range covers 2 different habitats, One has a lot of trees and the other a lot of tall green grass with few if any trees. Tree frogs can either be green or brown.", "qas": [{"question": "Which color tree frog is easier for predators to spot on grass?", "id": "779022392", "answers": [{"text": "brown"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "The tree frogs range covers 2 different habitats, One has a lot of trees and the other a lot of tall green grass with few if any trees. Tree frogs can either be green or brown.", "qas": [{"question": "Where is being green an disadvantage?", "id": "1001645721", "answers": [{"text": "trees"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "The tree frogs range covers 2 different habitats, One has a lot of trees and the other a lot of tall green grass with few if any trees. Tree frogs can either be green or brown.", "qas": [{"question": "Where is being green an advantage?", "id": "2286478681", "answers": [{"text": "grass"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "The tree frogs range covers 2 different habitats, One has a lot of trees and the other a lot of tall green grass with few if any trees. Tree frogs can either be green or brown.", "qas": [{"question": "Where is being brown an advantage?", "id": "2310268272", "answers": [{"text": "trees"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "The tree frogs range covers 2 different habitats, One has a lot of trees and the other a lot of tall green grass with few if any trees. Tree frogs can either be green or brown.", "qas": [{"question": "Where is being brown an disadvantage?", "id": "1029957296", "answers": [{"text": "grass"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "The tree frogs range covers 2 different habitats, One has a lot of trees and the other a lot of tall green grass with few if any trees. Tree frogs can either be green or brown.", "qas": [{"question": "Where are brown tree frogs more common?", "id": "248768378", "answers": [{"text": "trees"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "The tree frogs range covers 2 different habitats, One has a lot of trees and the other a lot of tall green grass with few if any trees. Tree frogs can either be green or brown.", "qas": [{"question": "Where are green tree frogs more common?", "id": "209905507", "answers": [{"text": "grass"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "John liked to sit in his yard and watch the birds and other animals. He was often amused by the antics of the squirrels. He especially liked to watch out for White squirrels. Unlike the grey ones that blended into the trees. The white ones were easy to spot. Still he rarely saw them.", "qas": [{"question": "Are there more or fewer white squirells?", "id": "2628456322", "answers": [{"text": "fewer"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "John liked to sit in his yard and watch the birds and other animals. He was often amused by the antics of the squirrels. He especially liked to watch out for White squirrels. Unlike the grey ones that blended into the trees. The white ones were easy to spot. Still he rarely saw them.", "qas": [{"question": "Which squirell is well adapted to the environment?", "id": "1414730592", "answers": [{"text": "grey"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "John liked to sit in his yard and watch the birds and other animals. He was often amused by the antics of the squirrels. He especially liked to watch out for White squirrels. Unlike the grey ones that blended into the trees. The white ones were easy to spot. Still he rarely saw them.", "qas": [{"question": "Which squirell is poorlyadapted to the environment?", "id": "1957303345", "answers": [{"text": "white"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "John liked to sit in his yard and watch the birds and other animals. He was often amused by the antics of the squirrels. He especially liked to watch out for White squirrels. Unlike the grey ones that blended into the trees. The white ones were easy to spot. Still he rarely saw them.", "qas": [{"question": "Which squirell is reproduces more?", "id": "1379405199", "answers": [{"text": "grey"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "John liked to sit in his yard and watch the birds and other animals. He was often amused by the antics of the squirrels. He especially liked to watch out for White squirrels. Unlike the grey ones that blended into the trees. The white ones were easy to spot. Still he rarely saw them.", "qas": [{"question": "Which squirell is reproduces less?", "id": "1378487699", "answers": [{"text": "white"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "John liked to sit in his yard and watch the birds and other animals. He was often amused by the antics of the squirrels. He especially liked to watch out for White squirrels. Unlike the grey ones that blended into the trees. The white ones were easy to spot. Still he rarely saw them.", "qas": [{"question": "Which squirell a harmful trait?", "id": "660737080", "answers": [{"text": "white"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "John liked to sit in his yard and watch the birds and other animals. He was often amused by the antics of the squirrels. He especially liked to watch out for White squirrels. Unlike the grey ones that blended into the trees. The white ones were easy to spot. Still he rarely saw them.", "qas": [{"question": "Which squirell a helpful trait?", "id": "661589049", "answers": [{"text": "grey"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "John liked to sit in his yard and watch the birds and other animals. He was often amused by the antics of the squirrels. He especially liked to watch out for White squirrels. Unlike the grey ones that blended into the trees. The white ones were easy to spot. Still he rarely saw them.", "qas": [{"question": "Which squirell will increase in numbers?", "id": "2852523961", "answers": [{"text": "grey"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "John liked to sit in his yard and watch the birds and other animals. He was often amused by the antics of the squirrels. He especially liked to watch out for White squirrels. Unlike the grey ones that blended into the trees. The white ones were easy to spot. Still he rarely saw them.", "qas": [{"question": "Which squirell will decrease in numbers?", "id": "2834763691", "answers": [{"text": "white"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "The peppered moth used to be a light color with black spots. Occasionally some darker moths were born but they did not blend in well with the trees. When the atmosphere in London became filled with soot because of the Industrial Revolution, the white trees became darker and light colored moths became easier to see on the dark trees. After the Industrial Revolution the trees returned to their original color and light colored moths once again blended in with the trees.", "qas": [{"question": "Which moth had a disadvantage during the Industrial Revolution?", "id": "526605859", "answers": [{"text": "light colored moths"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "There are two kinds of tree frogs each is a different color. Grey tree frogs and green tree. Grey tree frogs live in wooded areas and are difficult to see when on tree trunks. Green tree frogs live in wetlands with lots of grass and tall plants. They blend in very well with the green plants and grass.", "qas": [{"question": "What trait helps the grey tree frog blend into its environment?", "id": "1274158763", "answers": [{"text": "color"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "There are two kinds of tree frogs each is a different color. Grey tree frogs and green tree. Grey tree frogs live in wooded areas and are difficult to see when on tree trunks. Green tree frogs live in wetlands with lots of grass and tall plants. They blend in very well with the green plants and grass.", "qas": [{"question": "What trait helps the green tree frog blend into its environment?", "id": "1780358917", "answers": [{"text": "color"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "There are two kinds of tree frogs each is a different color. Grey tree frogs and green tree. Grey tree frogs live in wooded areas and are difficult to see when on tree trunks. Green tree frogs live in wetlands with lots of grass and tall plants. They blend in very well with the green plants and grass.", "qas": [{"question": "What habititat is the grey tree frog adapted to?", "id": "2847021235", "answers": [{"text": "wooded areas"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "There are two kinds of tree frogs each is a different color. Grey tree frogs and green tree. Grey tree frogs live in wooded areas and are difficult to see when on tree trunks. Green tree frogs live in wetlands with lots of grass and tall plants. They blend in very well with the green plants and grass.", "qas": [{"question": "Which habitat has more grey tree frogs?", "id": "3600291204", "answers": [{"text": "wooded areas"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "There are two kinds of tree frogs each is a different color. Grey tree frogs and green tree. Grey tree frogs live in wooded areas and are difficult to see when on tree trunks. Green tree frogs live in wetlands with lots of grass and tall plants. They blend in very well with the green plants and grass.", "qas": [{"question": "Which habitat has fewer green tree frogs?", "id": "51910212", "answers": [{"text": "wooded areas"}]}]}, {"background": "The theory of evolution by natural selection was proposed at about the same time by both Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace, shown in Figure below , and was set out in detail in Darwin's 1859 book On the Origin of Species . Natural selection is a process that causes heritable traits that are helpful for survival and reproduction to become more common, and harmful traits, or traits that are not helpful or advantageous for survival to become more rare in a population of organisms. This occurs because organisms with advantageous traits are more \"fit\" to survive in a particular environment and have \"adapted\" to the conditions of that environment. These individuals will have greater reproductive success than organisms less fit for survival in the environment. This will lead to an increase in the number of organisms with the advantageous trait(s) over time. Over many generations, adaptations occur through a combination of successive, small, random changes in traits, and natural selection of those variants best-suited for their environment. Natural selection is one of the cornerstones of modern biology.", "situation": "There are two kinds of tree frogs each is a different color. Grey tree frogs and green tree. Grey tree frogs live in wooded areas and are difficult to see when on tree trunks. Green tree frogs live in wetlands with lots of grass and tall plants. They blend in very well with the green plants and grass.", "qas": [{"question": "Where are green tree frogs more susptable o predators?", "id": "1212029787", "answers": [{"text": "wooded areas"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "During a particularly bad infestation of caterpillars Mark sprayed his orchards with pesticide. That year most of the caterpillars died. The next year the pesticide also seemed to be effective but as the years passed more and more caterpillars seemed to be surviving until Mark had no choice but to find a new and stronger pesticide.", "qas": [{"question": "What were the caterpillars adapting to?", "id": "2178826168", "answers": [{"text": "pesticide"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "During a particularly bad infestation of caterpillars Mark sprayed his orchards with pesticide. That year most of the caterpillars died. The next year the pesticide also seemed to be effective but as the years passed more and more caterpillars seemed to be surviving until Mark had no choice but to find a new and stronger pesticide.", "qas": [{"question": "The first year were most of the caterpillars susceptibal or immune to the pesticide? ?", "id": "3496104147", "answers": [{"text": "susceptibal"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "During a particularly bad infestation of caterpillars Mark sprayed his orchards with pesticide. That year most of the caterpillars died. The next year the pesticide also seemed to be effective but as the years passed more and more caterpillars seemed to be surviving until Mark had no choice but to find a new and stronger pesticide.", "qas": [{"question": "The second year were most of the caterpillars susceptibal or immune to the pesticide? ?", "id": "512250151", "answers": [{"text": "susceptibal"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "During a particularly bad infestation of caterpillars Mark sprayed his orchards with pesticide. That year most of the caterpillars died. The next year the pesticide also seemed to be effective but as the years passed more and more caterpillars seemed to be surviving until Mark had no choice but to find a new and stronger pesticide.", "qas": [{"question": "Were catipillars born after the first year more or less likely to be immune to the pesticide?", "id": "219697999", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "During a particularly bad infestation of caterpillars Mark sprayed his orchards with pesticide. That year most of the caterpillars died. The next year the pesticide also seemed to be effective but as the years passed more and more caterpillars seemed to be surviving until Mark had no choice but to find a new and stronger pesticide.", "qas": [{"question": "Were catipillars born after the first year more or less likely to be susceptibal to the pesticide?", "id": "3108787555", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "Bob's family had been farming this land for 3 generations but he was finding that he had to use much more pesticide to keep destructive insects from destroying his crops.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the pesticide weaker than in the past or less effective?", "id": "1919027877", "answers": [{"text": "less effective"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "Bob's family had been farming this land for 3 generations but he was finding that he had to use much more pesticide to keep destructive insects from destroying his crops.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the insects changing or staying the same?", "id": "58525091", "answers": [{"text": "changing"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "Bob's family had been farming this land for 3 generations but he was finding that he had to use much more pesticide to keep destructive insects from destroying his crops.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the initial pesticide kill all the insects or only some?", "id": "2162887447", "answers": [{"text": "some"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "Bob's family had been farming this land for 3 generations but he was finding that he had to use much more pesticide to keep destructive insects from destroying his crops.", "qas": [{"question": "Were some or none of the insects recistant to the earlier pesticide ?", "id": "4118023777", "answers": [{"text": "some"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "Bob's family had been farming this land for 3 generations but he was finding that he had to use much more pesticide to keep destructive insects from destroying his crops.", "qas": [{"question": "Are more insects resistant to now or in the past?", "id": "575735572", "answers": [{"text": "now"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "Bob's family had been farming this land for 3 generations but he was finding that he had to use much more pesticide to keep destructive insects from destroying his crops.", "qas": [{"question": "Were fewer insects resistant to the pesticide in the past or now?", "id": "3566472496", "answers": [{"text": "the past"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "Bob's family had been farming this land for 3 generations but he was finding that he had to use much more pesticide to keep destructive insects from destroying his crops.", "qas": [{"question": "Will more or less insects be resistant to the pesticide in the future??", "id": "476516155", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "Bob's family had been farming this land for 3 generations but he was finding that he had to use much more pesticide to keep destructive insects from destroying his crops.", "qas": [{"question": "Did resistant or nonresistent insects pass on their genes?", "id": "2296646433", "answers": [{"text": "resistant"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "Bob's family had been farming this land for 3 generations but he was finding that he had to use much more pesticide to keep destructive insects from destroying his crops.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the resistant or nonresistent incects more common now?", "id": "2191330087", "answers": [{"text": "resistant"}]}]}, {"background": "While the Grants were on the Gal\u00c3\u00a1pagos, a drought occurred. As a result, fewer seeds were available for finches to eat. Birds with smaller beaks could crack open and eat only the smaller seeds. Birds with bigger beaks could crack and eat seeds of all sizes. As a result, many of the small-beaked birds died in the drought. Birds with bigger beaks survived and reproduced (see Figure below ). Within 2 years, the average beak size in the finch population increased. Evolution by natural selection had occurred.", "situation": "Bob's family had been farming this land for 3 generations but he was finding that he had to use much more pesticide to keep destructive insects from destroying his crops.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the resistant or nonresistant incects less common now?", "id": "2185956135", "answers": [{"text": "nonresistant"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Mark had always wanted to go on a safari now that he was here he was amazed at thehuge herds of animals on the African Savannah but there is only grass to feed them part of the year and there are predators that hunt them for food.", "qas": [{"question": "food alimiting or non limiting factor for herd sized?", "id": "4271203816", "answers": [{"text": "limiting"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Mark had always wanted to go on a safari now that he was here he was amazed at thehuge herds of animals on the African Savannah but there is only grass to feed them part of the year and there are predators that hunt them for food.", "qas": [{"question": "Do predators increase or decrease herd sizes?", "id": "3578684144", "answers": [{"text": "decrease"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Mark had always wanted to go on a safari now that he was here he was amazed at thehuge herds of animals on the African Savannah but there is only grass to feed them part of the year and there are predators that hunt them for food.", "qas": [{"question": "Do larger herds increase or decrease predator populations??", "id": "1616144476", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Mark had always wanted to go on a safari now that he was here he was amazed at thehuge herds of animals on the African Savannah but there is only grass to feed them part of the year and there are predators that hunt them for food.", "qas": [{"question": "Do smaller predator populationsincrease or decrease herd sizes ?", "id": "1375431339", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Mark had always wanted to go on a safari now that he was here he was amazed at thehuge herds of animals on the African Savannah but there is only grass to feed them part of the year and there are predators that hunt them for food.", "qas": [{"question": "Do larger predator populationsincrease or decrease herd sizes ?", "id": "3801967160", "answers": [{"text": "decrease"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Mark had always wanted to go on a safari now that he was here he was amazed at thehuge herds of animals on the African Savannah but there is only grass to feed them part of the year and there are predators that hunt them for food.", "qas": [{"question": "If lions become extinct will herds increase or decrease?", "id": "661808868", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Mark had always wanted to go on a safari now that he was here he was amazed at thehuge herds of animals on the African Savannah but there is only grass to feed them part of the year and there are predators that hunt them for food.", "qas": [{"question": "Will larger herds eat more or less grass?", "id": "1161650465", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Mark had always wanted to go on a safari now that he was here he was amazed at thehuge herds of animals on the African Savannah but there is only grass to feed them part of the year and there are predators that hunt them for food.", "qas": [{"question": "Do predators limitherds or have no effect?", "id": "1746821628", "answers": [{"text": "limit"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Wolves, elk and deer lived in Yellowstone National Park. While wolves lived there the elk and deer population was stable. When wolves became extinct in the area the elk and deer population exploded. Soon the forest showed signs of being damaged by the grazing Elk and deer.", "qas": [{"question": "What was a limiting factor on the deer and elk population?", "id": "3556538193", "answers": [{"text": "wolves"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Wolves, elk and deer lived in Yellowstone National Park. While wolves lived there the elk and deer population was stable. When wolves became extinct in the area the elk and deer population exploded. Soon the forest showed signs of being damaged by the grazing Elk and deer.", "qas": [{"question": "When was the deer and elk population at capacity?", "id": "2960094232", "answers": [{"text": "While wolves lived there"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Wolves, elk and deer lived in Yellowstone National Park. While wolves lived there the elk and deer population was stable. When wolves became extinct in the area the elk and deer population exploded. Soon the forest showed signs of being damaged by the grazing Elk and deer.", "qas": [{"question": "When was the deer and elk population above capacity?", "id": "273970512", "answers": [{"text": "When wolves became extinct"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Wolves, elk and deer lived in Yellowstone National Park. While wolves lived there the elk and deer population was stable. When wolves became extinct in the area the elk and deer population exploded. Soon the forest showed signs of being damaged by the grazing Elk and deer.", "qas": [{"question": "Would bringing wolves back decrease or increase the deer and elk population??", "id": "380010154", "answers": [{"text": "decrease"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Wolves, elk and deer lived in Yellowstone National Park. While wolves lived there the elk and deer population was stable. When wolves became extinct in the area the elk and deer population exploded. Soon the forest showed signs of being damaged by the grazing Elk and deer.", "qas": [{"question": "What population is growing un checked?", "id": "3666964607", "answers": [{"text": "elk and deer"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Wolves, elk and deer lived in Yellowstone National Park. While wolves lived there the elk and deer population was stable. When wolves became extinct in the area the elk and deer population exploded. Soon the forest showed signs of being damaged by the grazing Elk and deer.", "qas": [{"question": "What population is growing exponentially?", "id": "873951809", "answers": [{"text": "elk and deer"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Wolves, elk and deer lived in Yellowstone National Park. While wolves lived there the elk and deer population was stable. When wolves became extinct in the area the elk and deer population exploded. Soon the forest showed signs of being damaged by the grazing Elk and deer.", "qas": [{"question": "#NAME?", "id": "649493263", "answers": [{"text": "wolves"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Wolves, elk and deer lived in Yellowstone National Park. While wolves lived there the elk and deer population was stable. When wolves became extinct in the area the elk and deer population exploded. Soon the forest showed signs of being damaged by the grazing Elk and deer.", "qas": [{"question": "What would make the growth rate of the deer population stop growing??", "id": "500595653", "answers": [{"text": "wolves"}]}]}, {"background": "When organisms face limiting factors, they show logistic growth (S-shaped curve, curve B: Figure below ). Competition for resources like food and space cause the growth rate to stop increasing, so the population levels off. This flat upper line on a growth curve is the carrying capacity. The carrying capacity (K) is the maximum population size that can be supported in a particular area without destroying the habitat. Limiting factors determine the carrying capacity of a population. Recall that when there are no limiting factors, the population grows exponentially. In exponential growth (J-shaped curve, curve A: Figure below ), as the population size increases, the growth rate also increases.", "situation": "Wolves, elk and deer lived in Yellowstone National Park. While wolves lived there the elk and deer population was stable. When wolves became extinct in the area the elk and deer population exploded. Soon the forest showed signs of being damaged by the grazing Elk and deer.", "qas": [{"question": "What would make the growth rate of the elk population stop growing??", "id": "2715646817", "answers": [{"text": "wolves"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Jane enjoyed sitting on her porch in the morning enjoying the cool air. However by afternoon she was uncomfortable outside. The temperature had reason 15 degrees so she went inside were it was air conditioned and much cooler.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the kinetic energy of the outside air higher in the morning or afternoon?", "id": "3785633274", "answers": [{"text": "afternoon"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Jane enjoyed sitting on her porch in the morning enjoying the cool air. However by afternoon she was uncomfortable outside. The temperature had reason 15 degrees so she went inside were it was air conditioned and much cooler.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the kinetic energy of the outside air lower in the morning or afternoon?", "id": "3050646956", "answers": [{"text": "morning"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Jane enjoyed sitting on her porch in the morning enjoying the cool air. However by afternoon she was uncomfortable outside. The temperature had reason 15 degrees so she went inside were it was air conditioned and much cooler.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the kinetic energy of the inside air lower with or without air conditioning?", "id": "1893936990", "answers": [{"text": "with"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Jane enjoyed sitting on her porch in the morning enjoying the cool air. However by afternoon she was uncomfortable outside. The temperature had reason 15 degrees so she went inside were it was air conditioned and much cooler.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the kinetic energy of the inside air higher with or without air conditioning?", "id": "2646028204", "answers": [{"text": "without"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Jane enjoyed sitting on her porch in the morning enjoying the cool air. However by afternoon she was uncomfortable outside. The temperature had reason 15 degrees so she went inside were it was air conditioned and much cooler.", "qas": [{"question": "was the kinetic energy of the air increasing or decreasing as the day went on?", "id": "388836878", "answers": [{"text": "increasing"}]}]}, {"background": "In exercises such as weight lifting, skeletal muscle contracts against a resisting force (see Figure below ). Using skeletal muscle in this way increases its size and strength. In exercises such as running, the cardiac muscle contracts faster and the heart pumps more blood. Using cardiac muscle in this way increases its strength and efficiency. Continued exercise is necessary to maintain bigger, stronger muscles. If you don\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use a muscle, it will get smaller and weaker\u00e2\u20ac\u201dso use it or lose it.", "situation": "Jane decided to get in shape for the summer. She went to the gym and started jogging on the treadmill everyday. She also lifted weights a couple days a week.", "qas": [{"question": "are janes muscles getting more or less efficent?", "id": "3312583284", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "In exercises such as weight lifting, skeletal muscle contracts against a resisting force (see Figure below ). Using skeletal muscle in this way increases its size and strength. In exercises such as running, the cardiac muscle contracts faster and the heart pumps more blood. Using cardiac muscle in this way increases its strength and efficiency. Continued exercise is necessary to maintain bigger, stronger muscles. If you don\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use a muscle, it will get smaller and weaker\u00e2\u20ac\u201dso use it or lose it.", "situation": "Jane decided to get in shape for the summer. She went to the gym and started jogging on the treadmill everyday. She also lifted weights a couple days a week.", "qas": [{"question": "Is jane's heart getting stronger or weaker?", "id": "2956787804", "answers": [{"text": "stronger"}]}]}, {"background": "In exercises such as weight lifting, skeletal muscle contracts against a resisting force (see Figure below ). Using skeletal muscle in this way increases its size and strength. In exercises such as running, the cardiac muscle contracts faster and the heart pumps more blood. Using cardiac muscle in this way increases its strength and efficiency. Continued exercise is necessary to maintain bigger, stronger muscles. If you don\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use a muscle, it will get smaller and weaker\u00e2\u20ac\u201dso use it or lose it.", "situation": "Jane decided to get in shape for the summer. She went to the gym and started jogging on the treadmill everyday. She also lifted weights a couple days a week.", "qas": [{"question": "Is janes body able to pump more or less blood?", "id": "2881487101", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "In exercises such as weight lifting, skeletal muscle contracts against a resisting force (see Figure below ). Using skeletal muscle in this way increases its size and strength. In exercises such as running, the cardiac muscle contracts faster and the heart pumps more blood. Using cardiac muscle in this way increases its strength and efficiency. Continued exercise is necessary to maintain bigger, stronger muscles. If you don\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use a muscle, it will get smaller and weaker\u00e2\u20ac\u201dso use it or lose it.", "situation": "Ann loves running. She ran five miles every day until she broke her leg. After that she had to wear a cast for 2 months . When the cast was removed Ann tried to walk and realized that she could not.", "qas": [{"question": "Where Ann's cardiac muscles getting weaker or stronger when she was running?", "id": "3987872294", "answers": [{"text": "stronger"}]}]}, {"background": "In exercises such as weight lifting, skeletal muscle contracts against a resisting force (see Figure below ). Using skeletal muscle in this way increases its size and strength. In exercises such as running, the cardiac muscle contracts faster and the heart pumps more blood. Using cardiac muscle in this way increases its strength and efficiency. Continued exercise is necessary to maintain bigger, stronger muscles. If you don\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use a muscle, it will get smaller and weaker\u00e2\u20ac\u201dso use it or lose it.", "situation": "Ann loves running. She ran five miles every day until she broke her leg. After that she had to wear a cast for 2 months . When the cast was removed Ann tried to walk and realized that she could not.", "qas": [{"question": "Where Ann's cardiac muscles getting weaker or stronger when she was not able to run?", "id": "3338738850", "answers": [{"text": "weaker"}]}]}, {"background": "In exercises such as weight lifting, skeletal muscle contracts against a resisting force (see Figure below ). Using skeletal muscle in this way increases its size and strength. In exercises such as running, the cardiac muscle contracts faster and the heart pumps more blood. Using cardiac muscle in this way increases its strength and efficiency. Continued exercise is necessary to maintain bigger, stronger muscles. If you don\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use a muscle, it will get smaller and weaker\u00e2\u20ac\u201dso use it or lose it.", "situation": "Ann loves running. She ran five miles every day until she broke her leg. After that she had to wear a cast for 2 months . When the cast was removed Ann tried to walk and realized that she could not.", "qas": [{"question": "Were Ann's leg muscles getting weaker or stronger when she was running?", "id": "1760434223", "answers": [{"text": "stronger"}]}]}, {"background": "In exercises such as weight lifting, skeletal muscle contracts against a resisting force (see Figure below ). Using skeletal muscle in this way increases its size and strength. In exercises such as running, the cardiac muscle contracts faster and the heart pumps more blood. Using cardiac muscle in this way increases its strength and efficiency. Continued exercise is necessary to maintain bigger, stronger muscles. If you don\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use a muscle, it will get smaller and weaker\u00e2\u20ac\u201dso use it or lose it.", "situation": "Ann loves running. She ran five miles every day until she broke her leg. After that she had to wear a cast for 2 months . When the cast was removed Ann tried to walk and realized that she could not.", "qas": [{"question": "Were Ann's leg muscles getting weaker or stronger when she was not able to running?", "id": "2719423575", "answers": [{"text": "weaker"}]}]}, {"background": "In exercises such as weight lifting, skeletal muscle contracts against a resisting force (see Figure below ). Using skeletal muscle in this way increases its size and strength. In exercises such as running, the cardiac muscle contracts faster and the heart pumps more blood. Using cardiac muscle in this way increases its strength and efficiency. Continued exercise is necessary to maintain bigger, stronger muscles. If you don\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use a muscle, it will get smaller and weaker\u00e2\u20ac\u201dso use it or lose it.", "situation": "Ann loves running. She ran five miles every day until she broke her leg. After that she had to wear a cast for 2 months . When the cast was removed Ann tried to walk and realized that she could not.", "qas": [{"question": "Where Ann's cardiac muscles more efficent before or after she broke her leg?", "id": "3750893929", "answers": [{"text": "before"}]}]}, {"background": "In exercises such as weight lifting, skeletal muscle contracts against a resisting force (see Figure below ). Using skeletal muscle in this way increases its size and strength. In exercises such as running, the cardiac muscle contracts faster and the heart pumps more blood. Using cardiac muscle in this way increases its strength and efficiency. Continued exercise is necessary to maintain bigger, stronger muscles. If you don\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use a muscle, it will get smaller and weaker\u00e2\u20ac\u201dso use it or lose it.", "situation": "Ann loves running. She ran five miles every day until she broke her leg. After that she had to wear a cast for 2 months . When the cast was removed Ann tried to walk and realized that she could not.", "qas": [{"question": "Where Ann's leg muscles bigger before or after she broke her leg?", "id": "3510506803", "answers": [{"text": "before"}]}]}, {"background": "In exercises such as weight lifting, skeletal muscle contracts against a resisting force (see Figure below ). Using skeletal muscle in this way increases its size and strength. In exercises such as running, the cardiac muscle contracts faster and the heart pumps more blood. Using cardiac muscle in this way increases its strength and efficiency. Continued exercise is necessary to maintain bigger, stronger muscles. If you don\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use a muscle, it will get smaller and weaker\u00e2\u20ac\u201dso use it or lose it.", "situation": "Ann loves running. She ran five miles every day until she broke her leg. After that she had to wear a cast for 2 months . When the cast was removed Ann tried to walk and realized that she could not.", "qas": [{"question": "Where Ann's leg muscles smaller before or after she broke her leg?", "id": "3969127859", "answers": [{"text": "after"}]}]}, {"background": "In exercises such as weight lifting, skeletal muscle contracts against a resisting force (see Figure below ). Using skeletal muscle in this way increases its size and strength. In exercises such as running, the cardiac muscle contracts faster and the heart pumps more blood. Using cardiac muscle in this way increases its strength and efficiency. Continued exercise is necessary to maintain bigger, stronger muscles. If you don\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use a muscle, it will get smaller and weaker\u00e2\u20ac\u201dso use it or lose it.", "situation": "Ann loves running. She ran five miles every day until she broke her leg. After that she had to wear a cast for 2 months . When the cast was removed Ann tried to walk and realized that she could not.", "qas": [{"question": "Where Ann's leg muscles weaker before or after she broke her leg?", "id": "3551073602", "answers": [{"text": "after"}]}]}, {"background": "In exercises such as weight lifting, skeletal muscle contracts against a resisting force (see Figure below ). Using skeletal muscle in this way increases its size and strength. In exercises such as running, the cardiac muscle contracts faster and the heart pumps more blood. Using cardiac muscle in this way increases its strength and efficiency. Continued exercise is necessary to maintain bigger, stronger muscles. If you don\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use a muscle, it will get smaller and weaker\u00e2\u20ac\u201dso use it or lose it.", "situation": "Ann loves running. She ran five miles every day until she broke her leg. After that she had to wear a cast for 2 months . When the cast was removed Ann tried to walk and realized that she could not.", "qas": [{"question": "If an walks everyday will her leg muscles gat stronger or weaker?", "id": "3768391153", "answers": [{"text": "stronger"}]}]}, {"background": "In exercises such as weight lifting, skeletal muscle contracts against a resisting force (see Figure below ). Using skeletal muscle in this way increases its size and strength. In exercises such as running, the cardiac muscle contracts faster and the heart pumps more blood. Using cardiac muscle in this way increases its strength and efficiency. Continued exercise is necessary to maintain bigger, stronger muscles. If you don\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use a muscle, it will get smaller and weaker\u00e2\u20ac\u201dso use it or lose it.", "situation": "Ann loves running. She ran five miles every day until she broke her leg. After that she had to wear a cast for 2 months . When the cast was removed Ann tried to walk and realized that she could not.", "qas": [{"question": "If an doesn't walk will her leg muscles gat stronger or weaker?", "id": "2693731529", "answers": [{"text": "weaker"}]}]}, {"background": "The Hawaiian Islands ( Figure above ) are in the central Pacific Ocean. The islands are volcanoes that increase in age from southeast to northwest. The youngest island is the Big Island of Hawaii at the southeast end of the chain. The volcanoes get older through Maui, Kahoolawe, Lanai, Molokai, Oahu, Kauai, and Niihau Islands through the northwest. The Kilauea volcano on Hawaii has been erupting almost continuously since 1983. There are also eruptions at an underwater volcano called Loihi seamount. Loihi is the youngest volcano. Hawaii is a fantastic place to see volcanic eruptions and features.", "situation": "Mark wanted to see the Hawaiian Islands islands in the order that they had formed. In 1990 he visited all the island and saw each volcano including the one on Kilauea. The only thing Mark did not do was go diving?", "qas": [{"question": "Was Mark traveling west or east?", "id": "801582696", "answers": [{"text": "west"}]}]}, {"background": "The Hawaiian Islands ( Figure above ) are in the central Pacific Ocean. The islands are volcanoes that increase in age from southeast to northwest. The youngest island is the Big Island of Hawaii at the southeast end of the chain. The volcanoes get older through Maui, Kahoolawe, Lanai, Molokai, Oahu, Kauai, and Niihau Islands through the northwest. The Kilauea volcano on Hawaii has been erupting almost continuously since 1983. There are also eruptions at an underwater volcano called Loihi seamount. Loihi is the youngest volcano. Hawaii is a fantastic place to see volcanic eruptions and features.", "situation": "Mark wanted to see the Hawaiian Islands islands in the order that they had formed. In 1990 he visited all the island and saw each volcano including the one on Kilauea. The only thing Mark did not do was go diving?", "qas": [{"question": "Did Mark see the volcanos from youngest to oldest or oldest to youngest?", "id": "2515484001", "answers": [{"text": "oldest to youngest"}]}]}, {"background": "The Hawaiian Islands ( Figure above ) are in the central Pacific Ocean. The islands are volcanoes that increase in age from southeast to northwest. The youngest island is the Big Island of Hawaii at the southeast end of the chain. The volcanoes get older through Maui, Kahoolawe, Lanai, Molokai, Oahu, Kauai, and Niihau Islands through the northwest. The Kilauea volcano on Hawaii has been erupting almost continuously since 1983. There are also eruptions at an underwater volcano called Loihi seamount. Loihi is the youngest volcano. Hawaii is a fantastic place to see volcanic eruptions and features.", "situation": "Mark wanted to see the Hawaiian Islands islands in the order that they had formed. In 1990 he visited all the island and saw each volcano including the one on Kilauea. The only thing Mark did not do was go diving?", "qas": [{"question": "Was Kilauea active or dormant when Mark saw it?", "id": "260912019", "answers": [{"text": "active"}]}]}, {"background": "The Hawaiian Islands ( Figure above ) are in the central Pacific Ocean. The islands are volcanoes that increase in age from southeast to northwest. The youngest island is the Big Island of Hawaii at the southeast end of the chain. The volcanoes get older through Maui, Kahoolawe, Lanai, Molokai, Oahu, Kauai, and Niihau Islands through the northwest. The Kilauea volcano on Hawaii has been erupting almost continuously since 1983. There are also eruptions at an underwater volcano called Loihi seamount. Loihi is the youngest volcano. Hawaii is a fantastic place to see volcanic eruptions and features.", "situation": "Mark wanted to see the Hawaiian Islands islands in the order that they had formed. In 1990 he visited all the island and saw each volcano including the one on Kilauea. The only thing Mark did not do was go diving?", "qas": [{"question": "Did Mark see all the youngest volcano or not?", "id": "2668901098", "answers": [{"text": "not"}]}]}, {"background": "The Hawaiian Islands ( Figure above ) are in the central Pacific Ocean. The islands are volcanoes that increase in age from southeast to northwest. The youngest island is the Big Island of Hawaii at the southeast end of the chain. The volcanoes get older through Maui, Kahoolawe, Lanai, Molokai, Oahu, Kauai, and Niihau Islands through the northwest. The Kilauea volcano on Hawaii has been erupting almost continuously since 1983. There are also eruptions at an underwater volcano called Loihi seamount. Loihi is the youngest volcano. Hawaii is a fantastic place to see volcanic eruptions and features.", "situation": "Mark wanted to see the Hawaiian Islands islands in the order that they had formed. In 1990 he visited all the island and saw each volcano including the one on Kilauea. The only thing Mark did not do was go diving?", "qas": [{"question": "Are the islands still geologically active or dormant?", "id": "1531328145", "answers": [{"text": "active"}]}]}, {"background": "The Hawaiian Islands ( Figure above ) are in the central Pacific Ocean. The islands are volcanoes that increase in age from southeast to northwest. The youngest island is the Big Island of Hawaii at the southeast end of the chain. The volcanoes get older through Maui, Kahoolawe, Lanai, Molokai, Oahu, Kauai, and Niihau Islands through the northwest. The Kilauea volcano on Hawaii has been erupting almost continuously since 1983. There are also eruptions at an underwater volcano called Loihi seamount. Loihi is the youngest volcano. Hawaii is a fantastic place to see volcanic eruptions and features.", "situation": "Mark wanted to see the Hawaiian Islands islands in the order that they had formed. In 1990 he visited all the island and saw each volcano including the one on Kilauea. The only thing Mark did not do was go diving?", "qas": [{"question": "Are the islands still growing or have thay stopped?", "id": "3920573851", "answers": [{"text": "growing"}]}]}, {"background": "The Hawaiian Islands ( Figure above ) are in the central Pacific Ocean. The islands are volcanoes that increase in age from southeast to northwest. The youngest island is the Big Island of Hawaii at the southeast end of the chain. The volcanoes get older through Maui, Kahoolawe, Lanai, Molokai, Oahu, Kauai, and Niihau Islands through the northwest. The Kilauea volcano on Hawaii has been erupting almost continuously since 1983. There are also eruptions at an underwater volcano called Loihi seamount. Loihi is the youngest volcano. Hawaii is a fantastic place to see volcanic eruptions and features.", "situation": "Dave recently went on vacation to the Hawaiian Islands. He started his vacation on The youngest island and ended it on the oldest island. Dave especially liked seeing the Kilauea volcano. One of the tour guides told him about the Loihi volcano which erupts under water.", "qas": [{"question": "Was Dave traveling through the islands from east to west or west to east?", "id": "3341702207", "answers": [{"text": "east to west"}]}]}, {"background": "The Hawaiian Islands ( Figure above ) are in the central Pacific Ocean. The islands are volcanoes that increase in age from southeast to northwest. The youngest island is the Big Island of Hawaii at the southeast end of the chain. The volcanoes get older through Maui, Kahoolawe, Lanai, Molokai, Oahu, Kauai, and Niihau Islands through the northwest. The Kilauea volcano on Hawaii has been erupting almost continuously since 1983. There are also eruptions at an underwater volcano called Loihi seamount. Loihi is the youngest volcano. Hawaii is a fantastic place to see volcanic eruptions and features.", "situation": "Dave recently went on vacation to the Hawaiian Islands. He started his vacation on The youngest island and ended it on the oldest island. Dave especially liked seeing the Kilauea volcano. One of the tour guides told him about the Loihi volcano which erupts under water.", "qas": [{"question": "Which volcano is younger Kilauea or Loihi?", "id": "1016219865", "answers": [{"text": "Loihi"}]}]}, {"background": "The Hawaiian Islands ( Figure above ) are in the central Pacific Ocean. The islands are volcanoes that increase in age from southeast to northwest. The youngest island is the Big Island of Hawaii at the southeast end of the chain. The volcanoes get older through Maui, Kahoolawe, Lanai, Molokai, Oahu, Kauai, and Niihau Islands through the northwest. The Kilauea volcano on Hawaii has been erupting almost continuously since 1983. There are also eruptions at an underwater volcano called Loihi seamount. Loihi is the youngest volcano. Hawaii is a fantastic place to see volcanic eruptions and features.", "situation": "Dave recently went on vacation to the Hawaiian Islands. He started his vacation on The youngest island and ended it on the oldest island. Dave especially liked seeing the Kilauea volcano. One of the tour guides told him about the Loihi volcano which erupts under water.", "qas": [{"question": "Which volcano is older Kilauea or Loihi?", "id": "2786543590", "answers": [{"text": "Kilauea"}]}]}, {"background": "Gibberellins are hormones that cause the plant to grow. When gibberellins are applied to plants by scientists, the stems grow longer. Some gardeners or horticulture scientists add gibberellins to increase the growth of plants. Dwarf plants (small plants), on the other hand, have low levels of gibberellins ( Figure below ). Another function of gibberellins is to stop dormancy (resting time) of seeds and buds. Gibberellins signal that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s time for a seed to germinate (sprout) or for a bud to open.", "situation": "Jane had a small garden she planted with beans andfull sized tomatoes each year. She wanted to plant more tomatoes this year but didn't have the room. She decided to plant some dwarf tomatoes in pots instead.", "qas": [{"question": "which tomatoes have more Gibberellins?", "id": "2967474495", "answers": [{"text": "full sized tomatoes"}]}]}, {"background": "Gibberellins are hormones that cause the plant to grow. When gibberellins are applied to plants by scientists, the stems grow longer. Some gardeners or horticulture scientists add gibberellins to increase the growth of plants. Dwarf plants (small plants), on the other hand, have low levels of gibberellins ( Figure below ). Another function of gibberellins is to stop dormancy (resting time) of seeds and buds. Gibberellins signal that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s time for a seed to germinate (sprout) or for a bud to open.", "situation": "Jane had a small garden she planted with beans andfull sized tomatoes each year. She wanted to plant more tomatoes this year but didn't have the room. She decided to plant some dwarf tomatoes in pots instead. Both tomato plants produced lots of delicious tomatoes.", "qas": [{"question": "Which tomatoes have fewer Gibberellins?", "id": "4189595296", "answers": [{"text": "dwarf tomatoes"}]}]}, {"background": "Gibberellins are hormones that cause the plant to grow. When gibberellins are applied to plants by scientists, the stems grow longer. Some gardeners or horticulture scientists add gibberellins to increase the growth of plants. Dwarf plants (small plants), on the other hand, have low levels of gibberellins ( Figure below ). Another function of gibberellins is to stop dormancy (resting time) of seeds and buds. Gibberellins signal that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s time for a seed to germinate (sprout) or for a bud to open.", "situation": "Jane had a small garden she planted with beans andfull sized tomatoes each year. She wanted to plant more tomatoes this year but didn't have the room. She decided to plant some dwarf tomatoes in pots instead. Both tomato plants produced lots of delicious tomatoes.", "qas": [{"question": "Which tomatoes started growing due to Gibberellins?", "id": "3963956024", "answers": [{"text": "Both tomato plants"}]}]}, {"background": "Gibberellins are hormones that cause the plant to grow. When gibberellins are applied to plants by scientists, the stems grow longer. Some gardeners or horticulture scientists add gibberellins to increase the growth of plants. Dwarf plants (small plants), on the other hand, have low levels of gibberellins ( Figure below ). Another function of gibberellins is to stop dormancy (resting time) of seeds and buds. Gibberellins signal that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s time for a seed to germinate (sprout) or for a bud to open.", "situation": "Jane had a small garden she planted with beans andfull sized tomatoes each year. She wanted to plant more tomatoes this year but didn't have the room. She decided to plant some dwarf tomatoes in pots instead. Both tomato plants produced lots of delicious tomatoes.", "qas": [{"question": "Which tomatoes plants have Gibberellins?", "id": "596322073", "answers": [{"text": "Both tomato plants"}]}]}, {"background": "Gibberellins are hormones that cause the plant to grow. When gibberellins are applied to plants by scientists, the stems grow longer. Some gardeners or horticulture scientists add gibberellins to increase the growth of plants. Dwarf plants (small plants), on the other hand, have low levels of gibberellins ( Figure below ). Another function of gibberellins is to stop dormancy (resting time) of seeds and buds. Gibberellins signal that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s time for a seed to germinate (sprout) or for a bud to open.", "situation": "Jane had a small garden she planted with beans andfull sized tomatoes each year. She wanted to plant more tomatoes this year but didn't have the room. She decided to plant some dwarf tomatoes in pots instead. Both tomato plants produced lots of delicious tomatoes.", "qas": [{"question": "Would adding more Gibberellins to the dwarf tomatoes make them taller or shorter??", "id": "3337827908", "answers": [{"text": "taller"}]}]}, {"background": "Gibberellins are hormones that cause the plant to grow. When gibberellins are applied to plants by scientists, the stems grow longer. Some gardeners or horticulture scientists add gibberellins to increase the growth of plants. Dwarf plants (small plants), on the other hand, have low levels of gibberellins ( Figure below ). Another function of gibberellins is to stop dormancy (resting time) of seeds and buds. Gibberellins signal that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s time for a seed to germinate (sprout) or for a bud to open.", "situation": "Jane had a small garden she planted with beans andfull sized tomatoes each year. She wanted to plant more tomatoes this year but didn't have the room. She decided to plant some dwarf tomatoes in pots instead. Both tomato plants produced lots of delicious tomatoes.", "qas": [{"question": "Would adding more Gibberellins to the full sized tomatoes make them taller or shorter??", "id": "3695786018", "answers": [{"text": "taller"}]}]}, {"background": "Gibberellins are hormones that cause the plant to grow. When gibberellins are applied to plants by scientists, the stems grow longer. Some gardeners or horticulture scientists add gibberellins to increase the growth of plants. Dwarf plants (small plants), on the other hand, have low levels of gibberellins ( Figure below ). Another function of gibberellins is to stop dormancy (resting time) of seeds and buds. Gibberellins signal that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s time for a seed to germinate (sprout) or for a bud to open.", "situation": "Jane had a small garden she planted with beans andfull sized tomatoes each year. She wanted to plant more tomatoes this year but didn't have the room. She decided to plant some dwarf tomatoes in pots instead. Both tomato plants produced lots of delicious tomatoes.", "qas": [{"question": "Would the full sized tomatoes grow or stay dormant without Gibberellins?", "id": "3331142456", "answers": [{"text": "stay dormant"}]}]}, {"background": "Gibberellins are hormones that cause the plant to grow. When gibberellins are applied to plants by scientists, the stems grow longer. Some gardeners or horticulture scientists add gibberellins to increase the growth of plants. Dwarf plants (small plants), on the other hand, have low levels of gibberellins ( Figure below ). Another function of gibberellins is to stop dormancy (resting time) of seeds and buds. Gibberellins signal that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s time for a seed to germinate (sprout) or for a bud to open.", "situation": "Jane had a small garden she planted with beans andfull sized tomatoes each year. She wanted to plant more tomatoes this year but didn't have the room. She decided to plant some dwarf tomatoes in pots instead. Both tomato plants produced lots of delicious tomatoes.", "qas": [{"question": "Would the dwarf tomatoes grow or stay dormant without Gibberellins?", "id": "3430691162", "answers": [{"text": "stay dormant"}]}]}, {"background": "Gibberellins are hormones that cause the plant to grow. When gibberellins are applied to plants by scientists, the stems grow longer. Some gardeners or horticulture scientists add gibberellins to increase the growth of plants. Dwarf plants (small plants), on the other hand, have low levels of gibberellins ( Figure below ). Another function of gibberellins is to stop dormancy (resting time) of seeds and buds. Gibberellins signal that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s time for a seed to germinate (sprout) or for a bud to open.", "situation": "Jane had a small garden she planted with beans andfull sized tomatoes each year. She wanted to plant more tomatoes this year but didn't have the room. She decided to plant some dwarf tomatoes in pots instead. Both tomato plants produced lots of delicious tomatoes.", "qas": [{"question": "Would the beans grow or stay dormant without Gibberellins?", "id": "386018755", "answers": [{"text": "stay dormant"}]}]}, {"background": "Gibberellins are hormones that cause the plant to grow. When gibberellins are applied to plants by scientists, the stems grow longer. Some gardeners or horticulture scientists add gibberellins to increase the growth of plants. Dwarf plants (small plants), on the other hand, have low levels of gibberellins ( Figure below ). Another function of gibberellins is to stop dormancy (resting time) of seeds and buds. Gibberellins signal that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s time for a seed to germinate (sprout) or for a bud to open.", "situation": "Jane had a small garden she planted with beans andfull sized tomatoes each year. She wanted to plant more tomatoes this year but didn't have the room. She decided to plant some dwarf tomatoes in pots instead. Both tomato plants produced lots of delicious tomatoes.", "qas": [{"question": "Would the beans get taller or shorter if they were given more Gibberellins?", "id": "1160131469", "answers": [{"text": "taller"}]}]}, {"background": "Another major cause of extinction is global warming , which is also known as global climate change. During the past century, the Earth's average temperature has risen by almost 1\u00c2\u00b0C (about 1.3\u00c2\u00b0F). You may not think that is significant, but to organisms that live in the wild and are constantly adapting to their environments, any climate change can be hazardous. Recall that burning fossil fuels releases gasses into the atmosphere that warm the Earth. Our increased use of fossil fuels, such as coal and oil, is changing the Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s climate. Any long-term change in the climate can destroy the habitat of a species. Even a brief change in climate may be too stressful for an organism to survive. For example, if the seas increase in temperature, even briefly, it may be too warm for certain types of fish to reproduce.", "situation": "To help hide from predators the snow hare has evolved to turn white in winter to blend in with the snow. But in recent years winters have been warmer and the snow is melting earlier than usual. Without snow on the ground the white hares stand out more and are easy prey for predators including foxes and coyotes.", "qas": [{"question": "Has the average winter temperature increased or decreased?", "id": "492417639", "answers": [{"text": "increased"}]}]}, {"background": "Another major cause of extinction is global warming , which is also known as global climate change. During the past century, the Earth's average temperature has risen by almost 1\u00c2\u00b0C (about 1.3\u00c2\u00b0F). You may not think that is significant, but to organisms that live in the wild and are constantly adapting to their environments, any climate change can be hazardous. Recall that burning fossil fuels releases gasses into the atmosphere that warm the Earth. Our increased use of fossil fuels, such as coal and oil, is changing the Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s climate. Any long-term change in the climate can destroy the habitat of a species. Even a brief change in climate may be too stressful for an organism to survive. For example, if the seas increase in temperature, even briefly, it may be too warm for certain types of fish to reproduce.", "situation": "To help hide from predators the snow hare has evolved to turn white in winter to blend in with the snow. But in recent years winters have been warmer and the snow is melting earlier than usual. Without snow on the ground the white hares stand out more and are easy prey for predators including foxes and coyotes.", "qas": [{"question": "What animal is being harmed by the shorter winter?", "id": "2238099181", "answers": [{"text": "snow hare"}]}]}, {"background": "Another major cause of extinction is global warming , which is also known as global climate change. During the past century, the Earth's average temperature has risen by almost 1\u00c2\u00b0C (about 1.3\u00c2\u00b0F). You may not think that is significant, but to organisms that live in the wild and are constantly adapting to their environments, any climate change can be hazardous. Recall that burning fossil fuels releases gasses into the atmosphere that warm the Earth. Our increased use of fossil fuels, such as coal and oil, is changing the Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s climate. Any long-term change in the climate can destroy the habitat of a species. Even a brief change in climate may be too stressful for an organism to survive. For example, if the seas increase in temperature, even briefly, it may be too warm for certain types of fish to reproduce.", "situation": "To help hide from predators the snow hare has evolved to turn white in winter to blend in with the snow. But in recent years winters have been warmer and the snow is melting earlier than usual. Without snow on the ground the white hares stand out more and are easy prey for predators including foxes and coyotes.", "qas": [{"question": "What animal is benefiting from the shorter winter?", "id": "2407640907", "answers": [{"text": "foxes and coyotes"}]}]}, {"background": "Another major cause of extinction is global warming , which is also known as global climate change. During the past century, the Earth's average temperature has risen by almost 1\u00c2\u00b0C (about 1.3\u00c2\u00b0F). You may not think that is significant, but to organisms that live in the wild and are constantly adapting to their environments, any climate change can be hazardous. Recall that burning fossil fuels releases gasses into the atmosphere that warm the Earth. Our increased use of fossil fuels, such as coal and oil, is changing the Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s climate. Any long-term change in the climate can destroy the habitat of a species. Even a brief change in climate may be too stressful for an organism to survive. For example, if the seas increase in temperature, even briefly, it may be too warm for certain types of fish to reproduce.", "situation": "To help hide from predators the snow hare has evolved to turn white in winter to blend in with the snow. But in recent years winters have been warmer and the snow is melting earlier than usual. Without snow on the ground the white hares stand out more and are easy prey for predators including foxes and coyotes.", "qas": [{"question": "What animal is adapted to the snow?", "id": "1853008185", "answers": [{"text": "snow hare"}]}]}, {"background": "Another major cause of extinction is global warming , which is also known as global climate change. During the past century, the Earth's average temperature has risen by almost 1\u00c2\u00b0C (about 1.3\u00c2\u00b0F). You may not think that is significant, but to organisms that live in the wild and are constantly adapting to their environments, any climate change can be hazardous. Recall that burning fossil fuels releases gasses into the atmosphere that warm the Earth. Our increased use of fossil fuels, such as coal and oil, is changing the Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s climate. Any long-term change in the climate can destroy the habitat of a species. Even a brief change in climate may be too stressful for an organism to survive. For example, if the seas increase in temperature, even briefly, it may be too warm for certain types of fish to reproduce.", "situation": "To help hide from predators the snow hare has evolved to turn white in winter to blend in with the snow. But in recent years winters have been warmer and the snow is melting earlier than usual. Without snow on the ground the white hares stand out more and are easy prey for predators including foxes and coyotes.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the snow hare population increasing or decreasing?", "id": "2709434497", "answers": [{"text": "decreasing"}]}]}, {"background": "Another major cause of extinction is global warming , which is also known as global climate change. During the past century, the Earth's average temperature has risen by almost 1\u00c2\u00b0C (about 1.3\u00c2\u00b0F). You may not think that is significant, but to organisms that live in the wild and are constantly adapting to their environments, any climate change can be hazardous. Recall that burning fossil fuels releases gasses into the atmosphere that warm the Earth. Our increased use of fossil fuels, such as coal and oil, is changing the Earth\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s climate. Any long-term change in the climate can destroy the habitat of a species. Even a brief change in climate may be too stressful for an organism to survive. For example, if the seas increase in temperature, even briefly, it may be too warm for certain types of fish to reproduce.", "situation": "To help hide from predators the snow hare has evolved to turn white in winter to blend in with the snow. But in recent years winters have been warmer and the snow is melting earlier than usual. Without snow on the ground the white hares stand out more and are easy prey for predators including foxes and coyotes.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the climate changing or staying the same?", "id": "1938009243", "answers": [{"text": "changing"}]}]}, {"background": "Any unused energy in food\u00e2\u20ac\u201dwhether it comes from carbohydrates, proteins, or lipids\u00e2\u20ac\u201dis stored in the body as fat. An extra 3,500 Calories of energy results in the storage of almost half a kilogram (1 pound) of stored body fat. People who consistently consume more food energy then they need may become obese. Obesity occurs when the body mass index is 30.0 kg/m 2 or greater. Body mass index (BMI) is an estimate of the fat content of the body. It is calculated by dividing a person\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s weight (in kilograms) by the square of the person\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s height (in meters). Obesity increases the risk of health problems such as type 2 diabetes and hypertension.", "situation": "Jane had always had a physical job. Recently she got a desk job. Jane realized that even though she was not as active as she used to be she was eating the same amount of food and wondered how this would effect her.", "qas": [{"question": "Will jane lose or gain weight?", "id": "2624668250", "answers": [{"text": "gain"}]}]}, {"background": "Any unused energy in food\u00e2\u20ac\u201dwhether it comes from carbohydrates, proteins, or lipids\u00e2\u20ac\u201dis stored in the body as fat. An extra 3,500 Calories of energy results in the storage of almost half a kilogram (1 pound) of stored body fat. People who consistently consume more food energy then they need may become obese. Obesity occurs when the body mass index is 30.0 kg/m 2 or greater. Body mass index (BMI) is an estimate of the fat content of the body. It is calculated by dividing a person\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s weight (in kilograms) by the square of the person\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s height (in meters). Obesity increases the risk of health problems such as type 2 diabetes and hypertension.", "situation": "Jane had always had a physical job. Recently she got a desk job. Jane realized that even though she was not as active as she used to be she was eating the same amount of food and had gained weight.", "qas": [{"question": "Is jane using more or less calories than she is eating?", "id": "2727757037", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Any unused energy in food\u00e2\u20ac\u201dwhether it comes from carbohydrates, proteins, or lipids\u00e2\u20ac\u201dis stored in the body as fat. An extra 3,500 Calories of energy results in the storage of almost half a kilogram (1 pound) of stored body fat. People who consistently consume more food energy then they need may become obese. Obesity occurs when the body mass index is 30.0 kg/m 2 or greater. Body mass index (BMI) is an estimate of the fat content of the body. It is calculated by dividing a person\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s weight (in kilograms) by the square of the person\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s height (in meters). Obesity increases the risk of health problems such as type 2 diabetes and hypertension.", "situation": "Jane had always had a physical job. Recently she got a desk job. Jane realized that even though she was not as active as she used to be she was eating the same amount of food and had gained weight.", "qas": [{"question": "Is jane easting more or less calories than she is using?", "id": "3925362016", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Any unused energy in food\u00e2\u20ac\u201dwhether it comes from carbohydrates, proteins, or lipids\u00e2\u20ac\u201dis stored in the body as fat. An extra 3,500 Calories of energy results in the storage of almost half a kilogram (1 pound) of stored body fat. People who consistently consume more food energy then they need may become obese. Obesity occurs when the body mass index is 30.0 kg/m 2 or greater. Body mass index (BMI) is an estimate of the fat content of the body. It is calculated by dividing a person\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s weight (in kilograms) by the square of the person\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s height (in meters). Obesity increases the risk of health problems such as type 2 diabetes and hypertension.", "situation": "Jane had always had a physical job. Recently she got a desk job. Jane realized that even though she was not as active as she used to be she was eating the same amount of food and had gained weight.", "qas": [{"question": "Is jane storing or burning body fat?", "id": "3327278640", "answers": [{"text": "storing"}]}]}, {"background": "A ramp like the one in the Figure below is another example of an inclined plane. Inclined planes make it easier to move objects to a higher elevation. The sloping surface of the inclined plane supports part of the weight of the object as it moves up the slope. As a result, it takes less force to move the object uphill. The trade-off is that the object must be moved over a greater distance than if it were moved straight up to the higher elevation. You can see several other examples of inclined planes at this URL", "situation": "Mark liked working in the warehouse. His favorite job was unloading the trucks. Mark could loaded boxes from the truck onto a dolly then push that up a ramp and onto the dock which was several feet above the ground.One of his coworkers Jim was a show off and insisted it was faster just to carry the boxes to the dock without the ramp and lift them up to the dock.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is carrying the boxes a shorter distance?", "id": "4045491618", "answers": [{"text": "Jim"}]}]}, {"background": "A ramp like the one in the Figure below is another example of an inclined plane. Inclined planes make it easier to move objects to a higher elevation. The sloping surface of the inclined plane supports part of the weight of the object as it moves up the slope. As a result, it takes less force to move the object uphill. The trade-off is that the object must be moved over a greater distance than if it were moved straight up to the higher elevation. You can see several other examples of inclined planes at this URL", "situation": "Mark liked working in the warehouse. His favorite job was unloading the trucks. Mark could loaded boxes from the truck onto a dolly then push that up a ramp and onto the dock which was several feet above the ground.One of his coworkers Jim was a show off and insisted it was faster just to carry the boxes to the dock without the ramp and lift them up to the dock.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is carrying the boxes a longer distance?", "id": "2716618018", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "A ramp like the one in the Figure below is another example of an inclined plane. Inclined planes make it easier to move objects to a higher elevation. The sloping surface of the inclined plane supports part of the weight of the object as it moves up the slope. As a result, it takes less force to move the object uphill. The trade-off is that the object must be moved over a greater distance than if it were moved straight up to the higher elevation. You can see several other examples of inclined planes at this URL", "situation": "Mark liked working in the warehouse. His favorite job was unloading the trucks. Mark could loaded boxes from the truck onto a dolly then push that up a ramp and onto the dock which was several feet above the ground.One of his coworkers Jim was a show off and insisted it was faster just to carry the boxes to the dock without the ramp and lift them up to the dock.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is carrying all the weight of the boxes?", "id": "2673102054", "answers": [{"text": "Jim"}]}]}, {"background": "A ramp like the one in the Figure below is another example of an inclined plane. Inclined planes make it easier to move objects to a higher elevation. The sloping surface of the inclined plane supports part of the weight of the object as it moves up the slope. As a result, it takes less force to move the object uphill. The trade-off is that the object must be moved over a greater distance than if it were moved straight up to the higher elevation. You can see several other examples of inclined planes at this URL", "situation": "Mark liked working in the warehouse. His favorite job was unloading the trucks. Mark could loaded boxes from the truck onto a dolly then push that up a ramp and onto the dock which was several feet above the ground.One of his coworkers Jim was a show off and insisted it was faster just to carry the boxes to the dock without the ramp and lift them up to the dock.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is carrying only some of the weight of the boxes?", "id": "1742295096", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "A ramp like the one in the Figure below is another example of an inclined plane. Inclined planes make it easier to move objects to a higher elevation. The sloping surface of the inclined plane supports part of the weight of the object as it moves up the slope. As a result, it takes less force to move the object uphill. The trade-off is that the object must be moved over a greater distance than if it were moved straight up to the higher elevation. You can see several other examples of inclined planes at this URL", "situation": "Mark liked working in the warehouse. His favorite job was unloading the trucks. Mark could loaded boxes from the truck onto a dolly then push that up a ramp and onto the dock which was several feet above the ground.One of his coworkers Jim was a show off and insisted it was faster just to carry the boxes to the dock without the ramp and lift them up to the dock.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is working harder?", "id": "1475036453", "answers": [{"text": "Jim"}]}]}, {"background": "A ramp like the one in the Figure below is another example of an inclined plane. Inclined planes make it easier to move objects to a higher elevation. The sloping surface of the inclined plane supports part of the weight of the object as it moves up the slope. As a result, it takes less force to move the object uphill. The trade-off is that the object must be moved over a greater distance than if it were moved straight up to the higher elevation. You can see several other examples of inclined planes at this URL", "situation": "Mark liked working in the warehouse. His favorite job was unloading the trucks. Mark could loaded boxes from the truck onto a dolly then push that up a ramp and onto the dock which was several feet above the ground.One of his coworkers Jim was a show off and insisted it was faster just to carry the boxes to the dock without the ramp and lift them up to the dock.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is working easier", "id": "315049193", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "A ramp like the one in the Figure below is another example of an inclined plane. Inclined planes make it easier to move objects to a higher elevation. The sloping surface of the inclined plane supports part of the weight of the object as it moves up the slope. As a result, it takes less force to move the object uphill. The trade-off is that the object must be moved over a greater distance than if it were moved straight up to the higher elevation. You can see several other examples of inclined planes at this URL", "situation": "Bob pulled the moving truck up in front of his new home. The truck was filled with everything he owned. He lowered the loading ramp and began carrying boxes down the ramp and into the house.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the ramp increase or decrese the distance to the ground?", "id": "3888124834", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "A ramp like the one in the Figure below is another example of an inclined plane. Inclined planes make it easier to move objects to a higher elevation. The sloping surface of the inclined plane supports part of the weight of the object as it moves up the slope. As a result, it takes less force to move the object uphill. The trade-off is that the object must be moved over a greater distance than if it were moved straight up to the higher elevation. You can see several other examples of inclined planes at this URL", "situation": "Bob pulled the moving truck up in front of his new home. The truck was filled with everything he owned. He lowered the loading ramp and began carrying boxes down the ramp and into the house.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the incline plane support some or all of weight of the boxes?", "id": "1419646302", "answers": [{"text": "some"}]}]}, {"background": "A ramp like the one in the Figure below is another example of an inclined plane. Inclined planes make it easier to move objects to a higher elevation. The sloping surface of the inclined plane supports part of the weight of the object as it moves up the slope. As a result, it takes less force to move the object uphill. The trade-off is that the object must be moved over a greater distance than if it were moved straight up to the higher elevation. You can see several other examples of inclined planes at this URL", "situation": "Bob pulled the moving truck up in front of his new home. The truck was filled with everything he owned. He lowered the loading ramp and began carrying boxes down the ramp and into the house.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the ramp make the work easier or harder?", "id": "3563064719", "answers": [{"text": "easier"}]}]}, {"background": "A ramp like the one in the Figure below is another example of an inclined plane. Inclined planes make it easier to move objects to a higher elevation. The sloping surface of the inclined plane supports part of the weight of the object as it moves up the slope. As a result, it takes less force to move the object uphill. The trade-off is that the object must be moved over a greater distance than if it were moved straight up to the higher elevation. You can see several other examples of inclined planes at this URL", "situation": "Bob pulled the moving truck up in front of his new home. The truck was filled with everything he owned. He lowered the loading ramp and began carrying boxes down the ramp and into the house.", "qas": [{"question": "would the distance to the ground be closer or further without the ramp??", "id": "338696345", "answers": [{"text": "closer"}]}]}, {"background": "A ramp like the one in the Figure below is another example of an inclined plane. Inclined planes make it easier to move objects to a higher elevation. The sloping surface of the inclined plane supports part of the weight of the object as it moves up the slope. As a result, it takes less force to move the object uphill. The trade-off is that the object must be moved over a greater distance than if it were moved straight up to the higher elevation. You can see several other examples of inclined planes at this URL", "situation": "Bob pulled the moving truck up in front of his new home. The truck was filled with everything he owned. He lowered the loading ramp and began carrying boxes down the ramp and into the house.", "qas": [{"question": "would the work be harder or easier without the ramp?", "id": "1757548838", "answers": [{"text": "harder"}]}]}, {"background": "A ramp like the one in the Figure below is another example of an inclined plane. Inclined planes make it easier to move objects to a higher elevation. The sloping surface of the inclined plane supports part of the weight of the object as it moves up the slope. As a result, it takes less force to move the object uphill. The trade-off is that the object must be moved over a greater distance than if it were moved straight up to the higher elevation. You can see several other examples of inclined planes at this URL", "situation": "Mark was putting a ramp in for his parents. His mother had recently started using a cane and sometime a wheelchair. She had a lot of difficulty climbing the stairs. Mark hoped the wheelchair would make her life a little easier.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the distance to the door longer or shorter without the ramp?", "id": "160768568", "answers": [{"text": "shorter"}]}]}, {"background": "Before dealing with the specifics of the rules for determining the significant figures in a calculated result, we need to be able to round numbers correctly. To round a number, first decide how many significant figures the number should have. Once you know that, round to that many digits, starting from the left. If the number immediately to the right of the last significant digit is less than 5, it is dropped and the value of the last significant digit remains the same. If the number immediately to the right of the last significant digit is greater than or equal to 5, the last significant digit is increased by 1.", "situation": "Matt was trying to stick to a budget at the grocery store so he estimated what he was spending as he went along. He grabbed some milk for $3.45 and $3.50 to his total. When picked up cookies for $2.03 he added $2 to his total.", "qas": [{"question": "What was the signifigant number in the milk price?", "id": "3591913191", "answers": [{"text": "3.4"}]}]}, {"background": "Before dealing with the specifics of the rules for determining the significant figures in a calculated result, we need to be able to round numbers correctly. To round a number, first decide how many significant figures the number should have. Once you know that, round to that many digits, starting from the left. If the number immediately to the right of the last significant digit is less than 5, it is dropped and the value of the last significant digit remains the same. If the number immediately to the right of the last significant digit is greater than or equal to 5, the last significant digit is increased by 1.", "situation": "Matt was trying to stick to a budget at the grocery store so he estimated what he was spending as he went along. He grabbed some milk for $3.45 and $3.50 to his total. When picked up cookies for $2.03 he added $2 to his total.", "qas": [{"question": "How many signifigant number were in the milk price?", "id": "453197661", "answers": [{"text": "2"}]}]}, {"background": "Before dealing with the specifics of the rules for determining the significant figures in a calculated result, we need to be able to round numbers correctly. To round a number, first decide how many significant figures the number should have. Once you know that, round to that many digits, starting from the left. If the number immediately to the right of the last significant digit is less than 5, it is dropped and the value of the last significant digit remains the same. If the number immediately to the right of the last significant digit is greater than or equal to 5, the last significant digit is increased by 1.", "situation": "Matt was trying to stick to a budget at the grocery store so he estimated what he was spending as he went along. He grabbed some milk for $3.45 and $3.50 to his total. When picked up cookies for $2.03 he added $2.00 to his total.", "qas": [{"question": "What was the signifigant numbers in the cookie price?", "id": "898056373", "answers": [{"text": "2"}]}]}, {"background": "Beginning in September 2012, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration will require larger, more prominent cigarette health warnings on all cigarette packaging and advertisements in the United States. These warnings are a significant advancement in communicating the dangers of smoking. These new cigarette health warnings contains nine different warnings that will increase awareness of the specific health risks associated with smoking, such as death, addiction, lung disease, cancer, stroke and heart disease. These warnings include:", "situation": "The United states decided to put more prominent health warnings of cigarettes. Meanwhile Canada has opted to keep the same labels that are not as prominent.", "qas": [{"question": "Where are consumers more likely to quit smoking?", "id": "2325810740", "answers": [{"text": "United states"}]}]}, {"background": "Beginning in September 2012, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration will require larger, more prominent cigarette health warnings on all cigarette packaging and advertisements in the United States. These warnings are a significant advancement in communicating the dangers of smoking. These new cigarette health warnings contains nine different warnings that will increase awareness of the specific health risks associated with smoking, such as death, addiction, lung disease, cancer, stroke and heart disease. These warnings include:", "situation": "The United states decided to put more prominent health warnings of cigarettes. Meanwhile Canada has opted to keep the same labels that are not as prominent.", "qas": [{"question": "Where are consumers less likely to quit smoking?", "id": "2330922552", "answers": [{"text": "Canada"}]}]}, {"background": "Beginning in September 2012, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration will require larger, more prominent cigarette health warnings on all cigarette packaging and advertisements in the United States. These warnings are a significant advancement in communicating the dangers of smoking. These new cigarette health warnings contains nine different warnings that will increase awareness of the specific health risks associated with smoking, such as death, addiction, lung disease, cancer, stroke and heart disease. These warnings include:", "situation": "The United states decided to put more prominent health warnings of cigarettes. Meanwhile Canada has opted to keep the same labels that are not as prominent.", "qas": [{"question": "Which country is most likely to see a decrease in lung cancer?", "id": "1777865389", "answers": [{"text": "United states"}]}]}, {"background": "Beginning in September 2012, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration will require larger, more prominent cigarette health warnings on all cigarette packaging and advertisements in the United States. These warnings are a significant advancement in communicating the dangers of smoking. These new cigarette health warnings contains nine different warnings that will increase awareness of the specific health risks associated with smoking, such as death, addiction, lung disease, cancer, stroke and heart disease. These warnings include:", "situation": "The United states decided to put more prominent health warnings of cigarettes. Meanwhile Canada has opted to keep the same labels that are not as prominent.", "qas": [{"question": "Which country is least likely to see a decrease in lung cancer?", "id": "2080051971", "answers": [{"text": "Canada"}]}]}, {"background": "Beginning in September 2012, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration will require larger, more prominent cigarette health warnings on all cigarette packaging and advertisements in the United States. These warnings are a significant advancement in communicating the dangers of smoking. These new cigarette health warnings contains nine different warnings that will increase awareness of the specific health risks associated with smoking, such as death, addiction, lung disease, cancer, stroke and heart disease. These warnings include:", "situation": "The United states decided to put more prominent health warnings of cigarettes. Meanwhile Canada has opted to keep the same labels that are not as prominent.", "qas": [{"question": "Will there be more or less heart disease in The United States?", "id": "1446449744", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Beginning in September 2012, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration will require larger, more prominent cigarette health warnings on all cigarette packaging and advertisements in the United States. These warnings are a significant advancement in communicating the dangers of smoking. These new cigarette health warnings contains nine different warnings that will increase awareness of the specific health risks associated with smoking, such as death, addiction, lung disease, cancer, stroke and heart disease. These warnings include:", "situation": "The United states decided to put more prominent health warnings of cigarettes. Meanwhile Canada has opted to keep the same labels that are not as prominent.", "qas": [{"question": "Will there be more or less addiction in The United States?", "id": "266604781", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Something that is elastic can return to its original shape after being stretched or compressed. This property is called elasticity . As you stretch or compress an elastic material like a bungee cord, it resists the change in shape. It exerts a counter force in the opposite direction. This force is called elastic force . The farther the material is stretched or compressed, the greater the elastic force becomes. As soon as the stretching or compressing force is released, elastic force causes the material to spring back to its original shape. You can watch a demonstration of elastic force at this URL:", "situation": "Matt and his friends where bored so they started shooting rubber bands at each other. Mat and Mark both stretched their rubber bands back and released them but Mark's went much further.", "qas": [{"question": "I gravitational or elastic force pushing back as the rubber band is stretched?", "id": "211500007", "answers": [{"text": "elastic"}]}]}, {"background": "Something that is elastic can return to its original shape after being stretched or compressed. This property is called elasticity . As you stretch or compress an elastic material like a bungee cord, it resists the change in shape. It exerts a counter force in the opposite direction. This force is called elastic force . The farther the material is stretched or compressed, the greater the elastic force becomes. As soon as the stretching or compressing force is released, elastic force causes the material to spring back to its original shape. You can watch a demonstration of elastic force at this URL:", "situation": "Matt and his friends where bored so they started shooting rubber bands at each other. Mat and Mark both stretched their rubber bands back and released them but Mark's went much further.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's rubber band had more elastic force?", "id": "1192701418", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Something that is elastic can return to its original shape after being stretched or compressed. This property is called elasticity . As you stretch or compress an elastic material like a bungee cord, it resists the change in shape. It exerts a counter force in the opposite direction. This force is called elastic force . The farther the material is stretched or compressed, the greater the elastic force becomes. As soon as the stretching or compressing force is released, elastic force causes the material to spring back to its original shape. You can watch a demonstration of elastic force at this URL:", "situation": "Matt and his friends where bored so they started shooting rubber bands at each other. Mat and Mark both stretched their rubber bands back and released them but Mark's went much further.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's rubber band had less elastic force?", "id": "1195453934", "answers": [{"text": "Mat"}]}]}, {"background": "Something that is elastic can return to its original shape after being stretched or compressed. This property is called elasticity . As you stretch or compress an elastic material like a bungee cord, it resists the change in shape. It exerts a counter force in the opposite direction. This force is called elastic force . The farther the material is stretched or compressed, the greater the elastic force becomes. As soon as the stretching or compressing force is released, elastic force causes the material to spring back to its original shape. You can watch a demonstration of elastic force at this URL:", "situation": "Matt and his friends where bored so they started shooting rubber bands at each other. Mat and Mark both stretched their rubber bands back and released them but Mark's went much further.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's rubber band was stretched the farthest?", "id": "155070409", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Something that is elastic can return to its original shape after being stretched or compressed. This property is called elasticity . As you stretch or compress an elastic material like a bungee cord, it resists the change in shape. It exerts a counter force in the opposite direction. This force is called elastic force . The farther the material is stretched or compressed, the greater the elastic force becomes. As soon as the stretching or compressing force is released, elastic force causes the material to spring back to its original shape. You can watch a demonstration of elastic force at this URL:", "situation": "Matt and his friends where bored so they started shooting rubber bands at each other. Mat and Mark both stretched their rubber bands back and released them but Mark's went much further.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's rubber band was stretched the least?", "id": "2057907841", "answers": [{"text": "Mat"}]}]}, {"background": "Circadian rhythms are regular changes in biology or behavior that occur in a 24-hour cycle. In humans, for example, blood pressure and body temperature change in a regular way throughout each 24-hour day. Animals may eat and drink at certain times of day as well. Humans have daily cycles of behavior, too. Most people start to get sleepy after dark and have a hard time sleeping when it is light outside. In many species, including humans, circadian rhythms are controlled by a tiny structure called the biological clock . This structure is located in a gland at the base of the brain. The biological clock sends signals to the body. The signals cause regular changes in behavior and body processes. The amount of light entering the eyes helps control the biological clock. The clock causes changes that repeat every 24 hours.", "situation": "Joe started work at 8 a.m. After a long day at work he spends time with his family and is usually in bed by 10p.m Beth works night shift. She starts work at 11 p.m. She gets of at 7 a.m after having breakfast and getting her children off to school she gets some things done around the house and is usually in bed by 2.p.m.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is following their cicrcadian rythem?", "id": "2187438408", "answers": [{"text": "Joe"}]}]}, {"background": "Circadian rhythms are regular changes in biology or behavior that occur in a 24-hour cycle. In humans, for example, blood pressure and body temperature change in a regular way throughout each 24-hour day. Animals may eat and drink at certain times of day as well. Humans have daily cycles of behavior, too. Most people start to get sleepy after dark and have a hard time sleeping when it is light outside. In many species, including humans, circadian rhythms are controlled by a tiny structure called the biological clock . This structure is located in a gland at the base of the brain. The biological clock sends signals to the body. The signals cause regular changes in behavior and body processes. The amount of light entering the eyes helps control the biological clock. The clock causes changes that repeat every 24 hours.", "situation": "Joe started work at 8 a.m. After a long day at work he spends time with his family and is usually in bed by 10p.m Beth works night shift. She starts work at 11 p.m. She gets of at 7 a.m after having breakfast and getting her children off to school she gets some things done around the house and is usually in bed by 2.p.m.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is not following their cicrcadian rythem?", "id": "673557177", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Circadian rhythms are regular changes in biology or behavior that occur in a 24-hour cycle. In humans, for example, blood pressure and body temperature change in a regular way throughout each 24-hour day. Animals may eat and drink at certain times of day as well. Humans have daily cycles of behavior, too. Most people start to get sleepy after dark and have a hard time sleeping when it is light outside. In many species, including humans, circadian rhythms are controlled by a tiny structure called the biological clock . This structure is located in a gland at the base of the brain. The biological clock sends signals to the body. The signals cause regular changes in behavior and body processes. The amount of light entering the eyes helps control the biological clock. The clock causes changes that repeat every 24 hours.", "situation": "Joe started work at 8 a.m. After a long day at work he spends time with his family and is usually in bed by 10p.m Beth works night shift. She starts work at 11 p.m. She gets of at 7 a.m after having breakfast and getting her children off to school she gets some things done around the house and is usually in bed by 2.p.m.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is sleepy when their day is starting?", "id": "2051385575", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Circadian rhythms are regular changes in biology or behavior that occur in a 24-hour cycle. In humans, for example, blood pressure and body temperature change in a regular way throughout each 24-hour day. Animals may eat and drink at certain times of day as well. Humans have daily cycles of behavior, too. Most people start to get sleepy after dark and have a hard time sleeping when it is light outside. In many species, including humans, circadian rhythms are controlled by a tiny structure called the biological clock . This structure is located in a gland at the base of the brain. The biological clock sends signals to the body. The signals cause regular changes in behavior and body processes. The amount of light entering the eyes helps control the biological clock. The clock causes changes that repeat every 24 hours.", "situation": "Joe started work at 8 a.m. After a long day at work he spends time with his family and is usually in bed by 10p.m Beth works night shift. She starts work at 11 p.m. She gets of at 7 a.m after having breakfast and getting her children off to school she gets some things done around the house and is usually in bed by 2.p.m.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is not sleepy when their day is starting?", "id": "537504344", "answers": [{"text": "Joe"}]}]}, {"background": "Circadian rhythms are regular changes in biology or behavior that occur in a 24-hour cycle. In humans, for example, blood pressure and body temperature change in a regular way throughout each 24-hour day. Animals may eat and drink at certain times of day as well. Humans have daily cycles of behavior, too. Most people start to get sleepy after dark and have a hard time sleeping when it is light outside. In many species, including humans, circadian rhythms are controlled by a tiny structure called the biological clock . This structure is located in a gland at the base of the brain. The biological clock sends signals to the body. The signals cause regular changes in behavior and body processes. The amount of light entering the eyes helps control the biological clock. The clock causes changes that repeat every 24 hours.", "situation": "Joe started work at 8 a.m. After a long day at work he spends time with his family and is usually in bed by 10p.m Beth works night shift. She starts work at 11 p.m. She gets of at 7 a.m after having breakfast and getting her children off to school she gets some things done around the house and is usually in bed by 2.p.m.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is has a hard ime sleeping?", "id": "3880494255", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Circadian rhythms are regular changes in biology or behavior that occur in a 24-hour cycle. In humans, for example, blood pressure and body temperature change in a regular way throughout each 24-hour day. Animals may eat and drink at certain times of day as well. Humans have daily cycles of behavior, too. Most people start to get sleepy after dark and have a hard time sleeping when it is light outside. In many species, including humans, circadian rhythms are controlled by a tiny structure called the biological clock . This structure is located in a gland at the base of the brain. The biological clock sends signals to the body. The signals cause regular changes in behavior and body processes. The amount of light entering the eyes helps control the biological clock. The clock causes changes that repeat every 24 hours.", "situation": "Joe started work at 8 a.m. After a long day at work he spends time with his family and is usually in bed by 10p.m Beth works night shift. She starts work at 11 p.m. She gets of at 7 a.m after having breakfast and getting her children off to school she gets some things done around the house and is usually in bed by 2.p.m.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is not havinga hard ime sleeping?", "id": "3578832705", "answers": [{"text": "Joe"}]}]}, {"background": "Circadian rhythms are regular changes in biology or behavior that occur in a 24-hour cycle. In humans, for example, blood pressure and body temperature change in a regular way throughout each 24-hour day. Animals may eat and drink at certain times of day as well. Humans have daily cycles of behavior, too. Most people start to get sleepy after dark and have a hard time sleeping when it is light outside. In many species, including humans, circadian rhythms are controlled by a tiny structure called the biological clock . This structure is located in a gland at the base of the brain. The biological clock sends signals to the body. The signals cause regular changes in behavior and body processes. The amount of light entering the eyes helps control the biological clock. The clock causes changes that repeat every 24 hours.", "situation": "Joe started work at 8 a.m. After a long day at work he spends time with his family and is usually in bed by 10p.m Beth works night shift. She starts work at 11 p.m. She gets of at 7 a.m after having breakfast and getting her children off to school she gets some things done around the house and is usually in bed by 2.p.m.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is not working with their biological clock?", "id": "2093919052", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Circadian rhythms are regular changes in biology or behavior that occur in a 24-hour cycle. In humans, for example, blood pressure and body temperature change in a regular way throughout each 24-hour day. Animals may eat and drink at certain times of day as well. Humans have daily cycles of behavior, too. Most people start to get sleepy after dark and have a hard time sleeping when it is light outside. In many species, including humans, circadian rhythms are controlled by a tiny structure called the biological clock . This structure is located in a gland at the base of the brain. The biological clock sends signals to the body. The signals cause regular changes in behavior and body processes. The amount of light entering the eyes helps control the biological clock. The clock causes changes that repeat every 24 hours.", "situation": "Joe started work at 8 a.m. After a long day at work he spends time with his family and is usually in bed by 10p.m Beth works night shift. She starts work at 11 p.m. She gets of at 7 a.m after having breakfast and getting her children off to school she gets some things done around the house and is usually in bed by 2.p.m.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is working with their biological clock?", "id": "3559434715", "answers": [{"text": "Joe"}]}]}, {"background": "Circadian rhythms are regular changes in biology or behavior that occur in a 24-hour cycle. In humans, for example, blood pressure and body temperature change in a regular way throughout each 24-hour day. Animals may eat and drink at certain times of day as well. Humans have daily cycles of behavior, too. Most people start to get sleepy after dark and have a hard time sleeping when it is light outside. In many species, including humans, circadian rhythms are controlled by a tiny structure called the biological clock . This structure is located in a gland at the base of the brain. The biological clock sends signals to the body. The signals cause regular changes in behavior and body processes. The amount of light entering the eyes helps control the biological clock. The clock causes changes that repeat every 24 hours.", "situation": "Joe started work at 8 a.m. After a long day at work he spends time with his family and is usually in bed by 10p.m Beth works night shift. She starts work at 11 p.m. She gets of at 7 a.m after having breakfast and getting her children off to school she gets some things done around the house and is usually in bed by 2.p.m.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is working with their bodies natural schedule?", "id": "2211425428", "answers": [{"text": "Joe"}]}]}, {"background": "Circadian rhythms are regular changes in biology or behavior that occur in a 24-hour cycle. In humans, for example, blood pressure and body temperature change in a regular way throughout each 24-hour day. Animals may eat and drink at certain times of day as well. Humans have daily cycles of behavior, too. Most people start to get sleepy after dark and have a hard time sleeping when it is light outside. In many species, including humans, circadian rhythms are controlled by a tiny structure called the biological clock . This structure is located in a gland at the base of the brain. The biological clock sends signals to the body. The signals cause regular changes in behavior and body processes. The amount of light entering the eyes helps control the biological clock. The clock causes changes that repeat every 24 hours.", "situation": "Joe started work at 8 a.m. After a long day at work he spends time with his family and is usually in bed by 10p.m Beth works night shift. She starts work at 11 p.m. She gets of at 7 a.m after having breakfast and getting her children off to school she gets some things done around the house and is usually in bed by 2.p.m.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is not working with their bodies natural schedule?", "id": "915189253", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solid is irregularly shaped, we can determine its volume by measuring the volume of water displaced by the solid. For example, say you want to measure the volume of the toy dinosaur in Figure below . After placing the dinosaur in the water, the volume measured in the container increases by an amount that is equal to the total volume of the dinosaur. Note that this method only works for solids that do not dissolve in water. If you tried to measure the volume occupied by a pile of salt, the salt would dissolve in the water and this method would not work very well.", "situation": "Beth is set up her new aquarium last night. First shefilled the tank with water leaving room at the top in case the water level to rose. Next she added gravel to the tank. After the gravel had settled she started adding decorations. She She looked at it a minute and decided she did not like it there. Beth lifted the castle out of the water and placed it to one side. She finished by adding some small plants and a tiny treasure chest. The water level was now at the top of the tank", "qas": [{"question": "What happened to the water level when the gravel was added?", "id": "372609456", "answers": [{"text": "rose"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solid is irregularly shaped, we can determine its volume by measuring the volume of water displaced by the solid. For example, say you want to measure the volume of the toy dinosaur in Figure below . After placing the dinosaur in the water, the volume measured in the container increases by an amount that is equal to the total volume of the dinosaur. Note that this method only works for solids that do not dissolve in water. If you tried to measure the volume occupied by a pile of salt, the salt would dissolve in the water and this method would not work very well.", "situation": "Beth is set up her new aquarium last night. First shefilled the tank with water leaving room at the top in case the water level to rose. Next she added gravel to the tank. After the gravel had settled she started adding decorations. She She looked at it a minute and decided she did not like it there. Beth lifted the castle out of the water and placed it to one side. She finished by adding some small plants and a tiny treasure chest. The water level was now at the top of the tank", "qas": [{"question": "What happened to the water level when the castle was added?", "id": "366645675", "answers": [{"text": "rose"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solid is irregularly shaped, we can determine its volume by measuring the volume of water displaced by the solid. For example, say you want to measure the volume of the toy dinosaur in Figure below . After placing the dinosaur in the water, the volume measured in the container increases by an amount that is equal to the total volume of the dinosaur. Note that this method only works for solids that do not dissolve in water. If you tried to measure the volume occupied by a pile of salt, the salt would dissolve in the water and this method would not work very well.", "situation": "Beth is set up her new aquarium last night. First shefilled the tank with water leaving room at the top in case the water level to rose. Next she added gravel to the tank. After the gravel had settled she started adding decorations. She She looked at it a minute and decided she did not like it there. Beth lifted the castle out of the water and placed it to one side. She finished by adding some small plants and a tiny treasure chest. The water level was now at the top of the tank", "qas": [{"question": "What happened to the water level when the plants were added?", "id": "2848756265", "answers": [{"text": "rose"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solid is irregularly shaped, we can determine its volume by measuring the volume of water displaced by the solid. For example, say you want to measure the volume of the toy dinosaur in Figure below . After placing the dinosaur in the water, the volume measured in the container increases by an amount that is equal to the total volume of the dinosaur. Note that this method only works for solids that do not dissolve in water. If you tried to measure the volume occupied by a pile of salt, the salt would dissolve in the water and this method would not work very well.", "situation": "Beth is set up her new aquarium last night. First shefilled the tank with water leaving room at the top in case the water level to rose. Next she added gravel to the tank. After the gravel had settled she started adding decorations. She She looked at it a minute and decided she did not like it there. Beth lifted the castle out of the water and placed it to one side. She finished by adding some small plants and a tiny treasure chest. The water level was now at the top of the tank", "qas": [{"question": "Was more water displaced when the castle or treasure chest were added?", "id": "2075694600", "answers": [{"text": "castle"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solid is irregularly shaped, we can determine its volume by measuring the volume of water displaced by the solid. For example, say you want to measure the volume of the toy dinosaur in Figure below . After placing the dinosaur in the water, the volume measured in the container increases by an amount that is equal to the total volume of the dinosaur. Note that this method only works for solids that do not dissolve in water. If you tried to measure the volume occupied by a pile of salt, the salt would dissolve in the water and this method would not work very well.", "situation": "Beth is set up her new aquarium last night. First shefilled the tank with water leaving room at the top in case the water level to rose. Next she added gravel to the tank. After the gravel had settled she started adding decorations. She She looked at it a minute and decided she did not like it there. Beth lifted the castle out of the water and placed it to one side. She finished by adding some small plants and a tiny treasure chest. The water level was now at the top of the tank", "qas": [{"question": "Was less water displaced when the castle or treasure ches were added?", "id": "3845625240", "answers": [{"text": "treasure chest"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solid is irregularly shaped, we can determine its volume by measuring the volume of water displaced by the solid. For example, say you want to measure the volume of the toy dinosaur in Figure below . After placing the dinosaur in the water, the volume measured in the container increases by an amount that is equal to the total volume of the dinosaur. Note that this method only works for solids that do not dissolve in water. If you tried to measure the volume occupied by a pile of salt, the salt would dissolve in the water and this method would not work very well.", "situation": "Beth is set up her new aquarium last night. First shefilled the tank with water leaving room at the top in case the water level to rose. Next she added gravel to the tank. She noticed that the water level rose 2 inches. After the gravel had settled she started adding decorations. She started with a large castle. Adding the castle took the water level up another inch. She looked at it a minute and decided she did not like it there. Beth lifted the castle out of the water and replaced it to one side of the tank. She finished by adding some small plants and a tiny treasure chest.", "qas": [{"question": "The gravel had a higher volume than what?", "id": "1391832842", "answers": [{"text": "castle"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solid is irregularly shaped, we can determine its volume by measuring the volume of water displaced by the solid. For example, say you want to measure the volume of the toy dinosaur in Figure below . After placing the dinosaur in the water, the volume measured in the container increases by an amount that is equal to the total volume of the dinosaur. Note that this method only works for solids that do not dissolve in water. If you tried to measure the volume occupied by a pile of salt, the salt would dissolve in the water and this method would not work very well.", "situation": "Beth is set up her new aquarium last night. First shefilled the tank with water leaving room at the top in case the water level to rose. Next she added gravel to the tank. She noticed that the water level rose 2 inches. After the gravel had settled she started adding decorations. She started with a large castle. Adding the castle took the water level up another inch. She looked at it a minute and decided she did not like it there. Beth lifted the castle out of the water and replaced it to one side of the tank. She finished by adding some small plants and a tiny treasure chest.", "qas": [{"question": "The gravel had a lower volume than what?", "id": "2774118076", "answers": [{"text": "water"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solid is irregularly shaped, we can determine its volume by measuring the volume of water displaced by the solid. For example, say you want to measure the volume of the toy dinosaur in Figure below . After placing the dinosaur in the water, the volume measured in the container increases by an amount that is equal to the total volume of the dinosaur. Note that this method only works for solids that do not dissolve in water. If you tried to measure the volume occupied by a pile of salt, the salt would dissolve in the water and this method would not work very well.", "situation": "Beth is set up her new aquarium last night. First shefilled the tank with water leaving room at the top in case the water level to rose. Next she added gravel to the tank. She noticed that the water level rose 2 inches. After the gravel had settled she started adding decorations. She started with a large castle. Adding the castle took the water level up another inch. She looked at it a minute and decided she did not like it there. Beth lifted the castle out of the water and replaced it to one side of the tank. She finished by adding some small plants and a tiny treasure chest.", "qas": [{"question": "The gravel displace more or less water than the treasure chest??", "id": "2222831566", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solid is irregularly shaped, we can determine its volume by measuring the volume of water displaced by the solid. For example, say you want to measure the volume of the toy dinosaur in Figure below . After placing the dinosaur in the water, the volume measured in the container increases by an amount that is equal to the total volume of the dinosaur. Note that this method only works for solids that do not dissolve in water. If you tried to measure the volume occupied by a pile of salt, the salt would dissolve in the water and this method would not work very well.", "situation": "Beth is set up her new aquarium last night. First shefilled the tank with water leaving room at the top in case the water level to rose. Next she added gravel to the tank. She noticed that the water level rose 2 inches. After the gravel had settled she started adding decorations. She started with a large castle. Adding the castle took the water level up another inch. She looked at it a minute and decided she did not like it there. Beth lifted the castle out of the water and replaced it to one side of the tank. She finished by adding some small plants and a tiny treasure chest.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the water level go up or down when the castle was removed???", "id": "1790686999", "answers": [{"text": "down"}]}]}, {"background": "If a solid is irregularly shaped, we can determine its volume by measuring the volume of water displaced by the solid. For example, say you want to measure the volume of the toy dinosaur in Figure below . After placing the dinosaur in the water, the volume measured in the container increases by an amount that is equal to the total volume of the dinosaur. Note that this method only works for solids that do not dissolve in water. If you tried to measure the volume occupied by a pile of salt, the salt would dissolve in the water and this method would not work very well.", "situation": "Beth is set up her new aquarium last night. First shefilled the tank with water leaving room at the top in case the water level to rose. Next she added gravel to the tank. She noticed that the water level rose 2 inches. After the gravel had settled she started adding decorations. She started with a large castle. Adding the castle took the water level up another inch. She looked at it a minute and decided she did not like it there. Beth lifted the castle out of the water and replaced it to one side of the tank. She finished by adding some small plants and a tiny treasure chest.", "qas": [{"question": "What what decoration had the most volume??", "id": "254980036", "answers": [{"text": "the castle"}]}]}, {"background": "Human beings invented agriculture about 10,000 years ago. This provided a bigger, more dependable food supply. It also allowed people to settle down in villages and cities for the first time. Birth rates went up because there was more food and settled life had other advantages. Death rates also rose because of crowded living conditions and diseases that spread from domestic animals. Because the higher birth rates were matched by higher death rates, the human population continued to grow very slowly.", "situation": "As people moved into the area and developed it. The rodents in the area found that human agriculture and waste from urban areas greatly increased the amount of food available to them. On the other hand humans brought a new predator with them in the form of house cats who quickly added the rodents to their menu.", "qas": [{"question": "Will an increase in food increase or decrease the rodent population?", "id": "3641393713", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "Human beings invented agriculture about 10,000 years ago. This provided a bigger, more dependable food supply. It also allowed people to settle down in villages and cities for the first time. Birth rates went up because there was more food and settled life had other advantages. Death rates also rose because of crowded living conditions and diseases that spread from domestic animals. Because the higher birth rates were matched by higher death rates, the human population continued to grow very slowly.", "situation": "As people moved into the area and developed it. The rodents in the area found that human agriculture and waste from urban areas greatly increased the amount of food available to them. On the other hand humans brought a new predator with them in the form of house cats who quickly added the rodents to their menu.", "qas": [{"question": "With more food will birth rates increase or decrease among rodents??", "id": "3841868320", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "Human beings invented agriculture about 10,000 years ago. This provided a bigger, more dependable food supply. It also allowed people to settle down in villages and cities for the first time. Birth rates went up because there was more food and settled life had other advantages. Death rates also rose because of crowded living conditions and diseases that spread from domestic animals. Because the higher birth rates were matched by higher death rates, the human population continued to grow very slowly.", "situation": "As people moved into the area and developed it. The rodents in the area found that human agriculture and waste from urban areas greatly increased the amount of food available to them. On the other hand humans brought a new predator with them in the form of house cats who quickly added the rodents to their menu.", "qas": [{"question": "With more predatorscause the death rate to increase or decrease? the roden?", "id": "3439477931", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "Human beings invented agriculture about 10,000 years ago. This provided a bigger, more dependable food supply. It also allowed people to settle down in villages and cities for the first time. Birth rates went up because there was more food and settled life had other advantages. Death rates also rose because of crowded living conditions and diseases that spread from domestic animals. Because the higher birth rates were matched by higher death rates, the human population continued to grow very slowly.", "situation": "As people moved into the area and developed it. The rodents in the area found that human agriculture and waste from urban areas greatly increased the amount of food available to them. On the other hand humans brought a new predator with them in the form of house cats who quickly added the rodents to their menu.", "qas": [{"question": "Will new predators cause an increase or decrease in the population?? the roden?", "id": "3577300473", "answers": [{"text": "decrease"}]}]}, {"background": "Human beings invented agriculture about 10,000 years ago. This provided a bigger, more dependable food supply. It also allowed people to settle down in villages and cities for the first time. Birth rates went up because there was more food and settled life had other advantages. Death rates also rose because of crowded living conditions and diseases that spread from domestic animals. Because the higher birth rates were matched by higher death rates, the human population continued to grow very slowly.", "situation": "As people moved into the area and developed it. The rodents in the area found that human agriculture and waste from urban areas greatly increased the amount of food available to them. On the other hand humans brought a new predator with them in the form of house cats who quickly added the rodents to their menu.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the over all population increase, decrease or stay the same with both more food and more predators?", "id": "494489396", "answers": [{"text": "stay the same"}]}]}, {"background": "Human beings invented agriculture about 10,000 years ago. This provided a bigger, more dependable food supply. It also allowed people to settle down in villages and cities for the first time. Birth rates went up because there was more food and settled life had other advantages. Death rates also rose because of crowded living conditions and diseases that spread from domestic animals. Because the higher birth rates were matched by higher death rates, the human population continued to grow very slowly.", "situation": "As people moved into the area and developed it. The rodents in the area found that human agriculture and waste from urban areas greatly increased the amount of food available to them. On the other hand humans brought a new predator with them in the form of house cats who quickly added the rodents to their menu.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the rodent population stable or unstable?", "id": "481376656", "answers": [{"text": "stable"}]}]}, {"background": "A baby is born with zones of cartilage in its bones that allow growth of the bones. These areas, called growth plates , allow the bones to grow longer as the child grows. By the time the child reaches an age of about 18 to 25 years, all of the cartilage in the growth plate has been replaced by bone. This stops the bone from growing any longer. Even though bones stop growing in length in early adulthood, they can continue to increase in thickness throughout life. This thickening occurs in response to strain from increased muscle activity and from weight-lifting exercises.", "situation": "Sam was always tall for his age. When he born was 21.5 inches long. By the time he was 1 he was 33 inches long. All the way through school he was always the tallest kid in his school. by high school he was was in high school he was 6ft 4 inches tall and finally stopped growing. He was self conscious about his height when he was a kid but know that he was 30 he embraces it as part of who he is.", "qas": [{"question": "Where Sam's bones longer or shorter at 1 yr than when he was born?", "id": "1701933246", "answers": [{"text": "longer"}]}]}, {"background": "A baby is born with zones of cartilage in its bones that allow growth of the bones. These areas, called growth plates , allow the bones to grow longer as the child grows. By the time the child reaches an age of about 18 to 25 years, all of the cartilage in the growth plate has been replaced by bone. This stops the bone from growing any longer. Even though bones stop growing in length in early adulthood, they can continue to increase in thickness throughout life. This thickening occurs in response to strain from increased muscle activity and from weight-lifting exercises.", "situation": "Sam was always tall for his age. When he born was 21.5 inches long. By the time he was 1 he was 33 inches long. All the way through school he was always the tallest kid in his school. by high school he was was in high school he was 6ft 4 inches tall and finally stopped growing. He was self conscious about his height when he was a kid but know that he was 30 he embraces it as part of who he is.", "qas": [{"question": "Where Sam's bones longer or shorter at school age than when he was born?", "id": "563180375", "answers": [{"text": "longer"}]}]}, {"background": "A baby is born with zones of cartilage in its bones that allow growth of the bones. These areas, called growth plates , allow the bones to grow longer as the child grows. By the time the child reaches an age of about 18 to 25 years, all of the cartilage in the growth plate has been replaced by bone. This stops the bone from growing any longer. Even though bones stop growing in length in early adulthood, they can continue to increase in thickness throughout life. This thickening occurs in response to strain from increased muscle activity and from weight-lifting exercises.", "situation": "Sam was always tall for his age. When he was born he was 21.5 inches long. By the time he was 1 he was 33 inches long. All the way through school he was always the tallest kid in his school. by high school he was was in high school he was 6ft 4 inches tall and finally stopped growing. He was self conscious about his height when he was a kid but know that he was 30 and an adult he embraces it as part of who he is.", "qas": [{"question": "When does Sam have the least growth plates?", "id": "4005195775", "answers": [{"text": "adult"}]}]}, {"background": "A baby is born with zones of cartilage in its bones that allow growth of the bones. These areas, called growth plates , allow the bones to grow longer as the child grows. By the time the child reaches an age of about 18 to 25 years, all of the cartilage in the growth plate has been replaced by bone. This stops the bone from growing any longer. Even though bones stop growing in length in early adulthood, they can continue to increase in thickness throughout life. This thickening occurs in response to strain from increased muscle activity and from weight-lifting exercises.", "situation": "Sam was always tall for his age. When he was born he was 21.5 inches long. By the time he was 1 he was 33 inches long. All the way through school he was always the tallest kid in his school. by high school he was was in high school he was 6ft 4 inches tall and finally stopped growing. He was self conscious about his height when he was a kid but know that he was 30 and an adult he embraces it as part of who he is.", "qas": [{"question": "When does Sam have the least cartilage zones?", "id": "3477500086", "answers": [{"text": "adult"}]}]}, {"background": "Another thing we can see in this animation is that particles are constantly colliding with one another. One assumption that we make when talking about collisions between gas particles is that they are completely elastic collisions. In an elastic collision , momentum is conserved, which means that none of the kinetic energy of the colliding particles is lost in some other form (such as the emission of light). This makes sense, because if energy were lost in collisions, the speeds of the particles would gradually decrease over time, and eventually everything would condense down into a solid form.", "situation": "Sam was driving his new car to school when he realized that the front tire was low. He pulled into the gas station and used the pump to put air in the tire. With the tire fully inflated he headed off to school.", "qas": [{"question": "What molecules where colliding in the tire?", "id": "3507304466", "answers": [{"text": "air"}]}]}, {"background": "Another thing we can see in this animation is that particles are constantly colliding with one another. One assumption that we make when talking about collisions between gas particles is that they are completely elastic collisions. In an elastic collision , momentum is conserved, which means that none of the kinetic energy of the colliding particles is lost in some other form (such as the emission of light). This makes sense, because if energy were lost in collisions, the speeds of the particles would gradually decrease over time, and eventually everything would condense down into a solid form.", "situation": "Sam was driving his new car to school when he realized that the front tire was low. He pulled into the gas station and used the pump to put air in the tire. With the tire fully inflated he headed off to school.", "qas": [{"question": "What molecules where expanding in the tire?", "id": "3520018459", "answers": [{"text": "air"}]}]}, {"background": "Another thing we can see in this animation is that particles are constantly colliding with one another. One assumption that we make when talking about collisions between gas particles is that they are completely elastic collisions. In an elastic collision , momentum is conserved, which means that none of the kinetic energy of the colliding particles is lost in some other form (such as the emission of light). This makes sense, because if energy were lost in collisions, the speeds of the particles would gradually decrease over time, and eventually everything would condense down into a solid form.", "situation": "Sam was driving his new car to school when he realized that the front tire was low. He pulled into the gas station and used the pump to put air in the tire. With the tire fully inflated he headed off to school.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the air particles lossing or maintaining their energy?", "id": "1013071306", "answers": [{"text": "maintaining"}]}]}, {"background": "Another thing we can see in this animation is that particles are constantly colliding with one another. One assumption that we make when talking about collisions between gas particles is that they are completely elastic collisions. In an elastic collision , momentum is conserved, which means that none of the kinetic energy of the colliding particles is lost in some other form (such as the emission of light). This makes sense, because if energy were lost in collisions, the speeds of the particles would gradually decrease over time, and eventually everything would condense down into a solid form.", "situation": "Sam was driving his new car to school when he realized that the front tire was low. He pulled into the gas station and used the pump to put air in the tire. With the tire fully inflated he headed off to school.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the air particles lossing or maintaining their speed?", "id": "4269817169", "answers": [{"text": "maintaining"}]}]}, {"background": "A mutant recessive allele, such as the allele that causes sickle cell anemia (see Figure below and the link that follows), is not expressed in people who inherit just one copy of it. These people are called carriers . They do not have the disorder themselves, but they carry the mutant allele and can pass it to their offspring. Thus, the allele is likely to pass on to the next generation rather than die out. http://www.dnalc.org/resources/3d/17-sickle-cell.html", "situation": "Mike was packing to go to the hospital again. It seemed like he was always in the hospital. Neither Mikes mom or dad had cystic fibrosis but Mike had inherited it from both of them.", "qas": [{"question": "was Mike's dad a carrier of cystic fibrosis or non carrier?", "id": "4242406531", "answers": [{"text": "carrier"}]}]}, {"background": "A mutant recessive allele, such as the allele that causes sickle cell anemia (see Figure below and the link that follows), is not expressed in people who inherit just one copy of it. These people are called carriers . They do not have the disorder themselves, but they carry the mutant allele and can pass it to their offspring. Thus, the allele is likely to pass on to the next generation rather than die out. http://www.dnalc.org/resources/3d/17-sickle-cell.html", "situation": "Mike was packing to go to the hospital again. It seemed like he was always in the hospital. Neither Mikes mom or dad had cystic fibrosis but Mike had inherited it from both of them.", "qas": [{"question": "was Mike's mon a carrier of cystic fibrosis or non carrier?", "id": "50003108", "answers": [{"text": "carrier"}]}]}, {"background": "A mutant recessive allele, such as the allele that causes sickle cell anemia (see Figure below and the link that follows), is not expressed in people who inherit just one copy of it. These people are called carriers . They do not have the disorder themselves, but they carry the mutant allele and can pass it to their offspring. Thus, the allele is likely to pass on to the next generation rather than die out. http://www.dnalc.org/resources/3d/17-sickle-cell.html", "situation": "Mike was packing to go to the hospital again. It seemed like he was always in the hospital. Neither Mikes mom or dad had cystic fibrosis but Mike had inherited it from both of them.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the allele that causes cystic fibrosis recesive or dominate.", "id": "260570805", "answers": [{"text": "recesive"}]}]}, {"background": "A mutant recessive allele, such as the allele that causes sickle cell anemia (see Figure below and the link that follows), is not expressed in people who inherit just one copy of it. These people are called carriers . They do not have the disorder themselves, but they carry the mutant allele and can pass it to their offspring. Thus, the allele is likely to pass on to the next generation rather than die out. http://www.dnalc.org/resources/3d/17-sickle-cell.html", "situation": "Mike was packing to go to the hospital again. It seemed like he was always in the hospital. Neither Mikes mom or dad had cystic fibrosis but Mike had inherited it from both of them.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the allele for cystic fibrosis likely to be passed on or die out?", "id": "34930636", "answers": [{"text": "passed on"}]}]}, {"background": "Some mutations have a positive effect on the organism in which they occur. They are called beneficial mutations . They lead to new versions of proteins that help organisms adapt to changes in their environment. Beneficial mutations are essential for evolution to occur. They increase an organism\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s changes of surviving or reproducing, so they are likely to become more common over time. There are several well-known examples of beneficial mutations. Here are just two:", "situation": "Milk is good for us we all know that. While babies can digest milk there was a time when adults could not. But in areas where humans domesticated cattle and other animals that they could obtain milk from milk became an important part of their diet. This happened because a small population of people developed the ability to digest lactose and they passed it onto their children and now most people can digest milk even as adults.", "qas": [{"question": "What mutation accord?", "id": "3428143751", "answers": [{"text": "the ability to digest lactose"}]}]}, {"background": "Some mutations have a positive effect on the organism in which they occur. They are called beneficial mutations . They lead to new versions of proteins that help organisms adapt to changes in their environment. Beneficial mutations are essential for evolution to occur. They increase an organism\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s changes of surviving or reproducing, so they are likely to become more common over time. There are several well-known examples of beneficial mutations. Here are just two:", "situation": "Milk is good for us we all know that. While babies can digest milk there was a time when adults could not. But in areas where humans domesticated cattle and other animals that they could obtain milk from milk became an important part of their diet. This happened because a small population of people developed the ability to digest lactose and they passed it onto their children and now most people can digest milk even as adults.", "qas": [{"question": "Where people more or less likely to thrive if they could not digest lactose?", "id": "2957272732", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Some mutations have a positive effect on the organism in which they occur. They are called beneficial mutations . They lead to new versions of proteins that help organisms adapt to changes in their environment. Beneficial mutations are essential for evolution to occur. They increase an organism\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s changes of surviving or reproducing, so they are likely to become more common over time. There are several well-known examples of beneficial mutations. Here are just two:", "situation": "Milk is good for us we all know that. While babies can digest milk there was a time when adults could not. But in areas where humans domesticated cattle and other animals that they could obtain milk from milk became an important part of their diet. This happened because a small population of people developed the ability to digest lactose and they passed it onto their children and now most people can digest milk even as adults.", "qas": [{"question": "Were people more or less likely to thrive if they could digest lactose?", "id": "2972738755", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Some mutations have a positive effect on the organism in which they occur. They are called beneficial mutations . They lead to new versions of proteins that help organisms adapt to changes in their environment. Beneficial mutations are essential for evolution to occur. They increase an organism\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s changes of surviving or reproducing, so they are likely to become more common over time. There are several well-known examples of beneficial mutations. Here are just two:", "situation": "Milk is good for us we all know that. While babies can digest milk there was a time when adults could not. But in areas where humans domesticated cattle and other animals that they could obtain milk from milk became an important part of their diet. This happened because a small population of people developed the ability to digest lactose and they passed it onto their children and now most people can digest milk even as adults.", "qas": [{"question": "Were people more or less likely to reproduce if they could digest lactose?", "id": "3852297722", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Some mutations have a positive effect on the organism in which they occur. They are called beneficial mutations . They lead to new versions of proteins that help organisms adapt to changes in their environment. Beneficial mutations are essential for evolution to occur. They increase an organism\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s changes of surviving or reproducing, so they are likely to become more common over time. There are several well-known examples of beneficial mutations. Here are just two:", "situation": "Milk is good for us we all know that. While babies can digest milk there was a time when adults could not. But in areas where humans domesticated cattle and other animals that they could obtain milk from milk became an important part of their diet. This happened because a small population of people developed the ability to digest lactose and they passed it onto their children and now most people can digest milk even as adults.", "qas": [{"question": "Where people more or less likely to reproduce if they could not digest lactose?", "id": "3938805715", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Some mutations have a positive effect on the organism in which they occur. They are called beneficial mutations . They lead to new versions of proteins that help organisms adapt to changes in their environment. Beneficial mutations are essential for evolution to occur. They increase an organism\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s changes of surviving or reproducing, so they are likely to become more common over time. There are several well-known examples of beneficial mutations. Here are just two:", "situation": "Milk is good for us we all know that. While babies can digest milk there was a time when adults could not. But in areas where humans domesticated cattle and other animals that they could obtain milk from milk became an important part of their diet. This happened because a small population of people developed the ability to digest lactose and they passed it onto their children and now most people can digest milk even as adults.", "qas": [{"question": "Has Lactose tolerance become more or less common?", "id": "1565875353", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Some mutations have a positive effect on the organism in which they occur. They are called beneficial mutations . They lead to new versions of proteins that help organisms adapt to changes in their environment. Beneficial mutations are essential for evolution to occur. They increase an organism\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s changes of surviving or reproducing, so they are likely to become more common over time. There are several well-known examples of beneficial mutations. Here are just two:", "situation": "Milk is good for us we all know that. While babies can digest milk there was a time when adults could not. But in areas where humans domesticated cattle and other animals that they could obtain milk from milk became an important part of their diet. This happened because a small population of people developed the ability to digest lactose and they passed it onto their children and now most people can digest milk even as adults.", "qas": [{"question": "Has Lactose intolerance become more or less common?", "id": "456351088", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Some mutations have a positive effect on the organism in which they occur. They are called beneficial mutations . They lead to new versions of proteins that help organisms adapt to changes in their environment. Beneficial mutations are essential for evolution to occur. They increase an organism\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s changes of surviving or reproducing, so they are likely to become more common over time. There are several well-known examples of beneficial mutations. Here are just two:", "situation": "Milk is good for us we all know that. While babies can digest milk there was a time when adults could not. But in areas where humans domesticated cattle and other animals that they could obtain milk from milk became an important part of their diet. This happened because a small population of people developed the ability to digest lactose and they passed it onto their children and now most people can digest milk even as adults.", "qas": [{"question": "What developed as a result of domesticating cattle and goats?", "id": "3593822500", "answers": [{"text": "the ability to digest lactose"}]}]}, {"background": "Type 2 diabetes is much more common than type 1 diabetes. Type 2 diabetes occurs when body cells no longer respond normally to insulin. The pancreas still makes insulin, but the cells of the body can\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use it. Being overweight and having high blood pressure increase the chances of developing type 2 diabetes. This type of diabetes usually develops in adulthood. However, it is becoming more common in teens and children because more young people are overweight now than ever before.", "situation": "Mike's doctor had been warning him he needed to lose weight. now he was telling him that he had type 2 diabetes and needed to take insulin.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Mike's pancrease making insulin or not?", "id": "2212295085", "answers": [{"text": "making insulin"}]}]}, {"background": "Type 2 diabetes is much more common than type 1 diabetes. Type 2 diabetes occurs when body cells no longer respond normally to insulin. The pancreas still makes insulin, but the cells of the body can\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use it. Being overweight and having high blood pressure increase the chances of developing type 2 diabetes. This type of diabetes usually develops in adulthood. However, it is becoming more common in teens and children because more young people are overweight now than ever before.", "situation": "Mike's doctor had been warning him he needed to lose weight. now he was telling him that he had type 2 diabetes and needed to take insulin.", "qas": [{"question": "What can't Mike's cells use?", "id": "1775954965", "answers": [{"text": "insulin"}]}]}, {"background": "Type 2 diabetes is much more common than type 1 diabetes. Type 2 diabetes occurs when body cells no longer respond normally to insulin. The pancreas still makes insulin, but the cells of the body can\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use it. Being overweight and having high blood pressure increase the chances of developing type 2 diabetes. This type of diabetes usually develops in adulthood. However, it is becoming more common in teens and children because more young people are overweight now than ever before.", "situation": "Mike's doctor had been warning him he needed to lose weight. now he was telling him that he had type 2 diabetes and needed to take insulin.", "qas": [{"question": "What is Mike's body nolonger responding to?", "id": "2007233074", "answers": [{"text": "insulin"}]}]}, {"background": "Type 2 diabetes is much more common than type 1 diabetes. Type 2 diabetes occurs when body cells no longer respond normally to insulin. The pancreas still makes insulin, but the cells of the body can\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use it. Being overweight and having high blood pressure increase the chances of developing type 2 diabetes. This type of diabetes usually develops in adulthood. However, it is becoming more common in teens and children because more young people are overweight now than ever before.", "situation": "Beth had had diabetes since she was a young child and needed to take insulin every day. Her friend Jane had recently been diagnosed with diabetes. Her doctor had recommended that she make changes to her diet and try to lose weight.", "qas": [{"question": "Who has type 1 diabetes?", "id": "2090208354", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Type 2 diabetes is much more common than type 1 diabetes. Type 2 diabetes occurs when body cells no longer respond normally to insulin. The pancreas still makes insulin, but the cells of the body can\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use it. Being overweight and having high blood pressure increase the chances of developing type 2 diabetes. This type of diabetes usually develops in adulthood. However, it is becoming more common in teens and children because more young people are overweight now than ever before.", "situation": "Beth had had diabetes since she was a young child and needed to take insulin every day. Her friend Jane had recently been diagnosed with diabetes. Her doctor had recommended that she make changes to her diet and try to lose weight.", "qas": [{"question": "Who has type 2 diabetes?", "id": "2090929251", "answers": [{"text": "Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "Type 2 diabetes is much more common than type 1 diabetes. Type 2 diabetes occurs when body cells no longer respond normally to insulin. The pancreas still makes insulin, but the cells of the body can\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use it. Being overweight and having high blood pressure increase the chances of developing type 2 diabetes. This type of diabetes usually develops in adulthood. However, it is becoming more common in teens and children because more young people are overweight now than ever before.", "situation": "Beth had had diabetes since she was a young child and needed to take insulin every day. Her friend Jane had recently been diagnosed with diabetes. Her doctor had recommended that she make changes to her diet and try to lose weight.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose body doesn't produce insulin?", "id": "722866464", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Type 2 diabetes is much more common than type 1 diabetes. Type 2 diabetes occurs when body cells no longer respond normally to insulin. The pancreas still makes insulin, but the cells of the body can\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t use it. Being overweight and having high blood pressure increase the chances of developing type 2 diabetes. This type of diabetes usually develops in adulthood. However, it is becoming more common in teens and children because more young people are overweight now than ever before.", "situation": "Beth had had diabetes since she was a young child and needed to take insulin every day. Her friend Jane had recently been diagnosed with diabetes. Her doctor had recommended that she make changes to her diet and try to lose weight.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose body doesn't use insulin?", "id": "4111011739", "answers": [{"text": "Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "The Keystone XL Pipeline would transport oil from the oil sands in Alberta, Canada. The oil would travel into the United States. In the U.S. it would be refined. The pipeline is controversial. A leak could cause damage to wildlife habitat. A leak could also release enough oil to contaminate the Ogallala Aquifer. The Aquifer is crucial to agriculture and urban development in the Midwestern U.S. When burned, the fuel from the oil sands would increase pollutants. Greenhouse gases into the atmosphere would increase. The future of the pipeline is currently on hold.", "situation": "Lisa's family owns an oil company. She was pleased to find out that the Keystone XL Pipeline might start transporting oil to the U.S soon. She knows some people have opposed the pipeline but she thinks it is good because it will lower gas prices for consumers.", "qas": [{"question": "What could cause damage to wildlife?", "id": "3948296069", "answers": [{"text": "Keystone XL Pipeline"}]}]}, {"background": "The Keystone XL Pipeline would transport oil from the oil sands in Alberta, Canada. The oil would travel into the United States. In the U.S. it would be refined. The pipeline is controversial. A leak could cause damage to wildlife habitat. A leak could also release enough oil to contaminate the Ogallala Aquifer. The Aquifer is crucial to agriculture and urban development in the Midwestern U.S. When burned, the fuel from the oil sands would increase pollutants. Greenhouse gases into the atmosphere would increase. The future of the pipeline is currently on hold.", "situation": "Lisa's family owns an oil company. She was pleased to find out that the Keystone XL Pipeline might start transporting oil to the U.S soon. She knows some people have opposed the pipeline especial in the Midwest but she thinks it is good because it will lower gas prices for consumers.", "qas": [{"question": "Where does the pipleline threaten agriculture?", "id": "4078847101", "answers": [{"text": "the Midwest"}]}]}, {"background": "The Keystone XL Pipeline would transport oil from the oil sands in Alberta, Canada. The oil would travel into the United States. In the U.S. it would be refined. The pipeline is controversial. A leak could cause damage to wildlife habitat. A leak could also release enough oil to contaminate the Ogallala Aquifer. The Aquifer is crucial to agriculture and urban development in the Midwestern U.S. When burned, the fuel from the oil sands would increase pollutants. Greenhouse gases into the atmosphere would increase. The future of the pipeline is currently on hold.", "situation": "Lisa's family owns an oil company. She was pleased to find out that the Keystone XL Pipeline might start transporting oil to the U.S soon. She knows some people have opposed the pipeline especial in the Midwest but she thinks it is good because it will lower gas prices for consumers.", "qas": [{"question": "What might contaminate the Ogallala Aquifer?", "id": "1765032765", "answers": [{"text": "oil"}]}]}, {"background": "Scientists think that the earliest flowers attracted insects and other animals, which spread pollen from flower to flower. This greatly increased the efficiency of fertilization over wind-spread pollen, which might or might not actually land on another flower. To take better advantage of this \u00e2\u20ac\u0153animal labor,\u00e2\u20ac\u009d plants evolved traits such as brightly colored petals to attract pollinators. In exchange for pollination, flowers gave the pollinators nectar.", "situation": "Ben wanted to encourage bees to visit his garden so he planted lots of blue, purple, and yellow flowers and plants to attract them. He also chose plants the bees would think smelled good.", "qas": [{"question": "Do bees harm or benefit plants?", "id": "2597583592", "answers": [{"text": "benefit"}]}]}, {"background": "Scientists think that the earliest flowers attracted insects and other animals, which spread pollen from flower to flower. This greatly increased the efficiency of fertilization over wind-spread pollen, which might or might not actually land on another flower. To take better advantage of this \u00e2\u20ac\u0153animal labor,\u00e2\u20ac\u009d plants evolved traits such as brightly colored petals to attract pollinators. In exchange for pollination, flowers gave the pollinators nectar.", "situation": "Ben wanted to encourage bees to visit his garden so he planted lots of blue, purple, and yellow flowers and plants to attract them. He also chose plants the bees would think smelled good.", "qas": [{"question": "Do plants need or tolerate bees?", "id": "2620652383", "answers": [{"text": "need"}]}]}, {"background": "Scientists think that the earliest flowers attracted insects and other animals, which spread pollen from flower to flower. This greatly increased the efficiency of fertilization over wind-spread pollen, which might or might not actually land on another flower. To take better advantage of this \u00e2\u20ac\u0153animal labor,\u00e2\u20ac\u009d plants evolved traits such as brightly colored petals to attract pollinators. In exchange for pollination, flowers gave the pollinators nectar.", "situation": "Ben wanted to encourage bees to visit his garden. He new color and scent were important for attracting bees, so he planted lots of blue, purple, and yellow flowers and plants to attract them. He also chose plants the bees would think smelled good.", "qas": [{"question": "What traits do plants use to attract bees?", "id": "3732018407", "answers": [{"text": "color and scent"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, nearsightedness first occurs in school-age children. There is some evidence that myopia is inherited. If one or both of your parents need glasses, there is an increased chance that you will too. Individuals who spend a lot of time reading, working or playing at a computer, or doing other close visual work may also be more likely to develop nearsightedness. Because the eye continues to grow during childhood, myopia typically progresses until about age 20. However, nearsightedness may also develop in adults due to visual stress or health conditions such as diabetes. A common sign of nearsightedness is difficulty seeing distant objects like a movie screen or the TV, or the whiteboard or chalkboard in school.", "situation": "Beth loved to do needle point in her spare time. Her mother had daughter when she was a child and she found it very relaxing. Lately though she was having trouble seeing some of the smaller work and found she had to hold it much closer than usual. Her daughter Sue had been complaining that she could not see the board at school from the back of the room despite getting new glasses last year. Beth decided it was time to make appointments for them at the eye doctors.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Beth nearsighted or farsighted?", "id": "8175204", "answers": [{"text": "nearsighted"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, nearsightedness first occurs in school-age children. There is some evidence that myopia is inherited. If one or both of your parents need glasses, there is an increased chance that you will too. Individuals who spend a lot of time reading, working or playing at a computer, or doing other close visual work may also be more likely to develop nearsightedness. Because the eye continues to grow during childhood, myopia typically progresses until about age 20. However, nearsightedness may also develop in adults due to visual stress or health conditions such as diabetes. A common sign of nearsightedness is difficulty seeing distant objects like a movie screen or the TV, or the whiteboard or chalkboard in school.", "situation": "Beth loved to do needle point in her spare time. Her mother had daughter when she was a child and she found it very relaxing. Lately though she was having trouble seeing some of the smaller work and found she had to hold it much closer than usual. Her daughter Sue had been complaining that she could not see the board at school from the back of the room despite getting new glasses last year. Beth decided it was time to make appointments for them at the eye doctors.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Sue nearsighted or farsighted?", "id": "1131068942", "answers": [{"text": "nearsighted"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, nearsightedness first occurs in school-age children. There is some evidence that myopia is inherited. If one or both of your parents need glasses, there is an increased chance that you will too. Individuals who spend a lot of time reading, working or playing at a computer, or doing other close visual work may also be more likely to develop nearsightedness. Because the eye continues to grow during childhood, myopia typically progresses until about age 20. However, nearsightedness may also develop in adults due to visual stress or health conditions such as diabetes. A common sign of nearsightedness is difficulty seeing distant objects like a movie screen or the TV, or the whiteboard or chalkboard in school.", "situation": "Beth loved to do needle point in her spare time. Her mother had daughter when she was a child and she found it very relaxing. Lately though she was having trouble seeing some of the smaller work and found she had to hold it much closer than usual. Her daughter Sue had been complaining that she could not see the board at school from the back of the room despite getting new glasses last year. Beth decided it was time to make appointments for them at the eye doctors.", "qas": [{"question": "What was stressing Beth's eyes?", "id": "3425484073", "answers": [{"text": "needle point"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, nearsightedness first occurs in school-age children. There is some evidence that myopia is inherited. If one or both of your parents need glasses, there is an increased chance that you will too. Individuals who spend a lot of time reading, working or playing at a computer, or doing other close visual work may also be more likely to develop nearsightedness. Because the eye continues to grow during childhood, myopia typically progresses until about age 20. However, nearsightedness may also develop in adults due to visual stress or health conditions such as diabetes. A common sign of nearsightedness is difficulty seeing distant objects like a movie screen or the TV, or the whiteboard or chalkboard in school.", "situation": "Beth loved to do needle point in her spare time. Her mother had daughter when she was a child and she found it very relaxing. Lately though she was having trouble seeing some of the smaller work and found she had to hold it much closer than usual. Her daughter Sue had been complaining that she could not see the board at school from the back of the room despite getting new glasses last year. Beth decided it was time to make appointments for them at the eye doctors.", "qas": [{"question": "Where Sue's eyes better or worse a year ago?", "id": "2103230829", "answers": [{"text": "better"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, nearsightedness first occurs in school-age children. There is some evidence that myopia is inherited. If one or both of your parents need glasses, there is an increased chance that you will too. Individuals who spend a lot of time reading, working or playing at a computer, or doing other close visual work may also be more likely to develop nearsightedness. Because the eye continues to grow during childhood, myopia typically progresses until about age 20. However, nearsightedness may also develop in adults due to visual stress or health conditions such as diabetes. A common sign of nearsightedness is difficulty seeing distant objects like a movie screen or the TV, or the whiteboard or chalkboard in school.", "situation": "Beth loved to do needle point in her spare time. Her mother had daughter when she was a child and she found it very relaxing. Lately though she was having trouble seeing some of the smaller work and found she had to hold it much closer than usual. Her daughter Sue had been complaining that she could not see the board at school from the back of the room despite getting new glasses last year. Beth decided it was time to make appointments for them at the eye doctors.", "qas": [{"question": "Are Sue's eyes better or worse than a year ago?", "id": "3170943573", "answers": [{"text": "worse"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, nearsightedness first occurs in school-age children. There is some evidence that myopia is inherited. If one or both of your parents need glasses, there is an increased chance that you will too. Individuals who spend a lot of time reading, working or playing at a computer, or doing other close visual work may also be more likely to develop nearsightedness. Because the eye continues to grow during childhood, myopia typically progresses until about age 20. However, nearsightedness may also develop in adults due to visual stress or health conditions such as diabetes. A common sign of nearsightedness is difficulty seeing distant objects like a movie screen or the TV, or the whiteboard or chalkboard in school.", "situation": "Beth loved to do needle point in her spare time. Her mother had daughter when she was a child and she found it very relaxing. Lately though she was having trouble seeing some of the smaller work and found she had to hold it much closer than usual. Her daughter Sue had been complaining that she could not see the board at school from the back of the room despite getting new glasses last year. Beth decided it was time to make appointments for them at the eye doctors.", "qas": [{"question": "Are Sues eyes getting better or worse?", "id": "4251828172", "answers": [{"text": "worse"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, nearsightedness first occurs in school-age children. There is some evidence that myopia is inherited. If one or both of your parents need glasses, there is an increased chance that you will too. Individuals who spend a lot of time reading, working or playing at a computer, or doing other close visual work may also be more likely to develop nearsightedness. Because the eye continues to grow during childhood, myopia typically progresses until about age 20. However, nearsightedness may also develop in adults due to visual stress or health conditions such as diabetes. A common sign of nearsightedness is difficulty seeing distant objects like a movie screen or the TV, or the whiteboard or chalkboard in school.", "situation": "Beth loved to do needle point in her spare time. Her mother had daughter when she was a child and she found it very relaxing. Lately though she was having trouble seeing some of the smaller work and found she had to hold it much closer than usual. Her daughter Sue had been complaining that she could not see the board at school from the back of the room despite getting new glasses last year. Beth decided it was time to make appointments for them at the eye doctors.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Sue's myopia getting better or worse?", "id": "2049622128", "answers": [{"text": "worse"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, nearsightedness first occurs in school-age children. There is some evidence that myopia is inherited. If one or both of your parents need glasses, there is an increased chance that you will too. Individuals who spend a lot of time reading, working or playing at a computer, or doing other close visual work may also be more likely to develop nearsightedness. Because the eye continues to grow during childhood, myopia typically progresses until about age 20. However, nearsightedness may also develop in adults due to visual stress or health conditions such as diabetes. A common sign of nearsightedness is difficulty seeing distant objects like a movie screen or the TV, or the whiteboard or chalkboard in school.", "situation": "Beth loved to do needle point in her spare time. Her mother had daughter when she was a child and she found it very relaxing. Lately though she was having trouble seeing some of the smaller work and found she had to hold it much closer than usual. Her daughter Sue had been complaining that she could not see the board at school from the back of the room despite getting new glasses last year. Beth decided it was time to make appointments for them at the eye doctors.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Beth developing myopia yes or no?", "id": "2122956511", "answers": [{"text": "yes"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, nearsightedness first occurs in school-age children. There is some evidence that myopia is inherited. If one or both of your parents need glasses, there is an increased chance that you will too. Individuals who spend a lot of time reading, working or playing at a computer, or doing other close visual work may also be more likely to develop nearsightedness. Because the eye continues to grow during childhood, myopia typically progresses until about age 20. However, nearsightedness may also develop in adults due to visual stress or health conditions such as diabetes. A common sign of nearsightedness is difficulty seeing distant objects like a movie screen or the TV, or the whiteboard or chalkboard in school.", "situation": "Beth loved to do needle point in her spare time. Her mother had daughter when she was a child and she found it very relaxing. Lately though she was having trouble seeing some of the smaller work and found she had to hold it much closer than usual. Her daughter Sue had been complaining that she could not see the board at school from the back of the room despite getting new glasses last year. Beth decided it was time to make appointments for them at the eye doctors.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is developing myopia due to visual stress?", "id": "302891796", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, nearsightedness first occurs in school-age children. There is some evidence that myopia is inherited. If one or both of your parents need glasses, there is an increased chance that you will too. Individuals who spend a lot of time reading, working or playing at a computer, or doing other close visual work may also be more likely to develop nearsightedness. Because the eye continues to grow during childhood, myopia typically progresses until about age 20. However, nearsightedness may also develop in adults due to visual stress or health conditions such as diabetes. A common sign of nearsightedness is difficulty seeing distant objects like a movie screen or the TV, or the whiteboard or chalkboard in school.", "situation": "Beth loved to do needle point in her spare time. Her mother had daughter when she was a child and she found it very relaxing. Lately though she was having trouble seeing some of the smaller work and found she had to hold it much closer than usual. Her daughter Sue had been complaining that she could not see the board at school from the back of the room despite getting new glasses last year. Beth decided it was time to make appointments for them at the eye doctors.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's myopia is getting worse?", "id": "193641706", "answers": [{"text": "Sue"}]}]}, {"background": "New species develop naturally through the process of natural selection . Due to natural selection, organisms with traits that better enable them to adapt to their environment will tend to survive and reproduce in greater numbers. Natural selection causes beneficial heritable traits to become more common in a population and unfavorable heritable traits to become less common. For example, a giraffe\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s neck is beneficial because it allows the giraffe to reach leaves high in trees. Natural selection caused this beneficial trait to become more common than short necks.", "situation": "When visiting the Galapagos islands Beth was fascinated by the many species of finches. Each had different sides beaks and had carved out its on habitat on the island eating the seeds that were available there. Each one seemed to have the size beak that was perfect for the seeds it ate.", "qas": [{"question": "Were finches with a certain size beak more or less likely to survive??", "id": "1880577116", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "New species develop naturally through the process of natural selection . Due to natural selection, organisms with traits that better enable them to adapt to their environment will tend to survive and reproduce in greater numbers. Natural selection causes beneficial heritable traits to become more common in a population and unfavorable heritable traits to become less common. For example, a giraffe\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s neck is beneficial because it allows the giraffe to reach leaves high in trees. Natural selection caused this beneficial trait to become more common than short necks.", "situation": "When visiting the Galapagos islands Beth was fascinated by the many species of finches. Each had different sides beaks and had carved out its on habitat on the island eating the seeds that were available there. Each one seemed to have the size beak that was perfect for the seeds it ate.", "qas": [{"question": "Were finches with a certain size beak more or less likely to find food?", "id": "3257029746", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "New species develop naturally through the process of natural selection . Due to natural selection, organisms with traits that better enable them to adapt to their environment will tend to survive and reproduce in greater numbers. Natural selection causes beneficial heritable traits to become more common in a population and unfavorable heritable traits to become less common. For example, a giraffe\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s neck is beneficial because it allows the giraffe to reach leaves high in trees. Natural selection caused this beneficial trait to become more common than short necks.", "situation": "When visiting the Galapagos islands Beth was fascinated by the many species of finches. Each had different sides beaks and had carved out its on habitat on the island eating the seeds that were available there. Each one seemed to have the size beak that was perfect for the seeds it ate.", "qas": [{"question": "Were finches with optimal sized beaks more or less likely to pass on genes", "id": "3607123478", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "New species develop naturally through the process of natural selection . Due to natural selection, organisms with traits that better enable them to adapt to their environment will tend to survive and reproduce in greater numbers. Natural selection causes beneficial heritable traits to become more common in a population and unfavorable heritable traits to become less common. For example, a giraffe\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s neck is beneficial because it allows the giraffe to reach leaves high in trees. Natural selection caused this beneficial trait to become more common than short necks.", "situation": "When visiting the Galapagos islands Beth was fascinated by the many species of finches. Each had different sides beaks and had carved out its on habitat on the island eating the seeds that were available there. Each one seemed to have the size beak that was perfect for the seeds it ate.", "qas": [{"question": "Were finches without optimal sized beaks more or less likely to pass on genes", "id": "3926480750", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "New species develop naturally through the process of natural selection . Due to natural selection, organisms with traits that better enable them to adapt to their environment will tend to survive and reproduce in greater numbers. Natural selection causes beneficial heritable traits to become more common in a population and unfavorable heritable traits to become less common. For example, a giraffe\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s neck is beneficial because it allows the giraffe to reach leaves high in trees. Natural selection caused this beneficial trait to become more common than short necks.", "situation": "When visiting the Galapagos islands Beth was fascinated by the many species of finches. Each had different sides beaks and had carved out its on habitat on the island eating the seeds that were available there. Each one seemed to have the size beak that was perfect for the seeds it ate.", "qas": [{"question": "Were finches without optimal sized beaks more or less likely to survive", "id": "3843642780", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "New species develop naturally through the process of natural selection . Due to natural selection, organisms with traits that better enable them to adapt to their environment will tend to survive and reproduce in greater numbers. Natural selection causes beneficial heritable traits to become more common in a population and unfavorable heritable traits to become less common. For example, a giraffe\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s neck is beneficial because it allows the giraffe to reach leaves high in trees. Natural selection caused this beneficial trait to become more common than short necks.", "situation": "When visiting the Galapagos islands Beth was fascinated by the many species of finches. Each had different sides beaks and had carved out its on habitat on the island eating the seeds that were available there. Each one seemed to have the size beak that was perfect for the seeds it ate.", "qas": [{"question": "Were finches without optimal sized beaks more or less likely to find food", "id": "2394314225", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "New species develop naturally through the process of natural selection . Due to natural selection, organisms with traits that better enable them to adapt to their environment will tend to survive and reproduce in greater numbers. Natural selection causes beneficial heritable traits to become more common in a population and unfavorable heritable traits to become less common. For example, a giraffe\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s neck is beneficial because it allows the giraffe to reach leaves high in trees. Natural selection caused this beneficial trait to become more common than short necks.", "situation": "When visiting the Galapagos islands Beth was fascinated by the many species of finches. Each had different sides beaks and had carved out its on habitat on the island eating the seeds that were available there. Each one seemed to have the size beak that was perfect for the seeds it ate.", "qas": [{"question": "Are beak sizes random or a response to the environment?", "id": "2693156625", "answers": [{"text": "response to the environment"}]}]}, {"background": "New species develop naturally through the process of natural selection . Due to natural selection, organisms with traits that better enable them to adapt to their environment will tend to survive and reproduce in greater numbers. Natural selection causes beneficial heritable traits to become more common in a population and unfavorable heritable traits to become less common. For example, a giraffe\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s neck is beneficial because it allows the giraffe to reach leaves high in trees. Natural selection caused this beneficial trait to become more common than short necks.", "situation": "When visiting the Galapagos islands Beth was fascinated by the many species of finches. Each had different sides beaks and had carved out its on habitat on the island eating the seeds that were available there. Each one seemed to have the size beak that was perfect for the seeds it ate.", "qas": [{"question": "Would finches from one island thrive or struggle on another?", "id": "1191137591", "answers": [{"text": "struggle"}]}]}, {"background": "New species develop naturally through the process of natural selection . Due to natural selection, organisms with traits that better enable them to adapt to their environment will tend to survive and reproduce in greater numbers. Natural selection causes beneficial heritable traits to become more common in a population and unfavorable heritable traits to become less common. For example, a giraffe\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s neck is beneficial because it allows the giraffe to reach leaves high in trees. Natural selection caused this beneficial trait to become more common than short necks.", "situation": "When visiting the Galapagos islands Beth was fascinated by the many species of finches. Each had different sides beaks and had carved out its on habitat on the island eating the seeds that were available there. Each one seemed to have the size beak that was perfect for the seeds it ate.", "qas": [{"question": "Is each species of finch able to thrive only on their island or anywhere??", "id": "2990626181", "answers": [{"text": "on their island"}]}]}, {"background": "New species develop naturally through the process of natural selection . Due to natural selection, organisms with traits that better enable them to adapt to their environment will tend to survive and reproduce in greater numbers. Natural selection causes beneficial heritable traits to become more common in a population and unfavorable heritable traits to become less common. For example, a giraffe\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s neck is beneficial because it allows the giraffe to reach leaves high in trees. Natural selection caused this beneficial trait to become more common than short necks.", "situation": "When visiting the Galapagos islands Beth was fascinated by the many species of finches. Each had different sides beaks and had carved out its on habitat on the island eating the seeds that were available there. Each one seemed to have the size beak that was perfect for the seeds it ate.", "qas": [{"question": "Will a change in available food cause finches to thrive or struggle???", "id": "1671058462", "answers": [{"text": "struggle"}]}]}, {"background": "As new changes in the DNA sequence are constantly being generated in a population's gene pool (changing the population's allele frequencies), some of these changes will be beneficial and result in traits that allow adaptation and survival. Natural selection causes evolution of a species as these beneficial traits become more common within a population. Evolution can occur within a species without completely resulting in a new species. Therefore, evolution and speciation are not the same.", "situation": "In population of mice, young mice could be born with one of three colors. They were born with grey, black or white fur. Initially the color was random. However black coloring made the mice easy targets for fox and cats during the day while white coloring made them easy targets for owls at night.", "qas": [{"question": "Which colors were a disadvantage?", "id": "4027853951", "answers": [{"text": "black or white"}]}]}, {"background": "As new changes in the DNA sequence are constantly being generated in a population's gene pool (changing the population's allele frequencies), some of these changes will be beneficial and result in traits that allow adaptation and survival. Natural selection causes evolution of a species as these beneficial traits become more common within a population. Evolution can occur within a species without completely resulting in a new species. Therefore, evolution and speciation are not the same.", "situation": "In population of mice, young mice could be born with one of three colors. They were born with grey, black or white fur. Initially the color was random. However black coloring made the mice easy targets for fox and cats during the day while white coloring made them easy targets for owls at night.", "qas": [{"question": "Which color mouse was least likely to reproduce?", "id": "3112251952", "answers": [{"text": "black or white"}]}]}, {"background": "As new changes in the DNA sequence are constantly being generated in a population's gene pool (changing the population's allele frequencies), some of these changes will be beneficial and result in traits that allow adaptation and survival. Natural selection causes evolution of a species as these beneficial traits become more common within a population. Evolution can occur within a species without completely resulting in a new species. Therefore, evolution and speciation are not the same.", "situation": "In population of mice, young mice could be born with one of three colors. They were born with grey, black or white fur. Initially the color was random. However black coloring made the mice easy targets for fox and cats during the day while white coloring made them easy targets for owls at night.", "qas": [{"question": "Which color mouse was most least likely to pass on genes?", "id": "2323002672", "answers": [{"text": "black or white"}]}]}, {"background": "As new changes in the DNA sequence are constantly being generated in a population's gene pool (changing the population's allele frequencies), some of these changes will be beneficial and result in traits that allow adaptation and survival. Natural selection causes evolution of a species as these beneficial traits become more common within a population. Evolution can occur within a species without completely resulting in a new species. Therefore, evolution and speciation are not the same.", "situation": "In population of mice, young mice could be born with one of three colors. They were born with grey, black or white fur. Initially the color was random. However black coloring made the mice easy targets for fox and cats during the day while white coloring made them easy targets for owls at night.", "qas": [{"question": "What color mouse would become less common over time?", "id": "2276799384", "answers": [{"text": "black or white"}]}]}, {"background": "As new changes in the DNA sequence are constantly being generated in a population's gene pool (changing the population's allele frequencies), some of these changes will be beneficial and result in traits that allow adaptation and survival. Natural selection causes evolution of a species as these beneficial traits become more common within a population. Evolution can occur within a species without completely resulting in a new species. Therefore, evolution and speciation are not the same.", "situation": "In population of mice, young mice could be born with one of three colors. They were born with grey, black or white fur. Initially the color was random. However black coloring made the mice easy targets for fox and cats during the day while white coloring made them easy targets for owls at night.", "qas": [{"question": "What color mouse was favored by natural selection?", "id": "525021953", "answers": [{"text": "grey"}]}]}, {"background": "As new changes in the DNA sequence are constantly being generated in a population's gene pool (changing the population's allele frequencies), some of these changes will be beneficial and result in traits that allow adaptation and survival. Natural selection causes evolution of a species as these beneficial traits become more common within a population. Evolution can occur within a species without completely resulting in a new species. Therefore, evolution and speciation are not the same.", "situation": "In population of mice, young mice could be born with one of three colors. They were born with grey, black or white fur. Initially the color was random. However black coloring made the mice easy targets for fox and cats during the day while white coloring made them easy targets for owls at night.", "qas": [{"question": "Were the grey mice a new or the same species?", "id": "243937315", "answers": [{"text": "same species"}]}]}, {"background": "The parts of the ears involved in balance are the semicircular canals. These are the curved structures above the cochlea in the inner ear in Figure above . Like the cochlea, the semicircular canals contain liquid and are lined with tiny hair cells. As the head changes position, the liquid moves. This causes the hair cells to bend. The bending of the hair cells triggers nerve impulses that travel to the cerebellum in the brain. The cerebellum uses the information to maintain balance.", "situation": "Some people think Rock Music is just loud noise but Sam loves it. Sam liked going to Rock concert when he was younger. In his opinion the louder the better. Unfortunately over the years Sam's hearing has declined and he has trouble hearing the music he loves so much.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Sam's balance problem temerary or permanant?", "id": "3857850763", "answers": [{"text": "permanant"}]}]}, {"background": "The parts of the ears involved in balance are the semicircular canals. These are the curved structures above the cochlea in the inner ear in Figure above . Like the cochlea, the semicircular canals contain liquid and are lined with tiny hair cells. As the head changes position, the liquid moves. This causes the hair cells to bend. The bending of the hair cells triggers nerve impulses that travel to the cerebellum in the brain. The cerebellum uses the information to maintain balance.", "situation": "Some people think Rock Music is just loud noise but Sam loves it. Sam liked going to Rock concert when he was younger. In his opinion the louder the better. Unfortunately over the years Sam's hearing has declined and he has trouble hearing the music he loves so much.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the hair cells in Sam's cochlea normal or damaged?", "id": "3427083083", "answers": [{"text": "damaged"}]}]}, {"background": "The parts of the ears involved in balance are the semicircular canals. These are the curved structures above the cochlea in the inner ear in Figure above . Like the cochlea, the semicircular canals contain liquid and are lined with tiny hair cells. As the head changes position, the liquid moves. This causes the hair cells to bend. The bending of the hair cells triggers nerve impulses that travel to the cerebellum in the brain. The cerebellum uses the information to maintain balance.", "situation": "Some people think Rock Music is just loud noise but Sam loves it. Sam liked going to Rock concert when he was younger. In his opinion the louder the better. Unfortunately over the years Sam's hearing has declined and he has trouble hearing the music he loves so much.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Sam's cerrabellum able or unable to get nerve pulses from the hair cells in his ear?", "id": "1076637532", "answers": [{"text": "unable"}]}]}, {"background": "Many different chemical substances cause cancer. Dozens of chemicals in tobacco smoke, including nicotine, have been shown to cause cancer ( Figure below ). In fact, tobacco smoke is one of the main sources of chemical carcinogens. Smoking tobacco increases the risk of cancer of the lung, mouth, throat, and bladder. Using smokeless tobacco can also cause cancer. Other chemicals that cause cancer include asbestos, formaldehyde, benzene, cadmium, and nickel.", "situation": "Three friends Mark, John and Sam have very different views on smoking. Mark has never smoked and doesn't see what people see in it. John and Same both smoke about the same each day but John likes traditional cigarettes. Sam on the other hand chooses to use smokeless tobacco products.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is at risk for lung cancer?", "id": "2279478990", "answers": [{"text": "John and Sam"}]}]}, {"background": "Many different chemical substances cause cancer. Dozens of chemicals in tobacco smoke, including nicotine, have been shown to cause cancer ( Figure below ). In fact, tobacco smoke is one of the main sources of chemical carcinogens. Smoking tobacco increases the risk of cancer of the lung, mouth, throat, and bladder. Using smokeless tobacco can also cause cancer. Other chemicals that cause cancer include asbestos, formaldehyde, benzene, cadmium, and nickel.", "situation": "Three friends Mark, John and Sam have very different views on smoking. Mark has never smoked and doesn't see what people see in it. John and Same both smoke about the same each day but John likes traditional cigarettes. Sam on the other hand chooses to use smokeless tobacco products.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is at lower risk for lung cancer?", "id": "452598039", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Many different chemical substances cause cancer. Dozens of chemicals in tobacco smoke, including nicotine, have been shown to cause cancer ( Figure below ). In fact, tobacco smoke is one of the main sources of chemical carcinogens. Smoking tobacco increases the risk of cancer of the lung, mouth, throat, and bladder. Using smokeless tobacco can also cause cancer. Other chemicals that cause cancer include asbestos, formaldehyde, benzene, cadmium, and nickel.", "situation": "Three friends Mark, John and Sam have very different views on smoking. Mark has never smoked and doesn't see what people see in it. John and Same both smoke about the same each day but John likes traditional cigarettes. Sam on the other hand chooses to use smokeless tobacco products.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is being exposed to chemical carcinogens?", "id": "4154858617", "answers": [{"text": "John and Sam"}]}]}, {"background": "Many different chemical substances cause cancer. Dozens of chemicals in tobacco smoke, including nicotine, have been shown to cause cancer ( Figure below ). In fact, tobacco smoke is one of the main sources of chemical carcinogens. Smoking tobacco increases the risk of cancer of the lung, mouth, throat, and bladder. Using smokeless tobacco can also cause cancer. Other chemicals that cause cancer include asbestos, formaldehyde, benzene, cadmium, and nickel.", "situation": "Three friends Mark, John and Sam have very different views on smoking. Mark has never smoked and doesn't see what people see in it. John and Same both smoke about the same each day but John likes traditional cigarettes. Sam on the other hand chooses to use smokeless tobacco products.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is not being exposed to chemical carcinogens?", "id": "1793596906", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Many different chemical substances cause cancer. Dozens of chemicals in tobacco smoke, including nicotine, have been shown to cause cancer ( Figure below ). In fact, tobacco smoke is one of the main sources of chemical carcinogens. Smoking tobacco increases the risk of cancer of the lung, mouth, throat, and bladder. Using smokeless tobacco can also cause cancer. Other chemicals that cause cancer include asbestos, formaldehyde, benzene, cadmium, and nickel.", "situation": "Three friends Mark, John and Sam have very different views on smoking. Mark has never smoked and doesn't see what people see in it. John and Same both smoke about the same each day but John likes traditional cigarettes. Sam on the other hand chooses to use smokeless tobacco products.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is at higher risk for mouth cancer?", "id": "1302665692", "answers": [{"text": "John and Sam"}]}]}, {"background": "Many different chemical substances cause cancer. Dozens of chemicals in tobacco smoke, including nicotine, have been shown to cause cancer ( Figure below ). In fact, tobacco smoke is one of the main sources of chemical carcinogens. Smoking tobacco increases the risk of cancer of the lung, mouth, throat, and bladder. Using smokeless tobacco can also cause cancer. Other chemicals that cause cancer include asbestos, formaldehyde, benzene, cadmium, and nickel.", "situation": "Three friends Mark, John and Sam have very different views on smoking. Mark has never smoked and doesn't see what people see in it. John and Same both smoke about the same each day but John likes traditional cigarettes. Sam on the other hand chooses to use smokeless tobacco products.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is at higher risk for throat cancer?", "id": "1747982913", "answers": [{"text": "John and Sam"}]}]}, {"background": "Many different chemical substances cause cancer. Dozens of chemicals in tobacco smoke, including nicotine, have been shown to cause cancer ( Figure below ). In fact, tobacco smoke is one of the main sources of chemical carcinogens. Smoking tobacco increases the risk of cancer of the lung, mouth, throat, and bladder. Using smokeless tobacco can also cause cancer. Other chemicals that cause cancer include asbestos, formaldehyde, benzene, cadmium, and nickel.", "situation": "Three friends Mark, John and Sam have very different views on smoking. Mark has never smoked and doesn't see what people see in it. John and Same both smoke about the same each day but John likes traditional cigarettes. Sam on the other hand chooses to use smokeless tobacco products.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is at higher risk for bladder cancer?", "id": "2164005501", "answers": [{"text": "John and Sam"}]}]}, {"background": "Many different chemical substances cause cancer. Dozens of chemicals in tobacco smoke, including nicotine, have been shown to cause cancer ( Figure below ). In fact, tobacco smoke is one of the main sources of chemical carcinogens. Smoking tobacco increases the risk of cancer of the lung, mouth, throat, and bladder. Using smokeless tobacco can also cause cancer. Other chemicals that cause cancer include asbestos, formaldehyde, benzene, cadmium, and nickel.", "situation": "Three friends Mark, John and Sam have very different views on smoking. Mark has never smoked and doesn't see what people see in it. John and Same both smoke about the same each day but John likes traditional cigarettes. Sam on the other hand chooses to use smokeless tobacco products.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is at lower risk for bladder cancer?", "id": "1748834863", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Many different chemical substances cause cancer. Dozens of chemicals in tobacco smoke, including nicotine, have been shown to cause cancer ( Figure below ). In fact, tobacco smoke is one of the main sources of chemical carcinogens. Smoking tobacco increases the risk of cancer of the lung, mouth, throat, and bladder. Using smokeless tobacco can also cause cancer. Other chemicals that cause cancer include asbestos, formaldehyde, benzene, cadmium, and nickel.", "situation": "Three friends Mark, John and Sam have very different views on smoking. Mark has never smoked and doesn't see what people see in it. John and Same both smoke about the same each day but John likes traditional cigarettes. Sam on the other hand chooses to use smokeless tobacco products.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is at lower risk for throat cancer?", "id": "1337924083", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Many different chemical substances cause cancer. Dozens of chemicals in tobacco smoke, including nicotine, have been shown to cause cancer ( Figure below ). In fact, tobacco smoke is one of the main sources of chemical carcinogens. Smoking tobacco increases the risk of cancer of the lung, mouth, throat, and bladder. Using smokeless tobacco can also cause cancer. Other chemicals that cause cancer include asbestos, formaldehyde, benzene, cadmium, and nickel.", "situation": "Three friends Mark, John and Sam have very different views on smoking. Mark has never smoked and doesn't see what people see in it. John and Same both smoke about the same each day but John likes traditional cigarettes. Sam on the other hand chooses to use smokeless tobacco products.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is at lower risk for mouth cancer?", "id": "897718670", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Continued heating of the water after the ice has completely melted will now increase the kinetic energy of the liquid molecules and the temperature will rise. Assuming that the atmospheric pressure is standard, the temperature will rise steadily until it reaches 100\u00c2\u00b0C. At this point, the added energy from the heat will cause the liquid to begin to vaporize. As with the previous state change, the temperature will remain at 100\u00c2\u00b0C while the water molecules are going from the liquid to the gas or vapor state. Once all the liquid has completely boiled away, continued heating of the steam (remember the container is closed) will increase its temperature above 100\u00c2\u00b0C.", "situation": "Ann wanted to make broth so she but some frozen stock and a little water in a pot on the stove to simmer. A few minutes later the phone rang. She started talking to her friend and forgot the broth was on the stove. When she returned to the kitchen the stock had melted and the broth had boiled away.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the kinetic energy increase or decrease as the temerature rose?", "id": "2031974669", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "Continued heating of the water after the ice has completely melted will now increase the kinetic energy of the liquid molecules and the temperature will rise. Assuming that the atmospheric pressure is standard, the temperature will rise steadily until it reaches 100\u00c2\u00b0C. At this point, the added energy from the heat will cause the liquid to begin to vaporize. As with the previous state change, the temperature will remain at 100\u00c2\u00b0C while the water molecules are going from the liquid to the gas or vapor state. Once all the liquid has completely boiled away, continued heating of the steam (remember the container is closed) will increase its temperature above 100\u00c2\u00b0C.", "situation": "Ann wanted to make broth so she but some frozen stock and a little water in a pot on the stove to simmer. A few minutes later the phone rang. She started talking to her friend and forgot the broth was on the stove. When she returned to the kitchen the stock had melted and the broth had boiled away.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the kinetic energy increase before or after the frozen stock melted?", "id": "3701963486", "answers": [{"text": "after"}]}]}, {"background": "Continued heating of the water after the ice has completely melted will now increase the kinetic energy of the liquid molecules and the temperature will rise. Assuming that the atmospheric pressure is standard, the temperature will rise steadily until it reaches 100\u00c2\u00b0C. At this point, the added energy from the heat will cause the liquid to begin to vaporize. As with the previous state change, the temperature will remain at 100\u00c2\u00b0C while the water molecules are going from the liquid to the gas or vapor state. Once all the liquid has completely boiled away, continued heating of the steam (remember the container is closed) will increase its temperature above 100\u00c2\u00b0C.", "situation": "Ann wanted to make broth so she but some frozen stock and a little water in a pot on the stove to simmer. A few minutes later the phone rang. She started talking to her friend and forgot the broth was on the stove. When she returned to the kitchen the stock had melted and the broth had boiled away.", "qas": [{"question": "did the temerature rise before or after the stock melted?", "id": "3652613472", "answers": [{"text": "after"}]}]}, {"background": "Continued heating of the water after the ice has completely melted will now increase the kinetic energy of the liquid molecules and the temperature will rise. Assuming that the atmospheric pressure is standard, the temperature will rise steadily until it reaches 100\u00c2\u00b0C. At this point, the added energy from the heat will cause the liquid to begin to vaporize. As with the previous state change, the temperature will remain at 100\u00c2\u00b0C while the water molecules are going from the liquid to the gas or vapor state. Once all the liquid has completely boiled away, continued heating of the steam (remember the container is closed) will increase its temperature above 100\u00c2\u00b0C.", "situation": "Ann wanted to make broth so she but some frozen stock and a little water in a pot on the stove to simmer. A few minutes later the phone rang. She started talking to her friend and forgot the broth was on the stove. When she returned to the kitchen the stock had melted and the broth had boiled away.", "qas": [{"question": "What happened to the broth when it reached 100 degrees C?", "id": "3303961601", "answers": [{"text": "boiled"}]}]}, {"background": "Continued heating of the water after the ice has completely melted will now increase the kinetic energy of the liquid molecules and the temperature will rise. Assuming that the atmospheric pressure is standard, the temperature will rise steadily until it reaches 100\u00c2\u00b0C. At this point, the added energy from the heat will cause the liquid to begin to vaporize. As with the previous state change, the temperature will remain at 100\u00c2\u00b0C while the water molecules are going from the liquid to the gas or vapor state. Once all the liquid has completely boiled away, continued heating of the steam (remember the container is closed) will increase its temperature above 100\u00c2\u00b0C.", "situation": "Ann wanted to make broth so she but some frozen stock and a little water in a pot on the stove to simmer. A few minutes later the phone rang. She started talking to her friend and forgot the broth was on the stove. When she returned to the kitchen the stock had melted and the broth had boiled away.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the temerature rise or stay the same as it boiled?", "id": "1864397763", "answers": [{"text": "the same"}]}]}, {"background": "Continued heating of the water after the ice has completely melted will now increase the kinetic energy of the liquid molecules and the temperature will rise. Assuming that the atmospheric pressure is standard, the temperature will rise steadily until it reaches 100\u00c2\u00b0C. At this point, the added energy from the heat will cause the liquid to begin to vaporize. As with the previous state change, the temperature will remain at 100\u00c2\u00b0C while the water molecules are going from the liquid to the gas or vapor state. Once all the liquid has completely boiled away, continued heating of the steam (remember the container is closed) will increase its temperature above 100\u00c2\u00b0C.", "situation": "Ann wanted to make broth so she but some frozen stock and a little water in a pot on the stove to simmer. A few minutes later the phone rang. She started talking to her friend and forgot the broth was on the stove. When she returned to the kitchen the stock had melted and the broth had boiled away.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the temerature stable or rising as it melted?", "id": "944534101", "answers": [{"text": "stable"}]}]}, {"background": "Continued heating of the water after the ice has completely melted will now increase the kinetic energy of the liquid molecules and the temperature will rise. Assuming that the atmospheric pressure is standard, the temperature will rise steadily until it reaches 100\u00c2\u00b0C. At this point, the added energy from the heat will cause the liquid to begin to vaporize. As with the previous state change, the temperature will remain at 100\u00c2\u00b0C while the water molecules are going from the liquid to the gas or vapor state. Once all the liquid has completely boiled away, continued heating of the steam (remember the container is closed) will increase its temperature above 100\u00c2\u00b0C.", "situation": "Ann wanted to make broth so she but some frozen stock and a little water in a pot on the stove to simmer. A few minutes later the phone rang. She started talking to her friend and forgot the broth was on the stove. When she returned to the kitchen the stock had melted and the broth had boiled away.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the temperature rise steadily or unevenly after melting?", "id": "1150711554", "answers": [{"text": "steadily"}]}]}, {"background": "Diffusion is the movement of molecules from an area of high concentration of the molecules to an area with a lower concentration. For cell transport, diffusion is the movement of small molecules across the cell membrane. The difference in the concentrations of the molecules in the two areas is called the concentration gradient . The kinetic energy of the molecules results in random motion, causing diffusion. In simple diffusion, this process proceeds without the aid of a transport protein. it is the random motion of the molecules that causes them to move from an area of high concentration to an area with a lower concentration.", "situation": "Beth was getting ready for her date. The last thing she needed to do was put on some perfume and grab her sweater. She sprayed some perfume on then walked across the room to get her sweater. Beth was surprised she could smell the perfume so strongly across the room.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the perfume molecules still or moving.", "id": "2364692719", "answers": [{"text": "moving"}]}]}, {"background": "Diffusion is the movement of molecules from an area of high concentration of the molecules to an area with a lower concentration. For cell transport, diffusion is the movement of small molecules across the cell membrane. The difference in the concentrations of the molecules in the two areas is called the concentration gradient . The kinetic energy of the molecules results in random motion, causing diffusion. In simple diffusion, this process proceeds without the aid of a transport protein. it is the random motion of the molecules that causes them to move from an area of high concentration to an area with a lower concentration.", "situation": "Beth was getting ready for her date. The last thing she needed to do was put on some perfume and grab her sweater. She sprayed some perfume on then walked across the room to get her sweater. Beth was surprised she could smell the perfume so strongly across the room.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the perfume molecules stay where Beth sprayed them or spread out?", "id": "2001035972", "answers": [{"text": "spread out"}]}]}, {"background": "Diffusion is the movement of molecules from an area of high concentration of the molecules to an area with a lower concentration. For cell transport, diffusion is the movement of small molecules across the cell membrane. The difference in the concentrations of the molecules in the two areas is called the concentration gradient . The kinetic energy of the molecules results in random motion, causing diffusion. In simple diffusion, this process proceeds without the aid of a transport protein. it is the random motion of the molecules that causes them to move from an area of high concentration to an area with a lower concentration.", "situation": "Beth was getting ready for her date. The last thing she needed to do was put on some perfume and grab her sweater. She sprayed some perfume on then walked across the room to get her sweater. Beth was surprised she could smell the perfume so strongly across the room.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the space between molecules increasing or decreasing as the move?", "id": "381837945", "answers": [{"text": "increasing"}]}]}, {"background": "Diffusion is the movement of molecules from an area of high concentration of the molecules to an area with a lower concentration. For cell transport, diffusion is the movement of small molecules across the cell membrane. The difference in the concentrations of the molecules in the two areas is called the concentration gradient . The kinetic energy of the molecules results in random motion, causing diffusion. In simple diffusion, this process proceeds without the aid of a transport protein. it is the random motion of the molecules that causes them to move from an area of high concentration to an area with a lower concentration.", "situation": "Beth was getting ready for her date. The last thing she needed to do was put on some perfume and grab her sweater. She sprayed some perfume on then walked across the room to get her sweater. Beth was surprised she could smell the perfume so strongly across the room.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the molecules moving in a pattern around the room or randomly?", "id": "1245012398", "answers": [{"text": "randomly"}]}]}, {"background": "Diffusion is the movement of molecules from an area of high concentration of the molecules to an area with a lower concentration. For cell transport, diffusion is the movement of small molecules across the cell membrane. The difference in the concentrations of the molecules in the two areas is called the concentration gradient . The kinetic energy of the molecules results in random motion, causing diffusion. In simple diffusion, this process proceeds without the aid of a transport protein. it is the random motion of the molecules that causes them to move from an area of high concentration to an area with a lower concentration.", "situation": "Beth was getting ready for her date. The last thing she needed to do was put on some perfume and grab her sweater. She sprayed some perfume on then walked across the room to get her sweater. Beth was surprised she could smell the perfume so strongly across the room.", "qas": [{"question": "When Beth first sprayed the perfume was was the concent4ration orf perfume higher near her or across the room?", "id": "2194436549", "answers": [{"text": "near her"}]}]}, {"background": "Diffusion is the movement of molecules from an area of high concentration of the molecules to an area with a lower concentration. For cell transport, diffusion is the movement of small molecules across the cell membrane. The difference in the concentrations of the molecules in the two areas is called the concentration gradient . The kinetic energy of the molecules results in random motion, causing diffusion. In simple diffusion, this process proceeds without the aid of a transport protein. it is the random motion of the molecules that causes them to move from an area of high concentration to an area with a lower concentration.", "situation": "Beth was getting ready for her date. The last thing she needed to do was put on some perfume and grab her sweater. She sprayed some perfume on then walked across the room to get her sweater. Beth was surprised she could smell the perfume so strongly across the room.", "qas": [{"question": "When Beth first sprayed the perfume was was the concent4ration orf perfume lower near her or across the room?", "id": "316830071", "answers": [{"text": "across the room"}]}]}, {"background": "Diffusion is the movement of molecules from an area of high concentration of the molecules to an area with a lower concentration. For cell transport, diffusion is the movement of small molecules across the cell membrane. The difference in the concentrations of the molecules in the two areas is called the concentration gradient . The kinetic energy of the molecules results in random motion, causing diffusion. In simple diffusion, this process proceeds without the aid of a transport protein. it is the random motion of the molecules that causes them to move from an area of high concentration to an area with a lower concentration.", "situation": "Jeff knows smoking isn't good for you but he still loves the the smell of fresh pipe tobacco. Some of his fondest childhood memories are of sitting on the porch talking to his grandpa as he smoked his pipe. Jeff remembers being fascinated by the smoke as it billowed out of the pipe and wafted across the porch.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the concentration of smoke molecules highest near the pipe or on the other side of the porch?", "id": "1699839156", "answers": [{"text": "near the pipe"}]}]}, {"background": "Diffusion is the movement of molecules from an area of high concentration of the molecules to an area with a lower concentration. For cell transport, diffusion is the movement of small molecules across the cell membrane. The difference in the concentrations of the molecules in the two areas is called the concentration gradient . The kinetic energy of the molecules results in random motion, causing diffusion. In simple diffusion, this process proceeds without the aid of a transport protein. it is the random motion of the molecules that causes them to move from an area of high concentration to an area with a lower concentration.", "situation": "Jeff knows smoking isn't good for you but he still loves the the smell of fresh pipe tobacco. Some of his fondest childhood memories are of sitting on the porch talking to his grandpa as he smoked his pipe. Jeff remembers being fascinated by the smoke as it billowed out of the pipe and wafted across the porch.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the smoke move in a pattern or randomly?", "id": "1702914336", "answers": [{"text": "randomly"}]}]}, {"background": "Diffusion is the movement of molecules from an area of high concentration of the molecules to an area with a lower concentration. For cell transport, diffusion is the movement of small molecules across the cell membrane. The difference in the concentrations of the molecules in the two areas is called the concentration gradient . The kinetic energy of the molecules results in random motion, causing diffusion. In simple diffusion, this process proceeds without the aid of a transport protein. it is the random motion of the molecules that causes them to move from an area of high concentration to an area with a lower concentration.", "situation": "Jeff knows smoking isn't good for you but he still loves the the smell of fresh pipe tobacco. Some of his fondest childhood memories are of sitting on the porch talking to his grandpa as he smoked his pipe. Jeff remembers being fascinated by the smoke as it billowed out of the pipe and wafted across the porch.", "qas": [{"question": "Was it kinetic or thermal energy that moved the smoke?", "id": "2740153614", "answers": [{"text": "kinetic"}]}]}, {"background": "Diffusion is the movement of molecules from an area of high concentration of the molecules to an area with a lower concentration. For cell transport, diffusion is the movement of small molecules across the cell membrane. The difference in the concentrations of the molecules in the two areas is called the concentration gradient . The kinetic energy of the molecules results in random motion, causing diffusion. In simple diffusion, this process proceeds without the aid of a transport protein. it is the random motion of the molecules that causes them to move from an area of high concentration to an area with a lower concentration.", "situation": "Jeff knows smoking isn't good for you but he still loves the the smell of fresh pipe tobacco. Some of his fondest childhood memories are of sitting on the porch talking to his grandpa as he smoked his pipe. Jeff remembers being fascinated by the smoke as it billowed out of the pipe and wafted across the porch.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the smoke thicker or thinner across the porch?", "id": "2228906818", "answers": [{"text": "thinner"}]}]}, {"background": "Diffusion is the movement of molecules from an area of high concentration of the molecules to an area with a lower concentration. For cell transport, diffusion is the movement of small molecules across the cell membrane. The difference in the concentrations of the molecules in the two areas is called the concentration gradient . The kinetic energy of the molecules results in random motion, causing diffusion. In simple diffusion, this process proceeds without the aid of a transport protein. it is the random motion of the molecules that causes them to move from an area of high concentration to an area with a lower concentration.", "situation": "Jeff knows smoking isn't good for you but he still loves the the smell of fresh pipe tobacco. Some of his fondest childhood memories are of sitting on the porch talking to his grandpa as he smoked his pipe. Jeff remembers being fascinated by the smoke as it billowed out of the pipe and wafted across the porch.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the smoke thicker or thinner right above the pipe?", "id": "879586452", "answers": [{"text": "above the pipe"}]}]}, {"background": "Diffusion is the movement of molecules from an area of high concentration of the molecules to an area with a lower concentration. For cell transport, diffusion is the movement of small molecules across the cell membrane. The difference in the concentrations of the molecules in the two areas is called the concentration gradient . The kinetic energy of the molecules results in random motion, causing diffusion. In simple diffusion, this process proceeds without the aid of a transport protein. it is the random motion of the molecules that causes them to move from an area of high concentration to an area with a lower concentration.", "situation": "Jeff knows smoking isn't good for you but he still loves the the smell of fresh pipe tobacco. Some of his fondest childhood memories are of sitting on the porch talking to his grandpa as he smoked his pipe. Jeff remembers being fascinated by the smoke as it billowed out of the pipe and wafted across the porch.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the smoke have more kinetic energy near the pipe or farther away?", "id": "3050467827", "answers": [{"text": "near"}]}]}, {"background": "The Hawaiian Islands ( Figure above ) are in the central Pacific Ocean. The islands are volcanoes that increase in age from southeast to northwest. The youngest island is the Big Island of Hawaii at the southeast end of the chain. The volcanoes get older through Maui, Kahoolawe, Lanai, Molokai, Oahu, Kauai, and Niihau Islands through the northwest. The Kilauea volcano on Hawaii has been erupting almost continuously since 1983. There are also eruptions at an underwater volcano called Loih", "situation": "Matt to see The Hawaiian Islands. His plan is to start at the youngest island and travel in order from the youngest to the oldest visiting the volcanoes on each Island.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Matt start on Maui or the Big Island?", "id": "295107348", "answers": [{"text": "the Big Island"}]}]}, {"background": "The Hawaiian Islands ( Figure above ) are in the central Pacific Ocean. The islands are volcanoes that increase in age from southeast to northwest. The youngest island is the Big Island of Hawaii at the southeast end of the chain. The volcanoes get older through Maui, Kahoolawe, Lanai, Molokai, Oahu, Kauai, and Niihau Islands through the northwest. The Kilauea volcano on Hawaii has been erupting almost continuously since 1983. There are also eruptions at an underwater volcano called Loih", "situation": "Matt to see The Hawaiian Islands. His plan is to start at the youngest island and travel in order from the youngest to the oldest visiting the volcanoes on each Island.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Matt going to travel west or east?", "id": "782694856", "answers": [{"text": "west"}]}]}, {"background": "The Hawaiian Islands ( Figure above ) are in the central Pacific Ocean. The islands are volcanoes that increase in age from southeast to northwest. The youngest island is the Big Island of Hawaii at the southeast end of the chain. The volcanoes get older through Maui, Kahoolawe, Lanai, Molokai, Oahu, Kauai, and Niihau Islands through the northwest. The Kilauea volcano on Hawaii has been erupting almost continuously since 1983. There are also eruptions at an underwater volcano called Loih", "situation": "Matt to see The Hawaiian Islands. His plan is to start at the youngest island and travel in order from the youngest to the oldest visiting the volcanoes on each Island.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Kilauea likely or unlikely to be erupting when he visits?", "id": "269288088", "answers": [{"text": "likely"}]}]}, {"background": "The Hawaiian Islands ( Figure above ) are in the central Pacific Ocean. The islands are volcanoes that increase in age from southeast to northwest. The youngest island is the Big Island of Hawaii at the southeast end of the chain. The volcanoes get older through Maui, Kahoolawe, Lanai, Molokai, Oahu, Kauai, and Niihau Islands through the northwest. The Kilauea volcano on Hawaii has been erupting almost continuously since 1983. There are also eruptions at an underwater volcano called Loih", "situation": "Matt to see The Hawaiian Islands. His plan is to start at the youngest island and travel in order from the youngest to the oldest visiting the volcanoes on each Island.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Matt be able or unable to visit the youngest volcano in the islands?", "id": "1067648793", "answers": [{"text": "unable"}]}]}, {"background": "A catalyst is a substance that increases the rate of a chemical reaction. A catalyst is a substance that increases the rate of a chemical reaction. The presence of a catalyst is one of several factors that influence the rate of chemical reactions. (Other factors include the temperature, concentration, and surface area of reactants.) A catalyst isn\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t a reactant in the chemical reaction it speeds up. As a result, it isn\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t changed or used up in the reaction, so it can go on to catalyze many more reactions.", "situation": "Matt borrowed his fathers pan to use on a camping trip. When he got home he sat it on his back porch, meaning to return the next day but forgot about it. A week later he saw the pan sitting on the porch with a puddle of rain water in it and rust on the bottom.", "qas": [{"question": "Is the pan copper or iron?", "id": "1265180614", "answers": [{"text": "iron"}]}]}, {"background": "A catalyst is a substance that increases the rate of a chemical reaction. A catalyst is a substance that increases the rate of a chemical reaction. The presence of a catalyst is one of several factors that influence the rate of chemical reactions. (Other factors include the temperature, concentration, and surface area of reactants.) A catalyst isn\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t a reactant in the chemical reaction it speeds up. As a result, it isn\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t changed or used up in the reaction, so it can go on to catalyze many more reactions.", "situation": "Matt borrowed his fathers pan to use on a camping trip. When he got home he sat it on his back porch, meaning to return the next day but forgot about it. A week later he saw the pan sitting on the porch with a puddle of rain water in it and rust on the bottom.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the pan exposed to water or not.", "id": "2711298930", "answers": [{"text": "exposed to water"}]}]}, {"background": "A catalyst is a substance that increases the rate of a chemical reaction. A catalyst is a substance that increases the rate of a chemical reaction. The presence of a catalyst is one of several factors that influence the rate of chemical reactions. (Other factors include the temperature, concentration, and surface area of reactants.) A catalyst isn\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t a reactant in the chemical reaction it speeds up. As a result, it isn\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t changed or used up in the reaction, so it can go on to catalyze many more reactions.", "situation": "Matt borrowed his fathers pan to use on a camping trip. When he got home he sat it on his back porch, meaning to return the next day but forgot about it. A week later he saw the pan sitting on the porch with a puddle of rain water in it and rust on the bottom.", "qas": [{"question": "What caused the rust.", "id": "3030130223", "answers": [{"text": "water"}]}]}, {"background": "A catalyst is a substance that increases the rate of a chemical reaction. A catalyst is a substance that increases the rate of a chemical reaction. The presence of a catalyst is one of several factors that influence the rate of chemical reactions. (Other factors include the temperature, concentration, and surface area of reactants.) A catalyst isn\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t a reactant in the chemical reaction it speeds up. As a result, it isn\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t changed or used up in the reaction, so it can go on to catalyze many more reactions.", "situation": "Matt borrowed his fathers pan to use on a camping trip. When he got home he sat it on his back porch, meaning to return the next day but forgot about it. A week later he saw the pan sitting on the porch with a puddle of rain water in it and rust on the bottom.", "qas": [{"question": "Was there less or the same amount of water after the rust formed?", "id": "1197878836", "answers": [{"text": "the same"}]}]}, {"background": "A catalyst is a substance that increases the rate of a chemical reaction. A catalyst is a substance that increases the rate of a chemical reaction. The presence of a catalyst is one of several factors that influence the rate of chemical reactions. (Other factors include the temperature, concentration, and surface area of reactants.) A catalyst isn\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t a reactant in the chemical reaction it speeds up. As a result, it isn\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t changed or used up in the reaction, so it can go on to catalyze many more reactions.", "situation": "Matt borrowed his fathers pan to use on a camping trip. When he got home he sat it on his back porch, meaning to return the next day but forgot about it. A week later he saw the pan sitting on the porch with a puddle of rain water in it and rust on the bottom.", "qas": [{"question": "Did the water make the rust form faster or slower?", "id": "3053725888", "answers": [{"text": "faster"}]}]}, {"background": "A catalyst is a substance that increases the rate of a chemical reaction. A catalyst is a substance that increases the rate of a chemical reaction. The presence of a catalyst is one of several factors that influence the rate of chemical reactions. (Other factors include the temperature, concentration, and surface area of reactants.) A catalyst isn\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t a reactant in the chemical reaction it speeds up. As a result, it isn\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t changed or used up in the reaction, so it can go on to catalyze many more reactions.", "situation": "Matt borrowed his fathers pan to use on a camping trip. When he got home he sat it on his back porch, meaning to return the next day but forgot about it. A week later he saw the pan sitting on the porch with a puddle of rain water in it and rust on the bottom.", "qas": [{"question": "If there had been no rain would the rust have formed faster or slower?", "id": "567947226", "answers": [{"text": "slower"}]}]}, {"background": "Many chemicals that were once commonly used were later found out to be harmful to the environment , to human health, or both. The element lead was once a common additive to gasoline and to paint. Plumbing pipes were once typically made of lead. Only since the 1970s has the danger of lead become apparent. It causes brain damage and small children (who often chewed on objects painted with lead-based paint) are particularly susceptible. The use of lead in gasoline, paint, and plumbing pipes is now banned and new materials are being developed to replace the hazardous lead components.", "situation": "Asbestos was once used insulation in buildings and in various products such as roofing materials, water supply lines and clutches, brake linings, gaskets and pads for automobiles. Decades later asbestos was linked to cancer but can still be found in old buildings.", "qas": [{"question": "Is asbestos harmful or safe?", "id": "1198014153", "answers": [{"text": "harmful"}]}]}, {"background": "Many chemicals that were once commonly used were later found out to be harmful to the environment , to human health, or both. The element lead was once a common additive to gasoline and to paint. Plumbing pipes were once typically made of lead. Only since the 1970s has the danger of lead become apparent. It causes brain damage and small children (who often chewed on objects painted with lead-based paint) are particularly susceptible. The use of lead in gasoline, paint, and plumbing pipes is now banned and new materials are being developed to replace the hazardous lead components.", "situation": "Asbestos was once used insulation in buildings and in various products such as roofing materials, water supply lines and clutches, brake linings, gaskets and pads for automobiles. Decades later asbestos was linked to cancer but can still be found in old buildings.", "qas": [{"question": "Is asbestos harmful or safe for people?", "id": "304366293", "answers": [{"text": "harmful"}]}]}, {"background": "Many chemicals that were once commonly used were later found out to be harmful to the environment , to human health, or both. The element lead was once a common additive to gasoline and to paint. Plumbing pipes were once typically made of lead. Only since the 1970s has the danger of lead become apparent. It causes brain damage and small children (who often chewed on objects painted with lead-based paint) are particularly susceptible. The use of lead in gasoline, paint, and plumbing pipes is now banned and new materials are being developed to replace the hazardous lead components.", "situation": "Asbestos was once used insulation in buildings and in various products such as roofing materials, water supply lines and clutches, brake linings, gaskets and pads for automobiles. Decades later asbestos was linked to cancer but can still be found in old buildings.", "qas": [{"question": "Was asbestos always harmful or only recently?", "id": "3026142610", "answers": [{"text": "always"}]}]}, {"background": "An allergy is a disease in which the immune system makes an inflammatory response to a harmless antigen . Any antigen that causes an allergy is called an allergen. Allergens may be inhaled or ingested, or they may come into contact with the skin. Two common causes of allergies are shown in Figure below . Inhaling ragweed pollen may cause coughing and sneezing. Skin contact with oils in poison ivy may cause an itchy rash. Other common causes of allergies include dust mites, mold, animal dander, insect stings, latex, and certain food and medications. Symptoms of a common allergy such as pollen can include sneezing, a runny nose, nasal congestion and itchy, watery eyes.", "situation": "Mark and Jane were working in their yard planting a garden and mowing. Jane was sneezing and coughing much of the day. Mark was fine until he pulled up some weeds and noticed that his arms were inch and had red bumps all over them.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is allergic to poison ivy?", "id": "394809894", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "An allergy is a disease in which the immune system makes an inflammatory response to a harmless antigen . Any antigen that causes an allergy is called an allergen. Allergens may be inhaled or ingested, or they may come into contact with the skin. Two common causes of allergies are shown in Figure below . Inhaling ragweed pollen may cause coughing and sneezing. Skin contact with oils in poison ivy may cause an itchy rash. Other common causes of allergies include dust mites, mold, animal dander, insect stings, latex, and certain food and medications. Symptoms of a common allergy such as pollen can include sneezing, a runny nose, nasal congestion and itchy, watery eyes.", "situation": "Mark and Jane were working in their yard planting a garden and mowing. Jane was sneezing and coughing much of the day. Mark was fine until he pulled up some weeds and noticed that his arms were inch and had red bumps all over them.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is having an allergic reaction?", "id": "3037221876", "answers": [{"text": "Mark and Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "An allergy is a disease in which the immune system makes an inflammatory response to a harmless antigen . Any antigen that causes an allergy is called an allergen. Allergens may be inhaled or ingested, or they may come into contact with the skin. Two common causes of allergies are shown in Figure below . Inhaling ragweed pollen may cause coughing and sneezing. Skin contact with oils in poison ivy may cause an itchy rash. Other common causes of allergies include dust mites, mold, animal dander, insect stings, latex, and certain food and medications. Symptoms of a common allergy such as pollen can include sneezing, a runny nose, nasal congestion and itchy, watery eyes.", "situation": "Mark and Jane were working in their yard planting a garden and mowing. Jane was sneezing and coughing much of the day. Mark was fine until he pulled up some weeds and noticed that his arms were inch and had red bumps all over them.", "qas": [{"question": "Who's having an inflamitory response?", "id": "1649825047", "answers": [{"text": "Mark and Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "An allergy is a disease in which the immune system makes an inflammatory response to a harmless antigen . Any antigen that causes an allergy is called an allergen. Allergens may be inhaled or ingested, or they may come into contact with the skin. Two common causes of allergies are shown in Figure below . Inhaling ragweed pollen may cause coughing and sneezing. Skin contact with oils in poison ivy may cause an itchy rash. Other common causes of allergies include dust mites, mold, animal dander, insect stings, latex, and certain food and medications. Symptoms of a common allergy such as pollen can include sneezing, a runny nose, nasal congestion and itchy, watery eyes.", "situation": "Mark and Jane were working in their yard planting a garden and mowing. Jane was sneezing and coughing much of the day. Mark was fine until he pulled up some weeds and noticed that his arms were inch and had red bumps all over them.", "qas": [{"question": "Who touched an allergen?", "id": "843796473", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "An allergy is a disease in which the immune system makes an inflammatory response to a harmless antigen . Any antigen that causes an allergy is called an allergen. Allergens may be inhaled or ingested, or they may come into contact with the skin. Two common causes of allergies are shown in Figure below . Inhaling ragweed pollen may cause coughing and sneezing. Skin contact with oils in poison ivy may cause an itchy rash. Other common causes of allergies include dust mites, mold, animal dander, insect stings, latex, and certain food and medications. Symptoms of a common allergy such as pollen can include sneezing, a runny nose, nasal congestion and itchy, watery eyes.", "situation": "Mark and Jane were working in their yard planting a garden and mowing. Jane was sneezing and coughing much of the day. Mark was fine until he pulled up some weeds and noticed that his arms were inch and had red bumps all over them.", "qas": [{"question": "Who inhaled an allergen?", "id": "814764002", "answers": [{"text": "Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "An allergy is a disease in which the immune system makes an inflammatory response to a harmless antigen . Any antigen that causes an allergy is called an allergen. Allergens may be inhaled or ingested, or they may come into contact with the skin. Two common causes of allergies are shown in Figure below . Inhaling ragweed pollen may cause coughing and sneezing. Skin contact with oils in poison ivy may cause an itchy rash. Other common causes of allergies include dust mites, mold, animal dander, insect stings, latex, and certain food and medications. Symptoms of a common allergy such as pollen can include sneezing, a runny nose, nasal congestion and itchy, watery eyes.", "situation": "Mark and Jane were working in their yard planting a garden and mowing. Jane was sneezing and coughing much of the day. Mark was fine until he pulled up some weeds and noticed that his arms were inch and had red bumps all over them.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is likely to also have watery eyes?", "id": "147608930", "answers": [{"text": "Jane"}]}]}, {"background": "An allergy is a disease in which the immune system makes an inflammatory response to a harmless antigen . Any antigen that causes an allergy is called an allergen. Allergens may be inhaled or ingested, or they may come into contact with the skin. Two common causes of allergies are shown in Figure below . Inhaling ragweed pollen may cause coughing and sneezing. Skin contact with oils in poison ivy may cause an itchy rash. Other common causes of allergies include dust mites, mold, animal dander, insect stings, latex, and certain food and medications. Symptoms of a common allergy such as pollen can include sneezing, a runny nose, nasal congestion and itchy, watery eyes.", "situation": "Mark and Jane were working in their yard planting a garden and mowing. Jane was sneezing and coughing much of the day. Mark was fine until he pulled up some weeds and noticed that his arms were inch and had red bumps all over them.", "qas": [{"question": "Who came in contact with a plant oil?", "id": "1519473741", "answers": [{"text": "Mark"}]}]}, {"background": "Chills is a feeling of coldness occurring during a high fever, but sometimes is also a common symptom which occurs alone in specific people. It occurs during fever due to the release of cytokines and prostaglandins as part of the inflammatory response, which increases the set point for body temperature in the hypothalamus. The increased set point causes the body temperature to rise (pyrexia), but also makes the patient feel cold or chills until the new set point is reached. Shivering also occurs along with chills because the patient's body produces heat during muscle contraction in a physiological attempt to increase body temperature to the new set point. When it does not accompany a high fever, it is normally a light chill. Sometimes a chill of medium power and short duration may occur during a scare, especially in scares of fear, commonly interpreted like or confused by trembling.", "situation": "Beth has been coughing all morning and she has a high fever. She decided to stay home but has noticed that she can not get warm and is shaking. Meanwhile her roommate Susan was driving to work when she was suddenly cut off by a large truck and had to go off the road to narrowly miss an accident. Susan was terrified, she looked at the steering wheel and saw that her hands were shaking.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Susan sick.", "id": "401725444", "answers": [{"text": "no"}]}]}, {"background": "Chills is a feeling of coldness occurring during a high fever, but sometimes is also a common symptom which occurs alone in specific people. It occurs during fever due to the release of cytokines and prostaglandins as part of the inflammatory response, which increases the set point for body temperature in the hypothalamus. The increased set point causes the body temperature to rise (pyrexia), but also makes the patient feel cold or chills until the new set point is reached. Shivering also occurs along with chills because the patient's body produces heat during muscle contraction in a physiological attempt to increase body temperature to the new set point. When it does not accompany a high fever, it is normally a light chill. Sometimes a chill of medium power and short duration may occur during a scare, especially in scares of fear, commonly interpreted like or confused by trembling.", "situation": "Beth has been coughing all morning and. She decided to stay home but has noticed that she can not get warm and is shaking. Meanwhile her roommate Susan was driving to work when she was suddenly cut off by a large truck and had to go off the road to narrowly miss an accident. Susan was terrified, she looked at the steering wheel and saw that her hands were shaking.", "qas": [{"question": "Who has a fever.", "id": "2989347170", "answers": [{"text": "Beth"}]}]}, {"background": "Chills is a feeling of coldness occurring during a high fever, but sometimes is also a common symptom which occurs alone in specific people. It occurs during fever due to the release of cytokines and prostaglandins as part of the inflammatory response, which increases the set point for body temperature in the hypothalamus. The increased set point causes the body temperature to rise (pyrexia), but also makes the patient feel cold or chills until the new set point is reached. Shivering also occurs along with chills because the patient's body produces heat during muscle contraction in a physiological attempt to increase body temperature to the new set point. When it does not accompany a high fever, it is normally a light chill. Sometimes a chill of medium power and short duration may occur during a scare, especially in scares of fear, commonly interpreted like or confused by trembling.", "situation": "Beth has been coughing all morning and. She decided to stay home but has noticed that she can not get warm and is shaking. Meanwhile her roommate Susan was driving to work when she was suddenly cut off by a large truck and had to go off the road to narrowly miss an accident. Susan looked at the steering wheel and saw that her hands were shaking.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is frightened.", "id": "4198878132", "answers": [{"text": "Susan"}]}]}, {"background": "To determine the concentration of an acid in an aqueous solution, an acid-base titration is commonly performed. A strong base solution with a known concentration, usually NaOH or KOH, is added to neutralize the acid solution according to the color change of the indicator with the amount of base added.[7] The titration curve of an acid titrated by a base has two axes, with the base volume on the x-axis and the solution's pH value on the y-axis. The pH of the solution always goes up as the base is added to the solution.", "situation": "Sam was looking over his notes from his science experiment. He looked at the graph he had made while titrating an acid with a base. He noticed that on the first day there was less base in the acid and the ph was lower. On the second day he added more base and the y-axis on his graph increased.", "qas": [{"question": "What happened to the ph of the solution on the second day.", "id": "1989097640", "answers": [{"text": "increased"}]}]}, {"background": "To determine the concentration of an acid in an aqueous solution, an acid-base titration is commonly performed. A strong base solution with a known concentration, usually NaOH or KOH, is added to neutralize the acid solution according to the color change of the indicator with the amount of base added.[7] The titration curve of an acid titrated by a base has two axes, with the base volume on the x-axis and the solution's pH value on the y-axis. The pH of the solution always goes up as the base is added to the solution.", "situation": "Sam was looking over his notes from his science experiment. He looked at the graph he had made while titrating an acid with a base. He noticed that on the first day there was less base in the acid and the ph was lower. On the second day he added more base and the y-axis on his graph increased.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the y-axis higher or lower the first day.", "id": "2904568823", "answers": [{"text": "lower"}]}]}, {"background": "To determine the concentration of an acid in an aqueous solution, an acid-base titration is commonly performed. A strong base solution with a known concentration, usually NaOH or KOH, is added to neutralize the acid solution according to the color change of the indicator with the amount of base added.[7] The titration curve of an acid titrated by a base has two axes, with the base volume on the x-axis and the solution's pH value on the y-axis. The pH of the solution always goes up as the base is added to the solution.", "situation": "Sam was looking over his notes from his science experiment. He looked at the graph he had made while titrating an acid with a base. He noticed that on the first day there was less base in the acid and the ph was lower. On the second day he added more base and the y-axis on his graph increased.", "qas": [{"question": "Was the x-axis increased or decreased the second day.", "id": "1594701560", "answers": [{"text": "increased"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "Air pollution has been a major topic of discussion in two countries on opposite sides of the world, Country A and Country B. Country A has decided to make changes to current policies in an effort to reduce the amount of air pollution they produce. Country B has decided that air pollution isn't so bad, so they don't make any changes to their policies regarding air pollution.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the citizens of Country A more or less likely to develop cancer than the citizens of Country B?", "id": "1143695762", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "Air pollution has been a major topic of discussion in two countries on opposite sides of the world, Country A and Country B. Country A has decided to make changes to current policies in an effort to reduce the amount of air pollution they produce. Country B has decided that air pollution isn't so bad, so they don't make any changes to their policies regarding air pollution.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the citizens of Country B more or less likely to develop cancer than the citizens of Country A?", "id": "1148217746", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "Air pollution has been a major topic of discussion in two countries on opposite sides of the world, Country A and Country B. Country A has decided to make changes to current policies in an effort to reduce the amount of air pollution they produce. Country B has decided that air pollution isn't so bad, so they don't make any changes to their policies regarding air pollution.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the citizens of Country B more or less likely to develop heart disease than the citizens of Country A?", "id": "917204024", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "Air pollution has been a major topic of discussion in two countries on opposite sides of the world, Country A and Country B. Country A has decided to make changes to current policies in an effort to reduce the amount of air pollution they produce. Country B has decided that air pollution isn't so bad, so they don't make any changes to their policies regarding air pollution.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the citizens of Country A more or less likely to develop heart disease than the citizens of Country B?", "id": "912223288", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "Air pollution has been a major topic of discussion in two countries on opposite sides of the world, Country A and Country B. Country A has decided to make changes to current policies in an effort to reduce the amount of air pollution they produce. Country B has decided that air pollution isn't so bad, so they don't make any changes to their policies regarding air pollution.", "qas": [{"question": "Which country will likely have more diagnosed cancer patients, Country A or Country B?", "id": "861234509", "answers": [{"text": "Country B"}]}]}, {"background": "Air pollution can also indirectly cause other health issues and even deaths. Air pollutants can cause an increase in cancer including lung cancer, eye problems, and other conditions. For example, using certain chemicals on farms, such as the insecticide DDT (dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane) and toxic PCBs (polychlorinated biphenyl), can cause cancer. Indoors, pollutants such as radon or asbestos can also increase your cancer risk. Lastly, air pollution can lead to heart disease, including heart attack and stroke.", "situation": "Air pollution has been a major topic of discussion in two countries on opposite sides of the world, Country A and Country B. Country A has decided to make changes to current policies in an effort to reduce the amount of air pollution they produce. Country B has decided that air pollution isn't so bad, so they don't make any changes to their policies regarding air pollution.", "qas": [{"question": "Which country will likely have fewer diagnosed cancer patients, Country A or Country B?", "id": "2599511475", "answers": [{"text": "Country A"}]}]}, {"background": "Raising the temperature of a chemical reaction usually results in a higher rate of reaction. When the reactant particles are heated, they move faster and faster. This results in a greater frequency of collisions. A more important effect of the temperature increase is that the collisions occur with a greater force and are thus more likely to surmount the activation energy barrier and go on to form products. Increasing the temperature of a reaction increases the number of effective collisions between reacting particles, so the reaction rate increases.", "situation": "Janet is baking cookies for her daughter's birthday party. She has so many cookies to bake that she decides to bake two batches at once using separate ovens. Janet asks her neighbor if she can use her oven for one batch, and uses her own oven for the other batch. Janet sets the oven temperature on both stoves to 375 degrees and begins baking the cookies. However, after she leaves her neighbors house, the oven temperature is accidentally increased to 475.", "qas": [{"question": "Which cookies will bake faster, the cookies in Janet's oven or the cookies in the neighbor's oven?", "id": "4032205996", "answers": [{"text": "the cookies in the neighbor's oven"}]}]}, {"background": "Raising the temperature of a chemical reaction usually results in a higher rate of reaction. When the reactant particles are heated, they move faster and faster. This results in a greater frequency of collisions. A more important effect of the temperature increase is that the collisions occur with a greater force and are thus more likely to surmount the activation energy barrier and go on to form products. Increasing the temperature of a reaction increases the number of effective collisions between reacting particles, so the reaction rate increases.", "situation": "Janet is baking cookies for her daughter's birthday party. She has so many cookies to bake that she decides to bake two batches at once using separate ovens. Janet asks her neighbor if she can use her oven for one batch, and uses her own oven for the other batch. Janet sets the oven temperature on both stoves to 375 degrees and begins baking the cookies. However, after she leaves her neighbors house, the oven temperature is accidentally increased to 475.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the cookies in Janet's oven cook faster or slower than the cookies in her neighbor's oven?", "id": "919114718", "answers": [{"text": "slower"}]}]}, {"background": "Raising the temperature of a chemical reaction usually results in a higher rate of reaction. When the reactant particles are heated, they move faster and faster. This results in a greater frequency of collisions. A more important effect of the temperature increase is that the collisions occur with a greater force and are thus more likely to surmount the activation energy barrier and go on to form products. Increasing the temperature of a reaction increases the number of effective collisions between reacting particles, so the reaction rate increases.", "situation": "Janet is baking cookies for her daughter's birthday party. She has so many cookies to bake that she decides to bake two batches at once using separate ovens. Janet asks her neighbor if she can use her oven for one batch, and uses her own oven for the other batch. Janet sets the oven temperature on both stoves to 375 degrees and begins baking the cookies. However, after she leaves her neighbors house, the oven temperature is accidentally increased to 475.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the cookies in the neighbor's oven cook faster or slower than the cookies in Janet's oven?", "id": "1114936288", "answers": [{"text": "faster"}]}]}, {"background": "The advantage of asexual reproduction is that it can be very quick and does not require the meeting of a male and female organism. The disadvantage of asexual reproduction is that organisms do not receive a mix of traits from both parents. An organism that is born through asexual reproduction only has the DNA from the one parent. In fact, the offspring is genetically an exact copy of the parent. This can cause problems for the individual. For example, if the parent has a gene that causes a particular disease, the offspring will also have the gene that causes that disease. Organisms produced sexually may or may not inherit the disease gene because they receive a mix of their parents' genes.", "situation": "James is a marine biologist. On a recent deep sea dive, he discovered two new organisms. James took the organisms back to his lab to study them. While in the lab, each organism produced an offspring. Since the organisms were previously undiscovered, James must determine how these organisms reproduce in order to correctly classify them. After examining the DNA of each offspring, James finds that the offspring of organism A shares the exact same DNA as the parent organism and the offspring of organism B does not contain the exact same DNA as the parent organism.", "qas": [{"question": "Which organism reproduced asexually, organism A or organism B?", "id": "1187176727", "answers": [{"text": "organism A"}]}]}, {"background": "The advantage of asexual reproduction is that it can be very quick and does not require the meeting of a male and female organism. The disadvantage of asexual reproduction is that organisms do not receive a mix of traits from both parents. An organism that is born through asexual reproduction only has the DNA from the one parent. In fact, the offspring is genetically an exact copy of the parent. This can cause problems for the individual. For example, if the parent has a gene that causes a particular disease, the offspring will also have the gene that causes that disease. Organisms produced sexually may or may not inherit the disease gene because they receive a mix of their parents' genes.", "situation": "James is a marine biologist. On a recent deep sea dive, he discovered two new organisms. James took the organisms back to his lab to study them. While in the lab, each organism produced an offspring. Since the organisms were previously undiscovered, James must determine how these organisms reproduce in order to correctly classify them. After examining the DNA of each offspring, James finds that the offspring of organism A shares the exact same DNA as the parent organism and the offspring of organism B does not contain the exact same DNA as the parent organism.", "qas": [{"question": "Which organism reproduced sexually, organism A or organism B?", "id": "1694490806", "answers": [{"text": "organism B"}]}]}, {"background": "The advantage of asexual reproduction is that it can be very quick and does not require the meeting of a male and female organism. The disadvantage of asexual reproduction is that organisms do not receive a mix of traits from both parents. An organism that is born through asexual reproduction only has the DNA from the one parent. In fact, the offspring is genetically an exact copy of the parent. This can cause problems for the individual. For example, if the parent has a gene that causes a particular disease, the offspring will also have the gene that causes that disease. Organisms produced sexually may or may not inherit the disease gene because they receive a mix of their parents' genes.", "situation": "James is a marine biologist. On a recent deep sea dive, he discovered two new organisms. James took the organisms back to his lab to study them. While in the lab, each organism produced an offspring. Since the organisms were previously undiscovered, James must determine how these organisms reproduce in order to correctly classify them. After examining the DNA of each offspring, James finds that the offspring of organism A shares the exact same DNA as the parent organism and the offspring of organism B does not contain the exact same DNA as the parent organism.", "qas": [{"question": "Did organism A reproduce sexually or asexually?", "id": "666491866", "answers": [{"text": "asexually"}]}]}, {"background": "The advantage of asexual reproduction is that it can be very quick and does not require the meeting of a male and female organism. The disadvantage of asexual reproduction is that organisms do not receive a mix of traits from both parents. An organism that is born through asexual reproduction only has the DNA from the one parent. In fact, the offspring is genetically an exact copy of the parent. This can cause problems for the individual. For example, if the parent has a gene that causes a particular disease, the offspring will also have the gene that causes that disease. Organisms produced sexually may or may not inherit the disease gene because they receive a mix of their parents' genes.", "situation": "James is a marine biologist. On a recent deep sea dive, he discovered two new organisms. James took the organisms back to his lab to study them. While in the lab, each organism produced an offspring. Since the organisms were previously undiscovered, James must determine how these organisms reproduce in order to correctly classify them. After examining the DNA of each offspring, James finds that the offspring of organism A shares the exact same DNA as the parent organism and the offspring of organism B does not contain the exact same DNA as the parent organism.", "qas": [{"question": "Did organism B reproduce sexually or asexually?", "id": "668720091", "answers": [{"text": "sexually"}]}]}, {"background": "As time passes, the number of HIV copies keeps increasing, while the number of helper T cells keeps decreasing. The graph in Figure below shows how the number of T cells typically declines over a period of many years following the initial HIV infection. As the number of T cells decreases, so does the ability of the immune system to defend the body. As a result, an HIV-infected person develops frequent infections. Medicines can slow down the virus but not get rid of it, so there is no cure at present for HIV infections or AIDS. There also is no vaccine to immunize people against HIV infection, but scientists are working to develop one.", "situation": "Jason and Elton have both been diagnosed with HIV. Jason was initially diagnosed 5 years ago. Elton was initially diagnosed 15 years ago. Both Jason and Elton recently had routine doctor appointments and had blood work done to assess the progression of the disease.", "qas": [{"question": "Who will have more copies of HIV in their blood, Jason or Elton?", "id": "3025951783", "answers": [{"text": "Elton"}]}]}, {"background": "As time passes, the number of HIV copies keeps increasing, while the number of helper T cells keeps decreasing. The graph in Figure below shows how the number of T cells typically declines over a period of many years following the initial HIV infection. As the number of T cells decreases, so does the ability of the immune system to defend the body. As a result, an HIV-infected person develops frequent infections. Medicines can slow down the virus but not get rid of it, so there is no cure at present for HIV infections or AIDS. There also is no vaccine to immunize people against HIV infection, but scientists are working to develop one.", "situation": "Jason and Elton have both been diagnosed with HIV. Jason was initially diagnosed 5 years ago. Elton was initially diagnosed 15 years ago. Both Jason and Elton recently had routine doctor appointments and had blood work done to assess the progression of the disease.", "qas": [{"question": "Who will have fewer copies of HIV in their blood, Jason or Elton?", "id": "326196365", "answers": [{"text": "Jason"}]}]}, {"background": "As time passes, the number of HIV copies keeps increasing, while the number of helper T cells keeps decreasing. The graph in Figure below shows how the number of T cells typically declines over a period of many years following the initial HIV infection. As the number of T cells decreases, so does the ability of the immune system to defend the body. As a result, an HIV-infected person develops frequent infections. Medicines can slow down the virus but not get rid of it, so there is no cure at present for HIV infections or AIDS. There also is no vaccine to immunize people against HIV infection, but scientists are working to develop one.", "situation": "Jason and Elton have both been diagnosed with HIV. Jason was initially diagnosed 5 years ago. Elton was initially diagnosed 15 years ago. Both Jason and Elton recently had routine doctor appointments and had blood work done to assess the progression of the disease.", "qas": [{"question": "Who will have fewer T cells, Jason or Elton?", "id": "3218298162", "answers": [{"text": "Elton"}]}]}, {"background": "As time passes, the number of HIV copies keeps increasing, while the number of helper T cells keeps decreasing. The graph in Figure below shows how the number of T cells typically declines over a period of many years following the initial HIV infection. As the number of T cells decreases, so does the ability of the immune system to defend the body. As a result, an HIV-infected person develops frequent infections. Medicines can slow down the virus but not get rid of it, so there is no cure at present for HIV infections or AIDS. There also is no vaccine to immunize people against HIV infection, but scientists are working to develop one.", "situation": "Jason and Elton have both been diagnosed with HIV. Jason was initially diagnosed 5 years ago. Elton was initially diagnosed 15 years ago. Both Jason and Elton recently had routine doctor appointments and had blood work done to assess the progression of the disease.", "qas": [{"question": "Who will have more T cells, Jason or Elton?", "id": "1764447436", "answers": [{"text": "Jason"}]}]}, {"background": "As time passes, the number of HIV copies keeps increasing, while the number of helper T cells keeps decreasing. The graph in Figure below shows how the number of T cells typically declines over a period of many years following the initial HIV infection. As the number of T cells decreases, so does the ability of the immune system to defend the body. As a result, an HIV-infected person develops frequent infections. Medicines can slow down the virus but not get rid of it, so there is no cure at present for HIV infections or AIDS. There also is no vaccine to immunize people against HIV infection, but scientists are working to develop one.", "situation": "Jason and Elton have both been diagnosed with HIV. Jason was initially diagnosed 5 years ago. Elton was initially diagnosed 15 years ago. Both Jason and Elton recently had routine doctor appointments and had blood work done to assess the progression of the disease.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is more likely to develop frequent infections, Jason or Elton?", "id": "2488294941", "answers": [{"text": "Elton"}]}]}, {"background": "As time passes, the number of HIV copies keeps increasing, while the number of helper T cells keeps decreasing. The graph in Figure below shows how the number of T cells typically declines over a period of many years following the initial HIV infection. As the number of T cells decreases, so does the ability of the immune system to defend the body. As a result, an HIV-infected person develops frequent infections. Medicines can slow down the virus but not get rid of it, so there is no cure at present for HIV infections or AIDS. There also is no vaccine to immunize people against HIV infection, but scientists are working to develop one.", "situation": "Jason and Elton have both been diagnosed with HIV. Jason was initially diagnosed 5 years ago. Elton was initially diagnosed 15 years ago. Both Jason and Elton recently had routine doctor appointments and had blood work done to assess the progression of the disease.", "qas": [{"question": "Who is less likely to develop frequent infections, Jason or Elton?", "id": "2501533217", "answers": [{"text": "Jason"}]}]}, {"background": "The epidermis also contains melanocytes, which are cells that produce melanin. Melanin is the brownish pigment that gives skin much of its color. Everyone has about the same number of melanocytes, but the melanocytes of people with darker skin produce more melanin. The amount of melanin produced is determined by heredity and exposure to UV light, which increases melanin output. Exposure to UV light also stimulates the skin to produce vitamin D. Because melanin blocks UV light from penetrating the skin, people with darker skin may be at greater risk of vitamin D deficiency.", "situation": "Lily and Ivy are biological sisters. Due to genetics, Lily has much lighter skin than Ivy, who is fairly dark complected.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose skin produces more melanin, Lily or Ivy?", "id": "1674973276", "answers": [{"text": "Ivy"}]}]}, {"background": "The epidermis also contains melanocytes, which are cells that produce melanin. Melanin is the brownish pigment that gives skin much of its color. Everyone has about the same number of melanocytes, but the melanocytes of people with darker skin produce more melanin. The amount of melanin produced is determined by heredity and exposure to UV light, which increases melanin output. Exposure to UV light also stimulates the skin to produce vitamin D. Because melanin blocks UV light from penetrating the skin, people with darker skin may be at greater risk of vitamin D deficiency.", "situation": "Lily and Ivy are biological sisters. Due to genetics, Lily has much lighter skin than Ivy, who is fairly dark complected.", "qas": [{"question": "Whose skin produces less melanin, Lily or Ivy?", "id": "1679560800", "answers": [{"text": "Lily"}]}]}, {"background": "The epidermis also contains melanocytes, which are cells that produce melanin. Melanin is the brownish pigment that gives skin much of its color. Everyone has about the same number of melanocytes, but the melanocytes of people with darker skin produce more melanin. The amount of melanin produced is determined by heredity and exposure to UV light, which increases melanin output. Exposure to UV light also stimulates the skin to produce vitamin D. Because melanin blocks UV light from penetrating the skin, people with darker skin may be at greater risk of vitamin D deficiency.", "situation": "Lily and Ivy are biological sisters. Due to genetics, Lily has much lighter skin than Ivy, who is fairly dark complected.", "qas": [{"question": "Does Lily or Ivy's skin have more melanin?", "id": "218631822", "answers": [{"text": "Ivy"}]}]}, {"background": "The epidermis also contains melanocytes, which are cells that produce melanin. Melanin is the brownish pigment that gives skin much of its color. Everyone has about the same number of melanocytes, but the melanocytes of people with darker skin produce more melanin. The amount of melanin produced is determined by heredity and exposure to UV light, which increases melanin output. Exposure to UV light also stimulates the skin to produce vitamin D. Because melanin blocks UV light from penetrating the skin, people with darker skin may be at greater risk of vitamin D deficiency.", "situation": "Lily and Ivy are biological sisters. Due to genetics, Lily has much lighter skin than Ivy, who is fairly dark complected.", "qas": [{"question": "Does Lily or Ivy's skin have less melanin?", "id": "219811474", "answers": [{"text": "Lily"}]}]}, {"background": "The epidermis also contains melanocytes, which are cells that produce melanin. Melanin is the brownish pigment that gives skin much of its color. Everyone has about the same number of melanocytes, but the melanocytes of people with darker skin produce more melanin. The amount of melanin produced is determined by heredity and exposure to UV light, which increases melanin output. Exposure to UV light also stimulates the skin to produce vitamin D. Because melanin blocks UV light from penetrating the skin, people with darker skin may be at greater risk of vitamin D deficiency.", "situation": "Lily and Ivy are biological sisters. Due to genetics, Lily has much lighter skin than Ivy, who is fairly dark complected.", "qas": [{"question": "If the sisters go to a tanning bed, will their skin produce more or less melanin?", "id": "1628642509", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "The epidermis also contains melanocytes, which are cells that produce melanin. Melanin is the brownish pigment that gives skin much of its color. Everyone has about the same number of melanocytes, but the melanocytes of people with darker skin produce more melanin. The amount of melanin produced is determined by heredity and exposure to UV light, which increases melanin output. Exposure to UV light also stimulates the skin to produce vitamin D. Because melanin blocks UV light from penetrating the skin, people with darker skin may be at greater risk of vitamin D deficiency.", "situation": "Lily and Ivy are biological sisters. Due to genetics, Lily has much lighter skin than Ivy, who is fairly dark complected.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Lily more or less likely to have vitamin D deficiency than Ivy?", "id": "3720353610", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "The epidermis also contains melanocytes, which are cells that produce melanin. Melanin is the brownish pigment that gives skin much of its color. Everyone has about the same number of melanocytes, but the melanocytes of people with darker skin produce more melanin. The amount of melanin produced is determined by heredity and exposure to UV light, which increases melanin output. Exposure to UV light also stimulates the skin to produce vitamin D. Because melanin blocks UV light from penetrating the skin, people with darker skin may be at greater risk of vitamin D deficiency.", "situation": "Lily and Ivy are biological sisters. Due to genetics, Lily has much lighter skin than Ivy, who is fairly dark complected.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Ivy more or less likely to have vitamin D deficiency than Lily?", "id": "3698988874", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "The epidermis also contains melanocytes, which are cells that produce melanin. Melanin is the brownish pigment that gives skin much of its color. Everyone has about the same number of melanocytes, but the melanocytes of people with darker skin produce more melanin. The amount of melanin produced is determined by heredity and exposure to UV light, which increases melanin output. Exposure to UV light also stimulates the skin to produce vitamin D. Because melanin blocks UV light from penetrating the skin, people with darker skin may be at greater risk of vitamin D deficiency.", "situation": "Lily and Ivy are biological sisters. Due to genetics, Lily has much lighter skin than Ivy, who is fairly dark complected.", "qas": [{"question": "Which sister is more likely to experience vitamin D deficiency?", "id": "3088586502", "answers": [{"text": "Ivy"}]}]}, {"background": "The epidermis also contains melanocytes, which are cells that produce melanin. Melanin is the brownish pigment that gives skin much of its color. Everyone has about the same number of melanocytes, but the melanocytes of people with darker skin produce more melanin. The amount of melanin produced is determined by heredity and exposure to UV light, which increases melanin output. Exposure to UV light also stimulates the skin to produce vitamin D. Because melanin blocks UV light from penetrating the skin, people with darker skin may be at greater risk of vitamin D deficiency.", "situation": "Lily and Ivy are biological sisters. Due to genetics, Lily has much lighter skin than Ivy, who is fairly dark complected.", "qas": [{"question": "Which sister is less likely to experience vitamin D deficiency?", "id": "3098679050", "answers": [{"text": "Lily"}]}]}, {"background": "The epidermis also contains melanocytes, which are cells that produce melanin. Melanin is the brownish pigment that gives skin much of its color. Everyone has about the same number of melanocytes, but the melanocytes of people with darker skin produce more melanin. The amount of melanin produced is determined by heredity and exposure to UV light, which increases melanin output. Exposure to UV light also stimulates the skin to produce vitamin D. Because melanin blocks UV light from penetrating the skin, people with darker skin may be at greater risk of vitamin D deficiency.", "situation": "Lily and Ivy are biological sisters. Due to genetics, Lily has much lighter skin than Ivy, who is fairly dark complected.", "qas": [{"question": "If Lily sunbathes and her skin gets darker, will her melanin production increase or decrease?", "id": "4026671556", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "At sea level, a mercury column will rise a distance of 760 mm. This atmospheric pressure is reported as 760 mmHg (millimeters of mercury). At higher altitudes, the atmospheric pressure is decreased and so the column of mercury will not rise as high. On the summit of Mt. Everest (elevation of 8848 m), the air pressure is 253 mmHg. Atmospheric pressure is slightly dependent on weather conditions. From the graph we can see the decrease in atmospheric pressure as the altitude increases. At sea level, the atmospheric pressure would be a little over 100 kPa (one atmosphere or 760 mm Hg). If we climb to the top of Mount Everest (the highest mountain in the world at 29,029 feet or 8848 meters), the atmospheric pressure will drop to slightly over 30 kPa (about 0.30 atmospheres or 228 mm Hg). This marked decrease in atmospheric pressure results in much lower levels of oxygen. Teams that climb this mountain must bring supplies of oxygen with them in order to breathe at these high altitudes.", "situation": "Danny is taking a team of hikers on a mountain climb. He has a choice between two mountains, Mount Everest and Mount Kamet. He knows Mount Everest is higher than Mount Kamet, and he is trying to determine the atmospheric pressure of each mountain in order to determine how much of an oxygen supply the hikers must bring.", "qas": [{"question": "Which mountain will have a lower atmospheric pressure?", "id": "1144121308", "answers": [{"text": "Mount Everest"}]}]}, {"background": "At sea level, a mercury column will rise a distance of 760 mm. This atmospheric pressure is reported as 760 mmHg (millimeters of mercury). At higher altitudes, the atmospheric pressure is decreased and so the column of mercury will not rise as high. On the summit of Mt. Everest (elevation of 8848 m), the air pressure is 253 mmHg. Atmospheric pressure is slightly dependent on weather conditions. From the graph we can see the decrease in atmospheric pressure as the altitude increases. At sea level, the atmospheric pressure would be a little over 100 kPa (one atmosphere or 760 mm Hg). If we climb to the top of Mount Everest (the highest mountain in the world at 29,029 feet or 8848 meters), the atmospheric pressure will drop to slightly over 30 kPa (about 0.30 atmospheres or 228 mm Hg). This marked decrease in atmospheric pressure results in much lower levels of oxygen. Teams that climb this mountain must bring supplies of oxygen with them in order to breathe at these high altitudes.", "situation": "Danny is taking a team of hikers on a mountain climb. He has a choice between two mountains, Mount Everest and Mount Kamet. He knows Mount Everest is higher than Mount Kamet, and he is trying to determine the atmospheric pressure of each mountain in order to determine how much of an oxygen supply the hikers must bring.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Mount Everest have a higher or lower atmospheric pressure than Mount Kamet?", "id": "947646711", "answers": [{"text": "lower"}]}]}, {"background": "At sea level, a mercury column will rise a distance of 760 mm. This atmospheric pressure is reported as 760 mmHg (millimeters of mercury). At higher altitudes, the atmospheric pressure is decreased and so the column of mercury will not rise as high. On the summit of Mt. Everest (elevation of 8848 m), the air pressure is 253 mmHg. Atmospheric pressure is slightly dependent on weather conditions. From the graph we can see the decrease in atmospheric pressure as the altitude increases. At sea level, the atmospheric pressure would be a little over 100 kPa (one atmosphere or 760 mm Hg). If we climb to the top of Mount Everest (the highest mountain in the world at 29,029 feet or 8848 meters), the atmospheric pressure will drop to slightly over 30 kPa (about 0.30 atmospheres or 228 mm Hg). This marked decrease in atmospheric pressure results in much lower levels of oxygen. Teams that climb this mountain must bring supplies of oxygen with them in order to breathe at these high altitudes.", "situation": "Danny is taking a team of hikers on a mountain climb. He has a choice between two mountains, Mount Everest and Mount Kamet. He knows Mount Everest is higher than Mount Kamet, and he is trying to determine the atmospheric pressure of each mountain in order to determine how much of an oxygen supply the hikers must bring.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Mount Kamet have a higher or lower atmospheric pressure than Mount Everest?", "id": "761000183", "answers": [{"text": "higher"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Aiden is studying the concept of temperature in his high school physics class. He has two glasses of liquid that are different temperatures and needs to determine the physical differences that exist in each glass. Glass A contains a cold liquid and Glass B contains a hot liquid.", "qas": [{"question": "Which glass has more kinetic energy?", "id": "2855416456", "answers": [{"text": "Glass B"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Aiden is studying the concept of temperature in his high school physics class. He has two glasses of liquid that are different temperatures and needs to determine the physical differences that exist in each glass. Glass A contains a cold liquid and Glass B contains a hot liquid.", "qas": [{"question": "Which glass has less kinetic energy?", "id": "2858431116", "answers": [{"text": "Glass A"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Aiden is studying the concept of temperature in his high school physics class. He has two glasses of liquid that are different temperatures and needs to determine the physical differences that exist in each glass. Glass A contains a cold liquid and Glass B contains a hot liquid.", "qas": [{"question": "In which glass are the particles of matter moving more quickly?", "id": "2157722758", "answers": [{"text": "Glass B"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Aiden is studying the concept of temperature in his high school physics class. He has two glasses of liquid that are different temperatures and needs to determine the physical differences that exist in each glass. Glass A contains a cold liquid and Glass B contains a hot liquid.", "qas": [{"question": "In which glass are the particles of matter moving slower?", "id": "468793933", "answers": [{"text": "Glass A"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Aiden is studying the concept of temperature in his high school physics class. He has two glasses of liquid that are different temperatures and needs to determine the physical differences that exist in each glass. Glass A contains a cold liquid and Glass B contains a hot liquid.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the particles of matter in Glass A moving faster or slower than the particles of matter in Glass B?", "id": "30755369", "answers": [{"text": "slower"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Aiden is studying the concept of temperature in his high school physics class. He has two glasses of liquid that are different temperatures and needs to determine the physical differences that exist in each glass. Glass A contains a cold liquid and Glass B contains a hot liquid.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the particles of matter in Glass B moving faster or slower than the particles of matter in Glass A?", "id": "34949673", "answers": [{"text": "faster"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Aiden is studying the concept of temperature in his high school physics class. He has two glasses of liquid that are different temperatures and needs to determine the physical differences that exist in each glass. Glass A contains a cold liquid and Glass B contains a hot liquid.", "qas": [{"question": "Does the liquid in Glass B have more or less kinetic energy than the liquid in Glass A?", "id": "1826505704", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Aiden is studying the concept of temperature in his high school physics class. He has two glasses of liquid that are different temperatures and needs to determine the physical differences that exist in each glass. Glass A contains a cold liquid and Glass B contains a hot liquid.", "qas": [{"question": "If the liquid in Glass A is heated, will the kinetic energy increase or decrease?", "id": "3314303497", "answers": [{"text": "increase"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Aiden is studying the concept of temperature in his high school physics class. He has two glasses of liquid that are different temperatures and needs to determine the physical differences that exist in each glass. Glass A contains a cold liquid and Glass B contains a hot liquid.", "qas": [{"question": "If the liquid in Glass B is cooled, will the kinetic energy increase or decrease?", "id": "3355394581", "answers": [{"text": "decrease"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Ryan is experimenting with how temperature affects matter. To do this, he tests how temperature changes the particles in each of two samples of water: sample A is boiling water, and sample B is frozen water.", "qas": [{"question": "Does sample B have more or less kinetic energy than sample A?", "id": "3168936121", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Ryan is experimenting with how temperature affects matter. To do this, he tests how temperature changes the particles in each of two samples of water: sample A is boiling water, and sample B is frozen water.", "qas": [{"question": "Which sample has higher kinetic energy, sample A or sample B?", "id": "3422691497", "answers": [{"text": "sample A"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Ryan is experimenting with how temperature affects matter. To do this, he tests how temperature changes the particles in each of two samples of water: sample A is boiling water, and sample B is frozen water.", "qas": [{"question": "Which sample has lower kinetic energy, sample A or sample B?", "id": "2907447387", "answers": [{"text": "sample B"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Ryan is experimenting with how temperature affects matter. To do this, he tests how temperature changes the particles in each of two samples of water: sample A is boiling water, and sample B is frozen water.", "qas": [{"question": "In which sample are the particles moving more quickly, sample A or sample B?", "id": "3938264641", "answers": [{"text": "sample a"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Ryan is experimenting with how temperature affects matter. To do this, he tests how temperature changes the particles in each of two samples of water: sample A is boiling water, and sample B is frozen water.", "qas": [{"question": "In which sample are the particles moving slower, sample A or sample B?", "id": "101786632", "answers": [{"text": "sample B"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Ryan is experimenting with how temperature affects matter. To do this, he tests how temperature changes the particles in each of two samples of water: sample A is boiling water, and sample B is frozen water.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the particles in sample A moving quicker or slower than sample B?", "id": "3734119398", "answers": [{"text": "quicker"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Ryan is experimenting with how temperature affects matter. To do this, he tests how temperature changes the particles in each of two samples of water: sample A is boiling water, and sample B is frozen water.", "qas": [{"question": "Are the particles in sample B moving quicker or slower than sample A?", "id": "3736675302", "answers": [{"text": "slower"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Ryan is experimenting with how temperature affects matter. To do this, he tests how temperature changes the particles in each of two samples of water: sample A is boiling water, and sample B is frozen water.", "qas": [{"question": "Which sample feels warmer, sample A or sample B?", "id": "923278306", "answers": [{"text": "sample A"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Ryan is experimenting with how temperature affects matter. To do this, he tests how temperature changes the particles in each of two samples of water: sample A is boiling water, and sample B is frozen water.", "qas": [{"question": "Which sample feels cooler, sample A or sample B?", "id": "903945176", "answers": [{"text": "sample B"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Ryan is experimenting with how temperature affects matter. To do this, he tests how temperature changes the particles in each of two samples of water: sample A is boiling water, and sample B is frozen water.", "qas": [{"question": "Does sample A feel warmer or cooler than sample B?", "id": "1729043624", "answers": [{"text": "warmer"}]}]}, {"background": "No doubt you already have a good idea of what temperature is. You might say that it\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s how warm or cool something feels. In physics, temperature is defined as the average kinetic energy of the particles of matter. When particles of matter move more quickly, they have more kinetic energy, so their temperature is higher. With a higher temperature, matter feels warmer. When particles move more slowly, they have less kinetic energy on average, so their temperature is lower. With a lower temperature, matter feels cooler.", "situation": "Ryan is experimenting with how temperature affects matter. To do this, he tests how temperature changes the particles in each of two samples of water: sample A is boiling water, and sample B is frozen water.", "qas": [{"question": "Does sample B feel warmer or cooler than sample A?", "id": "1731402920", "answers": [{"text": "cooler"}]}]}, {"background": "Figure above summarizes the basic transitions that a substance may undergo as a result of changes in temperature or pressure. For any phase change, energy will be either released (for exothermic processes) or absorbed from the surroundings (for endothermic processes). Processes in which intermolecular interactions are weakened or broken (melting, vaporization, and sublimation) require an input of energy; they are endothermic. Processes in which attractive interactions are formed (freezing, condensation, and deposition) release energy, so they are exothermic.", "situation": "Bethany is curious about the changes that occur when water changes states due to temperature changes. To study this, she observes two different units of water. Unit A is frozen and will be heated until melted. Unit B is liquid and will be cooled until frozen.", "qas": [{"question": "Which unit of water will be undergoing an exothermic process?", "id": "1540048439", "answers": [{"text": "Unit B"}]}]}, {"background": "Figure above summarizes the basic transitions that a substance may undergo as a result of changes in temperature or pressure. For any phase change, energy will be either released (for exothermic processes) or absorbed from the surroundings (for endothermic processes). Processes in which intermolecular interactions are weakened or broken (melting, vaporization, and sublimation) require an input of energy; they are endothermic. Processes in which attractive interactions are formed (freezing, condensation, and deposition) release energy, so they are exothermic.", "situation": "Bethany is curious about the changes that occur when water changes states due to temperature changes. To study this, she observes two different units of water. Unit A is frozen and will be heated until melted. Unit B is liquid and will be cooled until frozen.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Unit A be undergoing an endothermic or exothermic process?", "id": "3630778048", "answers": [{"text": "endothermic"}]}]}, {"background": "Figure above summarizes the basic transitions that a substance may undergo as a result of changes in temperature or pressure. For any phase change, energy will be either released (for exothermic processes) or absorbed from the surroundings (for endothermic processes). Processes in which intermolecular interactions are weakened or broken (melting, vaporization, and sublimation) require an input of energy; they are endothermic. Processes in which attractive interactions are formed (freezing, condensation, and deposition) release energy, so they are exothermic.", "situation": "Bethany is curious about the changes that occur when water changes states due to temperature changes. To study this, she observes two different units of water. Unit A is frozen and will be heated until melted. Unit B is liquid and will be cooled until frozen.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Unit B be undergoing an endothermic or exothermic process?", "id": "3634251457", "answers": [{"text": "exothermic"}]}]}, {"background": "Figure above summarizes the basic transitions that a substance may undergo as a result of changes in temperature or pressure. For any phase change, energy will be either released (for exothermic processes) or absorbed from the surroundings (for endothermic processes). Processes in which intermolecular interactions are weakened or broken (melting, vaporization, and sublimation) require an input of energy; they are endothermic. Processes in which attractive interactions are formed (freezing, condensation, and deposition) release energy, so they are exothermic.", "situation": "Bethany is curious about the changes that occur when water changes states due to temperature changes. To study this, she observes two different units of water. Unit A is frozen and will be heated until melted. Unit B is liquid and will be cooled until frozen.", "qas": [{"question": "In which unit will attractive interactions be formed?", "id": "1064190821", "answers": [{"text": "Unit B"}]}]}, {"background": "Figure above summarizes the basic transitions that a substance may undergo as a result of changes in temperature or pressure. For any phase change, energy will be either released (for exothermic processes) or absorbed from the surroundings (for endothermic processes). Processes in which intermolecular interactions are weakened or broken (melting, vaporization, and sublimation) require an input of energy; they are endothermic. Processes in which attractive interactions are formed (freezing, condensation, and deposition) release energy, so they are exothermic.", "situation": "Bethany is curious about the changes that occur when water changes states due to temperature changes. To study this, she observes two different units of water. Unit A is frozen and will be heated until melted. Unit B is liquid and will be cooled until frozen.", "qas": [{"question": "For which unit will the change in state cause energy to be released?", "id": "1093814288", "answers": [{"text": "Unit B"}]}]}, {"background": "Figure above summarizes the basic transitions that a substance may undergo as a result of changes in temperature or pressure. For any phase change, energy will be either released (for exothermic processes) or absorbed from the surroundings (for endothermic processes). Processes in which intermolecular interactions are weakened or broken (melting, vaporization, and sublimation) require an input of energy; they are endothermic. Processes in which attractive interactions are formed (freezing, condensation, and deposition) release energy, so they are exothermic.", "situation": "Bethany is curious about the changes that occur when water changes states due to temperature changes. To study this, she observes two different units of water. Unit A is frozen and will be heated until melted. Unit B is liquid and will be cooled until frozen.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the change in state for unit A cause energy to be released or absorbed?", "id": "2093632161", "answers": [{"text": "absorbed"}]}]}, {"background": "Figure above summarizes the basic transitions that a substance may undergo as a result of changes in temperature or pressure. For any phase change, energy will be either released (for exothermic processes) or absorbed from the surroundings (for endothermic processes). Processes in which intermolecular interactions are weakened or broken (melting, vaporization, and sublimation) require an input of energy; they are endothermic. Processes in which attractive interactions are formed (freezing, condensation, and deposition) release energy, so they are exothermic.", "situation": "Bethany is curious about the changes that occur when water changes states due to temperature changes. To study this, she observes two different units of water. Unit A is frozen and will be heated until melted. Unit B is liquid and will be cooled until frozen.", "qas": [{"question": "Will the change in state for unit B cause energy to be released or absorbed?", "id": "2096384674", "answers": [{"text": "released"}]}]}, {"background": "Aggressive resemblance is used by predators or parasites. In special aggressive resemblance, the animal looks like something else, luring the prey or host to approach, for example when a flower mantis resembles a particular kind of flower, such as an orchid. In general aggressive resemblance, the predator or parasite blends in with the background, for example when a leopard is hard to see in long grass.For adventitious protection, an animal uses materials such as twigs, sand, or pieces of shell to conceal its outline, for example when a caddis fly larva builds a decorated case, or when a decorator crab decorates its back with seaweed, sponges and stones.In variable protective resemblance, an animal such as a chameleon, flatfish, squid or octopus changes its skin pattern and color using special chromatophore cells to resemble whatever background it is currently resting on (as well as for signalling).The main mechanisms to create the resemblances described by Poulton \u00e2\u20ac\u201c whether in nature or in military applications \u00e2\u20ac\u201c are crypsis, blending into the background so as to become hard to see (this covers both special and general resemblance); disruptive patterning, using color and pattern to break up the animal's outline, which relates mainly to general resemblance; mimesis, resembling other objects of no special interest to the observer, which relates to special resemblance; countershading, using graded color to create the illusion of flatness, which relates mainly to general resemblance; and counterillumination, producing light to match the background, notably in some species of squid.Countershading was first described by the American artist Abbott Handerson Thayer, a pioneer in the theory of animal coloration. Thayer observed that whereas a painter takes a flat canvas and uses colored paint to create the illusion of solidity by painting in shadows, animals such as deer are often darkest on their backs, becoming lighter towards the belly, creating (as zoologist Hugh Cott observed) the illusion of flatness, and against a matching background, of invisibility. Thayer's observation \"Animals are painted by Nature, darkest on those parts which tend to be most lighted by the sky's light, and vice versa\" is called Thayer's Law.", "situation": "Dwight is studying a new region of a rainforest that has been previously unexplored. He is observing the different species of the area and is determining the different mechanisms by which these species disguise themselves in order to hide from prey in order to correctly classify them. Dwight observes that Species A blends into the background of its surroundings to disguise itself; Species B uses color to break up the outline of its body to disguise itself; Species C is able to resemble a flower that its prey is not interested in to disguise itself; Species D is able to adjust its color to appear flat and blend in to the ground to disguise itself; and Species E is able to produce light that helps it match the background of its surroundings to disguise itself.", "qas": [{"question": "Which species is using crypsis to disguise itself?", "id": "3938805755", "answers": [{"text": "Species A"}]}]}, {"background": "Aggressive resemblance is used by predators or parasites. In special aggressive resemblance, the animal looks like something else, luring the prey or host to approach, for example when a flower mantis resembles a particular kind of flower, such as an orchid. In general aggressive resemblance, the predator or parasite blends in with the background, for example when a leopard is hard to see in long grass.For adventitious protection, an animal uses materials such as twigs, sand, or pieces of shell to conceal its outline, for example when a caddis fly larva builds a decorated case, or when a decorator crab decorates its back with seaweed, sponges and stones.In variable protective resemblance, an animal such as a chameleon, flatfish, squid or octopus changes its skin pattern and color using special chromatophore cells to resemble whatever background it is currently resting on (as well as for signalling).The main mechanisms to create the resemblances described by Poulton \u00e2\u20ac\u201c whether in nature or in military applications \u00e2\u20ac\u201c are crypsis, blending into the background so as to become hard to see (this covers both special and general resemblance); disruptive patterning, using color and pattern to break up the animal's outline, which relates mainly to general resemblance; mimesis, resembling other objects of no special interest to the observer, which relates to special resemblance; countershading, using graded color to create the illusion of flatness, which relates mainly to general resemblance; and counterillumination, producing light to match the background, notably in some species of squid.Countershading was first described by the American artist Abbott Handerson Thayer, a pioneer in the theory of animal coloration. Thayer observed that whereas a painter takes a flat canvas and uses colored paint to create the illusion of solidity by painting in shadows, animals such as deer are often darkest on their backs, becoming lighter towards the belly, creating (as zoologist Hugh Cott observed) the illusion of flatness, and against a matching background, of invisibility. Thayer's observation \"Animals are painted by Nature, darkest on those parts which tend to be most lighted by the sky's light, and vice versa\" is called Thayer's Law.", "situation": "Dwight is studying a new region of a rainforest that has been previously unexplored. He is observing the different species of the area and is determining the different mechanisms by which these species disguise themselves in order to hide from prey in order to correctly classify them. Dwight observes that Species A blends into the background of its surroundings to disguise itself; Species B uses color to break up the outline of its body to disguise itself; Species C is able to resemble a flower that its prey is not interested in to disguise itself; Species D is able to adjust its color to appear flat and blend in to the ground to disguise itself; and Species E is able to produce light that helps it match the background of its surroundings to disguise itself.", "qas": [{"question": "Which species is using disruptive patterning to disguise itself?", "id": "3431755161", "answers": [{"text": "Species B"}]}]}, {"background": "Aggressive resemblance is used by predators or parasites. In special aggressive resemblance, the animal looks like something else, luring the prey or host to approach, for example when a flower mantis resembles a particular kind of flower, such as an orchid. In general aggressive resemblance, the predator or parasite blends in with the background, for example when a leopard is hard to see in long grass.For adventitious protection, an animal uses materials such as twigs, sand, or pieces of shell to conceal its outline, for example when a caddis fly larva builds a decorated case, or when a decorator crab decorates its back with seaweed, sponges and stones.In variable protective resemblance, an animal such as a chameleon, flatfish, squid or octopus changes its skin pattern and color using special chromatophore cells to resemble whatever background it is currently resting on (as well as for signalling).The main mechanisms to create the resemblances described by Poulton \u00e2\u20ac\u201c whether in nature or in military applications \u00e2\u20ac\u201c are crypsis, blending into the background so as to become hard to see (this covers both special and general resemblance); disruptive patterning, using color and pattern to break up the animal's outline, which relates mainly to general resemblance; mimesis, resembling other objects of no special interest to the observer, which relates to special resemblance; countershading, using graded color to create the illusion of flatness, which relates mainly to general resemblance; and counterillumination, producing light to match the background, notably in some species of squid.Countershading was first described by the American artist Abbott Handerson Thayer, a pioneer in the theory of animal coloration. Thayer observed that whereas a painter takes a flat canvas and uses colored paint to create the illusion of solidity by painting in shadows, animals such as deer are often darkest on their backs, becoming lighter towards the belly, creating (as zoologist Hugh Cott observed) the illusion of flatness, and against a matching background, of invisibility. Thayer's observation \"Animals are painted by Nature, darkest on those parts which tend to be most lighted by the sky's light, and vice versa\" is called Thayer's Law.", "situation": "Dwight is studying a new region of a rainforest that has been previously unexplored. He is observing the different species of the area and is determining the different mechanisms by which these species disguise themselves in order to hide from prey in order to correctly classify them. Dwight observes that Species A blends into the background of its surroundings to disguise itself; Species B uses color to break up the outline of its body to disguise itself; Species C is able to resemble a flower that its prey is not interested in to disguise itself; Species D is able to adjust its color to appear flat and blend in to the ground to disguise itself; and Species E is able to produce light that helps it match the background of its surroundings to disguise itself.", "qas": [{"question": "Which species is using mimesis to disguise itself?", "id": "3904202725", "answers": [{"text": "Species C"}]}]}, {"background": "Aggressive resemblance is used by predators or parasites. In special aggressive resemblance, the animal looks like something else, luring the prey or host to approach, for example when a flower mantis resembles a particular kind of flower, such as an orchid. In general aggressive resemblance, the predator or parasite blends in with the background, for example when a leopard is hard to see in long grass.For adventitious protection, an animal uses materials such as twigs, sand, or pieces of shell to conceal its outline, for example when a caddis fly larva builds a decorated case, or when a decorator crab decorates its back with seaweed, sponges and stones.In variable protective resemblance, an animal such as a chameleon, flatfish, squid or octopus changes its skin pattern and color using special chromatophore cells to resemble whatever background it is currently resting on (as well as for signalling).The main mechanisms to create the resemblances described by Poulton \u00e2\u20ac\u201c whether in nature or in military applications \u00e2\u20ac\u201c are crypsis, blending into the background so as to become hard to see (this covers both special and general resemblance); disruptive patterning, using color and pattern to break up the animal's outline, which relates mainly to general resemblance; mimesis, resembling other objects of no special interest to the observer, which relates to special resemblance; countershading, using graded color to create the illusion of flatness, which relates mainly to general resemblance; and counterillumination, producing light to match the background, notably in some species of squid.Countershading was first described by the American artist Abbott Handerson Thayer, a pioneer in the theory of animal coloration. Thayer observed that whereas a painter takes a flat canvas and uses colored paint to create the illusion of solidity by painting in shadows, animals such as deer are often darkest on their backs, becoming lighter towards the belly, creating (as zoologist Hugh Cott observed) the illusion of flatness, and against a matching background, of invisibility. Thayer's observation \"Animals are painted by Nature, darkest on those parts which tend to be most lighted by the sky's light, and vice versa\" is called Thayer's Law.", "situation": "Dwight is studying a new region of a rainforest that has been previously unexplored. He is observing the different species of the area and is determining the different mechanisms by which these species disguise themselves in order to hide from prey in order to correctly classify them. Dwight observes that Species A blends into the background of its surroundings to disguise itself; Species B uses color to break up the outline of its body to disguise itself; Species C is able to resemble a flower that its prey is not interested in to disguise itself; Species D is able to adjust its color to appear flat and blend in to the ground to disguise itself; and Species E is able to produce light that helps it match the background of its surroundings to disguise itself.", "qas": [{"question": "Which species is using countershading to disguise itself?", "id": "3528616652", "answers": [{"text": "Species D"}]}]}, {"background": "Aggressive resemblance is used by predators or parasites. In special aggressive resemblance, the animal looks like something else, luring the prey or host to approach, for example when a flower mantis resembles a particular kind of flower, such as an orchid. In general aggressive resemblance, the predator or parasite blends in with the background, for example when a leopard is hard to see in long grass.For adventitious protection, an animal uses materials such as twigs, sand, or pieces of shell to conceal its outline, for example when a caddis fly larva builds a decorated case, or when a decorator crab decorates its back with seaweed, sponges and stones.In variable protective resemblance, an animal such as a chameleon, flatfish, squid or octopus changes its skin pattern and color using special chromatophore cells to resemble whatever background it is currently resting on (as well as for signalling).The main mechanisms to create the resemblances described by Poulton \u00e2\u20ac\u201c whether in nature or in military applications \u00e2\u20ac\u201c are crypsis, blending into the background so as to become hard to see (this covers both special and general resemblance); disruptive patterning, using color and pattern to break up the animal's outline, which relates mainly to general resemblance; mimesis, resembling other objects of no special interest to the observer, which relates to special resemblance; countershading, using graded color to create the illusion of flatness, which relates mainly to general resemblance; and counterillumination, producing light to match the background, notably in some species of squid.Countershading was first described by the American artist Abbott Handerson Thayer, a pioneer in the theory of animal coloration. Thayer observed that whereas a painter takes a flat canvas and uses colored paint to create the illusion of solidity by painting in shadows, animals such as deer are often darkest on their backs, becoming lighter towards the belly, creating (as zoologist Hugh Cott observed) the illusion of flatness, and against a matching background, of invisibility. Thayer's observation \"Animals are painted by Nature, darkest on those parts which tend to be most lighted by the sky's light, and vice versa\" is called Thayer's Law.", "situation": "Dwight is studying a new region of a rainforest that has been previously unexplored. He is observing the different species of the area and is determining the different mechanisms by which these species disguise themselves in order to hide from prey in order to correctly classify them. Dwight observes that Species A blends into the background of its surroundings to disguise itself; Species B uses color to break up the outline of its body to disguise itself; Species C is able to resemble a flower that its prey is not interested in to disguise itself; Species D is able to adjust its color to appear flat and blend in to the ground to disguise itself; and Species E is able to produce light that helps it match the background of its surroundings to disguise itself.", "qas": [{"question": "Which species is using counterillumination to disguise itself?", "id": "4141378819", "answers": [{"text": "Species E"}]}]}, {"background": "Aggressive resemblance is used by predators or parasites. In special aggressive resemblance, the animal looks like something else, luring the prey or host to approach, for example when a flower mantis resembles a particular kind of flower, such as an orchid. In general aggressive resemblance, the predator or parasite blends in with the background, for example when a leopard is hard to see in long grass.For adventitious protection, an animal uses materials such as twigs, sand, or pieces of shell to conceal its outline, for example when a caddis fly larva builds a decorated case, or when a decorator crab decorates its back with seaweed, sponges and stones.In variable protective resemblance, an animal such as a chameleon, flatfish, squid or octopus changes its skin pattern and color using special chromatophore cells to resemble whatever background it is currently resting on (as well as for signalling).The main mechanisms to create the resemblances described by Poulton \u00e2\u20ac\u201c whether in nature or in military applications \u00e2\u20ac\u201c are crypsis, blending into the background so as to become hard to see (this covers both special and general resemblance); disruptive patterning, using color and pattern to break up the animal's outline, which relates mainly to general resemblance; mimesis, resembling other objects of no special interest to the observer, which relates to special resemblance; countershading, using graded color to create the illusion of flatness, which relates mainly to general resemblance; and counterillumination, producing light to match the background, notably in some species of squid.Countershading was first described by the American artist Abbott Handerson Thayer, a pioneer in the theory of animal coloration. Thayer observed that whereas a painter takes a flat canvas and uses colored paint to create the illusion of solidity by painting in shadows, animals such as deer are often darkest on their backs, becoming lighter towards the belly, creating (as zoologist Hugh Cott observed) the illusion of flatness, and against a matching background, of invisibility. Thayer's observation \"Animals are painted by Nature, darkest on those parts which tend to be most lighted by the sky's light, and vice versa\" is called Thayer's Law.", "situation": "Dwight is studying a new region of a rainforest that has been previously unexplored. He is observing the different species of the area and is determining the different mechanisms by which these species disguise themselves in order to hide from prey in order to correctly classify them. Dwight observes that Species A blends into the background of its surroundings to disguise itself; Species B uses color to break up the outline of its body to disguise itself; Species C is able to resemble a flower that its prey is not interested in to disguise itself; Species D is able to adjust its color to appear flat and blend in to the ground to disguise itself; and Species E is able to produce light that helps it match the background of its surroundings to disguise itself.", "qas": [{"question": "Which species is using general resemblance mechanisms to disguise itself?", "id": "2852483253", "answers": [{"text": "Species B"}]}]}, {"background": "Aggressive resemblance is used by predators or parasites. In special aggressive resemblance, the animal looks like something else, luring the prey or host to approach, for example when a flower mantis resembles a particular kind of flower, such as an orchid. In general aggressive resemblance, the predator or parasite blends in with the background, for example when a leopard is hard to see in long grass.For adventitious protection, an animal uses materials such as twigs, sand, or pieces of shell to conceal its outline, for example when a caddis fly larva builds a decorated case, or when a decorator crab decorates its back with seaweed, sponges and stones.In variable protective resemblance, an animal such as a chameleon, flatfish, squid or octopus changes its skin pattern and color using special chromatophore cells to resemble whatever background it is currently resting on (as well as for signalling).The main mechanisms to create the resemblances described by Poulton \u00e2\u20ac\u201c whether in nature or in military applications \u00e2\u20ac\u201c are crypsis, blending into the background so as to become hard to see (this covers both special and general resemblance); disruptive patterning, using color and pattern to break up the animal's outline, which relates mainly to general resemblance; mimesis, resembling other objects of no special interest to the observer, which relates to special resemblance; countershading, using graded color to create the illusion of flatness, which relates mainly to general resemblance; and counterillumination, producing light to match the background, notably in some species of squid.Countershading was first described by the American artist Abbott Handerson Thayer, a pioneer in the theory of animal coloration. Thayer observed that whereas a painter takes a flat canvas and uses colored paint to create the illusion of solidity by painting in shadows, animals such as deer are often darkest on their backs, becoming lighter towards the belly, creating (as zoologist Hugh Cott observed) the illusion of flatness, and against a matching background, of invisibility. Thayer's observation \"Animals are painted by Nature, darkest on those parts which tend to be most lighted by the sky's light, and vice versa\" is called Thayer's Law.", "situation": "Dwight is studying a new region of a rainforest that has been previously unexplored. He is observing the different species of the area and is determining the different mechanisms by which these species disguise themselves in order to hide from prey in order to correctly classify them. Dwight observes that Species A blends into the background of its surroundings to disguise itself; Species B uses color to break up the outline of its body to disguise itself; Species C is able to resemble a flower that its prey is not interested in to disguise itself; Species D is able to adjust its color to appear flat and blend in to the ground to disguise itself; and Species E is able to produce light that helps it match the background of its surroundings to disguise itself.", "qas": [{"question": "Which species is using a special resemblance mechanism, Species B or Species C?", "id": "935817577", "answers": [{"text": "Species C"}]}]}, {"background": "Aggressive resemblance is used by predators or parasites. In special aggressive resemblance, the animal looks like something else, luring the prey or host to approach, for example when a flower mantis resembles a particular kind of flower, such as an orchid. In general aggressive resemblance, the predator or parasite blends in with the background, for example when a leopard is hard to see in long grass.For adventitious protection, an animal uses materials such as twigs, sand, or pieces of shell to conceal its outline, for example when a caddis fly larva builds a decorated case, or when a decorator crab decorates its back with seaweed, sponges and stones.In variable protective resemblance, an animal such as a chameleon, flatfish, squid or octopus changes its skin pattern and color using special chromatophore cells to resemble whatever background it is currently resting on (as well as for signalling).The main mechanisms to create the resemblances described by Poulton \u00e2\u20ac\u201c whether in nature or in military applications \u00e2\u20ac\u201c are crypsis, blending into the background so as to become hard to see (this covers both special and general resemblance); disruptive patterning, using color and pattern to break up the animal's outline, which relates mainly to general resemblance; mimesis, resembling other objects of no special interest to the observer, which relates to special resemblance; countershading, using graded color to create the illusion of flatness, which relates mainly to general resemblance; and counterillumination, producing light to match the background, notably in some species of squid.Countershading was first described by the American artist Abbott Handerson Thayer, a pioneer in the theory of animal coloration. Thayer observed that whereas a painter takes a flat canvas and uses colored paint to create the illusion of solidity by painting in shadows, animals such as deer are often darkest on their backs, becoming lighter towards the belly, creating (as zoologist Hugh Cott observed) the illusion of flatness, and against a matching background, of invisibility. Thayer's observation \"Animals are painted by Nature, darkest on those parts which tend to be most lighted by the sky's light, and vice versa\" is called Thayer's Law.", "situation": "Dwight is studying a new region of a rainforest that has been previously unexplored. He is observing the different species of the area and is determining the different mechanisms by which these species disguise themselves in order to hide from prey in order to correctly classify them. Dwight observes that Species A blends into the background of its surroundings to disguise itself; Species B uses color to break up the outline of its body to disguise itself; Species C is able to resemble a flower that its prey is not interested in to disguise itself; Species D is able to adjust its color to appear flat and blend in to the ground to disguise itself; and Species E is able to produce light that helps it match the background of its surroundings to disguise itself.", "qas": [{"question": "Which species is using a special resemblance mechanism, Species C or Species D?", "id": "936931691", "answers": [{"text": "Species C"}]}]}, {"background": "Aggressive resemblance is used by predators or parasites. In special aggressive resemblance, the animal looks like something else, luring the prey or host to approach, for example when a flower mantis resembles a particular kind of flower, such as an orchid. In general aggressive resemblance, the predator or parasite blends in with the background, for example when a leopard is hard to see in long grass.For adventitious protection, an animal uses materials such as twigs, sand, or pieces of shell to conceal its outline, for example when a caddis fly larva builds a decorated case, or when a decorator crab decorates its back with seaweed, sponges and stones.In variable protective resemblance, an animal such as a chameleon, flatfish, squid or octopus changes its skin pattern and color using special chromatophore cells to resemble whatever background it is currently resting on (as well as for signalling).The main mechanisms to create the resemblances described by Poulton \u00e2\u20ac\u201c whether in nature or in military applications \u00e2\u20ac\u201c are crypsis, blending into the background so as to become hard to see (this covers both special and general resemblance); disruptive patterning, using color and pattern to break up the animal's outline, which relates mainly to general resemblance; mimesis, resembling other objects of no special interest to the observer, which relates to special resemblance; countershading, using graded color to create the illusion of flatness, which relates mainly to general resemblance; and counterillumination, producing light to match the background, notably in some species of squid.Countershading was first described by the American artist Abbott Handerson Thayer, a pioneer in the theory of animal coloration. Thayer observed that whereas a painter takes a flat canvas and uses colored paint to create the illusion of solidity by painting in shadows, animals such as deer are often darkest on their backs, becoming lighter towards the belly, creating (as zoologist Hugh Cott observed) the illusion of flatness, and against a matching background, of invisibility. Thayer's observation \"Animals are painted by Nature, darkest on those parts which tend to be most lighted by the sky's light, and vice versa\" is called Thayer's Law.", "situation": "Dwight is studying a new region of a rainforest that has been previously unexplored. He is observing the different species of the area and is determining the different mechanisms by which these species disguise themselves in order to hide from prey in order to correctly classify them. Dwight observes that Species A blends into the background of its surroundings to disguise itself; Species B uses color to break up the outline of its body to disguise itself; Species C is able to resemble a flower that its prey is not interested in to disguise itself; Species D is able to adjust its color to appear flat and blend in to the ground to disguise itself; and Species E is able to produce light that helps it match the background of its surroundings to disguise itself.", "qas": [{"question": "Which species is using a general resemblance mechanism, Species C or Species D?", "id": "923103592", "answers": [{"text": "Species D"}]}]}, {"background": "Aggressive resemblance is used by predators or parasites. In special aggressive resemblance, the animal looks like something else, luring the prey or host to approach, for example when a flower mantis resembles a particular kind of flower, such as an orchid. In general aggressive resemblance, the predator or parasite blends in with the background, for example when a leopard is hard to see in long grass.For adventitious protection, an animal uses materials such as twigs, sand, or pieces of shell to conceal its outline, for example when a caddis fly larva builds a decorated case, or when a decorator crab decorates its back with seaweed, sponges and stones.In variable protective resemblance, an animal such as a chameleon, flatfish, squid or octopus changes its skin pattern and color using special chromatophore cells to resemble whatever background it is currently resting on (as well as for signalling).The main mechanisms to create the resemblances described by Poulton \u00e2\u20ac\u201c whether in nature or in military applications \u00e2\u20ac\u201c are crypsis, blending into the background so as to become hard to see (this covers both special and general resemblance); disruptive patterning, using color and pattern to break up the animal's outline, which relates mainly to general resemblance; mimesis, resembling other objects of no special interest to the observer, which relates to special resemblance; countershading, using graded color to create the illusion of flatness, which relates mainly to general resemblance; and counterillumination, producing light to match the background, notably in some species of squid.Countershading was first described by the American artist Abbott Handerson Thayer, a pioneer in the theory of animal coloration. Thayer observed that whereas a painter takes a flat canvas and uses colored paint to create the illusion of solidity by painting in shadows, animals such as deer are often darkest on their backs, becoming lighter towards the belly, creating (as zoologist Hugh Cott observed) the illusion of flatness, and against a matching background, of invisibility. Thayer's observation \"Animals are painted by Nature, darkest on those parts which tend to be most lighted by the sky's light, and vice versa\" is called Thayer's Law.", "situation": "Dwight is studying a new region of a rainforest that has been previously unexplored. He is observing the different species of the area and is determining the different mechanisms by which these species disguise themselves in order to hide from prey in order to correctly classify them. Dwight observes that Species A blends into the background of its surroundings to disguise itself; Species B uses color to break up the outline of its body to disguise itself; Species C is able to resemble a flower that its prey is not interested in to disguise itself; Species D is able to adjust its color to appear flat and blend in to the ground to disguise itself; and Species E is able to produce light that helps it match the background of its surroundings to disguise itself.", "qas": [{"question": "Which species uses both general and special resemblance mechanisms?", "id": "88043085", "answers": [{"text": "Species A"}]}]}, {"background": "Depleted soils can be protected from soil erosion by groundcover plants such as naturally growing grasses in agroforestry systems. These help to stabilise the soil as they increase cover compared to short-cycle cropping systems. Soil cover is a crucial factor in preventing erosion. Cleaner water through reduced nutrient and soil surface runoff can be a further advantage of agroforestry. The runoff can be reduced by decreasing its velocity and increasing infiltration into the soil. Compared to row-cropped fields nutrient uptake can be higher and reduce nutrient loss into streams.Further advantages concerning plant growth:", "situation": "Jill owns a very large farm where she grows two types of crops. In Field C she grows corn in rows and there are no groundcover plants in the soil. In Field B she grows beans; the beans are not planted in rows and there is a layer of groundcover plants in the soil. She is curious about how the different styles of growing these crops will affect soil erosion.", "qas": [{"question": "Which field will experience more soil erosion?", "id": "4027940065", "answers": [{"text": "Field C"}]}]}, {"background": "Depleted soils can be protected from soil erosion by groundcover plants such as naturally growing grasses in agroforestry systems. These help to stabilise the soil as they increase cover compared to short-cycle cropping systems. Soil cover is a crucial factor in preventing erosion. Cleaner water through reduced nutrient and soil surface runoff can be a further advantage of agroforestry. The runoff can be reduced by decreasing its velocity and increasing infiltration into the soil. Compared to row-cropped fields nutrient uptake can be higher and reduce nutrient loss into streams.Further advantages concerning plant growth:", "situation": "Jill owns a very large farm where she grows two types of crops. In Field C she grows corn in rows and there are no groundcover plants in the soil. In Field B she grows beans; the beans are not planted in rows and there is a layer of groundcover plants in the soil. She is curious about how the different styles of growing these crops will affect soil erosion.", "qas": [{"question": "Which field will experience less soil erosion?", "id": "4030430437", "answers": [{"text": "Field B"}]}]}, {"background": "Depleted soils can be protected from soil erosion by groundcover plants such as naturally growing grasses in agroforestry systems. These help to stabilise the soil as they increase cover compared to short-cycle cropping systems. Soil cover is a crucial factor in preventing erosion. Cleaner water through reduced nutrient and soil surface runoff can be a further advantage of agroforestry. The runoff can be reduced by decreasing its velocity and increasing infiltration into the soil. Compared to row-cropped fields nutrient uptake can be higher and reduce nutrient loss into streams.Further advantages concerning plant growth:", "situation": "Jill owns a very large farm where she grows two types of crops. In Field C she grows corn in rows and there are no groundcover plants in the soil. In Field B she grows beans; the beans are not planted in rows and there is a layer of groundcover plants in the soil. She is curious about how the different styles of growing these crops will affect soil erosion.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Field C experience more or less soil erosion than Field B?", "id": "1425375738", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Depleted soils can be protected from soil erosion by groundcover plants such as naturally growing grasses in agroforestry systems. These help to stabilise the soil as they increase cover compared to short-cycle cropping systems. Soil cover is a crucial factor in preventing erosion. Cleaner water through reduced nutrient and soil surface runoff can be a further advantage of agroforestry. The runoff can be reduced by decreasing its velocity and increasing infiltration into the soil. Compared to row-cropped fields nutrient uptake can be higher and reduce nutrient loss into streams.Further advantages concerning plant growth:", "situation": "Jill owns a very large farm where she grows two types of crops. In Field C she grows corn in rows and there are no groundcover plants in the soil. In Field B she grows beans; the beans are not planted in rows and there is a layer of groundcover plants in the soil. She is curious about how the different styles of growing these crops will affect soil erosion.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Field B experience more or less soil erosion than Field C?", "id": "1422098938", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Depleted soils can be protected from soil erosion by groundcover plants such as naturally growing grasses in agroforestry systems. These help to stabilise the soil as they increase cover compared to short-cycle cropping systems. Soil cover is a crucial factor in preventing erosion. Cleaner water through reduced nutrient and soil surface runoff can be a further advantage of agroforestry. The runoff can be reduced by decreasing its velocity and increasing infiltration into the soil. Compared to row-cropped fields nutrient uptake can be higher and reduce nutrient loss into streams.Further advantages concerning plant growth:", "situation": "Jill owns a very large farm where she grows two types of crops. In Field C she grows corn in rows and there are no groundcover plants in the soil. In Field B she grows beans; the beans are not planted in rows and there is a layer of groundcover plants in the soil. She is curious about how the different styles of growing these crops will affect soil erosion.", "qas": [{"question": "Which planting system will result in cleaner water due to less runoff, Field B or Field C?", "id": "3507325891", "answers": [{"text": "Field B"}]}]}, {"background": "Depleted soils can be protected from soil erosion by groundcover plants such as naturally growing grasses in agroforestry systems. These help to stabilise the soil as they increase cover compared to short-cycle cropping systems. Soil cover is a crucial factor in preventing erosion. Cleaner water through reduced nutrient and soil surface runoff can be a further advantage of agroforestry. The runoff can be reduced by decreasing its velocity and increasing infiltration into the soil. Compared to row-cropped fields nutrient uptake can be higher and reduce nutrient loss into streams.Further advantages concerning plant growth:", "situation": "Jill owns a very large farm where she grows two types of crops. In Field C she grows corn in rows and there are no groundcover plants in the soil. In Field B she grows beans; the beans are not planted in rows and there is a layer of groundcover plants in the soil. She is curious about how the different styles of growing these crops will affect soil erosion.", "qas": [{"question": "Which planting system will not result in cleaner water due to more runoff, Field B or Field C?", "id": "116690224", "answers": [{"text": "Field C"}]}]}, {"background": "Depleted soils can be protected from soil erosion by groundcover plants such as naturally growing grasses in agroforestry systems. These help to stabilise the soil as they increase cover compared to short-cycle cropping systems. Soil cover is a crucial factor in preventing erosion. Cleaner water through reduced nutrient and soil surface runoff can be a further advantage of agroforestry. The runoff can be reduced by decreasing its velocity and increasing infiltration into the soil. Compared to row-cropped fields nutrient uptake can be higher and reduce nutrient loss into streams.Further advantages concerning plant growth:", "situation": "Jill owns a very large farm where she grows two types of crops. In Field C she grows corn in rows and there are no groundcover plants in the soil. In Field B she grows beans; the beans are not planted in rows and there is a layer of groundcover plants in the soil. She is curious about how the different styles of growing these crops will affect soil erosion.", "qas": [{"question": "Which crops will have higher nutrient uptake, Field B or Field C?", "id": "1850114699", "answers": [{"text": "Field B"}]}]}, {"background": "Depleted soils can be protected from soil erosion by groundcover plants such as naturally growing grasses in agroforestry systems. These help to stabilise the soil as they increase cover compared to short-cycle cropping systems. Soil cover is a crucial factor in preventing erosion. Cleaner water through reduced nutrient and soil surface runoff can be a further advantage of agroforestry. The runoff can be reduced by decreasing its velocity and increasing infiltration into the soil. Compared to row-cropped fields nutrient uptake can be higher and reduce nutrient loss into streams.Further advantages concerning plant growth:", "situation": "Jill owns a very large farm where she grows two types of crops. In Field C she grows corn in rows and there are no groundcover plants in the soil. In Field B she grows beans; the beans are not planted in rows and there is a layer of groundcover plants in the soil. She is curious about how the different styles of growing these crops will affect soil erosion.", "qas": [{"question": "Which crops will have less nutrient uptake, Field B or Field C?", "id": "1727168971", "answers": [{"text": "Field C"}]}]}, {"background": "Depleted soils can be protected from soil erosion by groundcover plants such as naturally growing grasses in agroforestry systems. These help to stabilise the soil as they increase cover compared to short-cycle cropping systems. Soil cover is a crucial factor in preventing erosion. Cleaner water through reduced nutrient and soil surface runoff can be a further advantage of agroforestry. The runoff can be reduced by decreasing its velocity and increasing infiltration into the soil. Compared to row-cropped fields nutrient uptake can be higher and reduce nutrient loss into streams.Further advantages concerning plant growth:", "situation": "Jill owns a very large farm where she grows two types of crops. In Field C she grows corn in rows and there are no groundcover plants in the soil. In Field B she grows beans; the beans are not planted in rows and there is a layer of groundcover plants in the soil. She is curious about how the different styles of growing these crops will affect soil erosion.", "qas": [{"question": "Which field will produce less runoff, Field B or Field C?", "id": "1406893923", "answers": [{"text": "Field B"}]}]}, {"background": "Depleted soils can be protected from soil erosion by groundcover plants such as naturally growing grasses in agroforestry systems. These help to stabilise the soil as they increase cover compared to short-cycle cropping systems. Soil cover is a crucial factor in preventing erosion. Cleaner water through reduced nutrient and soil surface runoff can be a further advantage of agroforestry. The runoff can be reduced by decreasing its velocity and increasing infiltration into the soil. Compared to row-cropped fields nutrient uptake can be higher and reduce nutrient loss into streams.Further advantages concerning plant growth:", "situation": "Jill owns a very large farm where she grows two types of crops. In Field C she grows corn in rows and there are no groundcover plants in the soil. In Field B she grows beans; the beans are not planted in rows and there is a layer of groundcover plants in the soil. She is curious about how the different styles of growing these crops will affect soil erosion.", "qas": [{"question": "Which field will produce more runoff, Field B or Field C?", "id": "1400733535", "answers": [{"text": "Field C"}]}]}, {"background": "Bicarbonate ions are crucial for regulating blood pH. A person's breathing rate influences the level of CO2 in their blood. Breathing that is too slow or shallow causes respiratory acidosis, while breathing that is too rapid leads to hyperventilation, which can cause respiratory alkalosis.", "situation": "Barb and Sandra just finished running a marathon. The women used different breathing techniques while running: Barb took very slow, shallow breaths while Sandra took very rapid breaths. Neither woman was feeling very well after the race and went to the medical tent to get checked out.", "qas": [{"question": "Which woman likely has respiratory acidosis, Barb or Sandra?", "id": "3249006871", "answers": [{"text": "Barb"}]}]}, {"background": "Bicarbonate ions are crucial for regulating blood pH. A person's breathing rate influences the level of CO2 in their blood. Breathing that is too slow or shallow causes respiratory acidosis, while breathing that is too rapid leads to hyperventilation, which can cause respiratory alkalosis.", "situation": "Barb and Sandra just finished running a marathon. The women used different breathing techniques while running: Barb took very slow, shallow breaths while Sandra took very rapid breaths. Neither woman was feeling very well after the race and went to the medical tent to get checked out.", "qas": [{"question": "Which woman likely has respiratory alkalosis, Barb or Sandra?", "id": "2913462667", "answers": [{"text": "Sandra"}]}]}, {"background": "Bicarbonate ions are crucial for regulating blood pH. A person's breathing rate influences the level of CO2 in their blood. Breathing that is too slow or shallow causes respiratory acidosis, while breathing that is too rapid leads to hyperventilation, which can cause respiratory alkalosis.", "situation": "Barb and Sandra just finished running a marathon. The women used different breathing techniques while running: Barb took very slow, shallow breaths while Sandra took very rapid breaths. Neither woman was feeling very well after the race and went to the medical tent to get checked out.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Barb more or less likely than Sandra to have respiratory acidosis?", "id": "3705859154", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Bicarbonate ions are crucial for regulating blood pH. A person's breathing rate influences the level of CO2 in their blood. Breathing that is too slow or shallow causes respiratory acidosis, while breathing that is too rapid leads to hyperventilation, which can cause respiratory alkalosis.", "situation": "Barb and Sandra just finished running a marathon. The women used different breathing techniques while running: Barb took very slow, shallow breaths while Sandra took very rapid breaths. Neither woman was feeling very well after the race and went to the medical tent to get checked out.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Sandra more or less likely than Barb to have respiratory acidosis?", "id": "3790662738", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Bicarbonate ions are crucial for regulating blood pH. A person's breathing rate influences the level of CO2 in their blood. Breathing that is too slow or shallow causes respiratory acidosis, while breathing that is too rapid leads to hyperventilation, which can cause respiratory alkalosis.", "situation": "Barb and Sandra just finished running a marathon. The women used different breathing techniques while running: Barb took very slow, shallow breaths while Sandra took very rapid breaths. Neither woman was feeling very well after the race and went to the medical tent to get checked out.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Sandra more or less likely than Barb to have respiratory alkalosis?", "id": "3475565766", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Bicarbonate ions are crucial for regulating blood pH. A person's breathing rate influences the level of CO2 in their blood. Breathing that is too slow or shallow causes respiratory acidosis, while breathing that is too rapid leads to hyperventilation, which can cause respiratory alkalosis.", "situation": "Barb and Sandra just finished running a marathon. The women used different breathing techniques while running: Barb took very slow, shallow breaths while Sandra took very rapid breaths. Neither woman was feeling very well after the race and went to the medical tent to get checked out.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Barb more or less likely than Sandra to have respiratory alkalosis?", "id": "3390762182", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Another possible benefit of aggregation is to protect against predation by group anti-predator behavior. Many species exhibit higher rates of predator vigilance behavior per individual at lower density. This increased vigilance might result in less time and energy spent on foraging, thus reducing the fitness of an individual living in smaller groups. One striking example of such shared vigilance is exhibited by meerkats. Meanwhile, other species move in synchrony to confuse and avoid predators such as schools of sardines and flocks of starlings. The confusion effect that this herding behavior would have on predators will be more effective when more individuals are present.Cooperative feeding", "situation": "Camilla is interested in how smaller fish avoid larger predators. She has been observing two groups of fish: Group A travels together in the same direction in a coordination fashion. Group B also travels together, but each fish moves somewhat independently.", "qas": [{"question": "Which group is more likely to confuse and avoid predators, Group A or Group B?", "id": "2735374031", "answers": [{"text": "Group A"}]}]}, {"background": "Another possible benefit of aggregation is to protect against predation by group anti-predator behavior. Many species exhibit higher rates of predator vigilance behavior per individual at lower density. This increased vigilance might result in less time and energy spent on foraging, thus reducing the fitness of an individual living in smaller groups. One striking example of such shared vigilance is exhibited by meerkats. Meanwhile, other species move in synchrony to confuse and avoid predators such as schools of sardines and flocks of starlings. The confusion effect that this herding behavior would have on predators will be more effective when more individuals are present.Cooperative feeding", "situation": "Camilla is interested in how smaller fish avoid larger predators. She has been observing two groups of fish: Group A travels together in the same direction in a coordination fashion. Group B also travels together, but each fish moves somewhat independently.", "qas": [{"question": "Which group is least likely to confuse and avoid predators, Group A or Group B?", "id": "618102581", "answers": [{"text": "Group B"}]}]}, {"background": "Another possible benefit of aggregation is to protect against predation by group anti-predator behavior. Many species exhibit higher rates of predator vigilance behavior per individual at lower density. This increased vigilance might result in less time and energy spent on foraging, thus reducing the fitness of an individual living in smaller groups. One striking example of such shared vigilance is exhibited by meerkats. Meanwhile, other species move in synchrony to confuse and avoid predators such as schools of sardines and flocks of starlings. The confusion effect that this herding behavior would have on predators will be more effective when more individuals are present.Cooperative feeding", "situation": "Camilla is interested in how smaller fish avoid larger predators. She has been observing two groups of fish: Group A travels together in the same direction in a coordination fashion. Group B also travels together, but each fish moves somewhat independently.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Group A more or less likely than Group B to confuse and avoid predators?", "id": "4141710789", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Another possible benefit of aggregation is to protect against predation by group anti-predator behavior. Many species exhibit higher rates of predator vigilance behavior per individual at lower density. This increased vigilance might result in less time and energy spent on foraging, thus reducing the fitness of an individual living in smaller groups. One striking example of such shared vigilance is exhibited by meerkats. Meanwhile, other species move in synchrony to confuse and avoid predators such as schools of sardines and flocks of starlings. The confusion effect that this herding behavior would have on predators will be more effective when more individuals are present.Cooperative feeding", "situation": "Camilla is interested in how smaller fish avoid larger predators. She has been observing two groups of fish: Group A travels together in the same direction in a coordination fashion. Group B also travels together, but each fish moves somewhat independently.", "qas": [{"question": "Is Group B more or less likely than Group A to confuse and avoid predators?", "id": "4143873477", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Mammals have a heart that is about 0.6% of the total body mass across the board from a small mouse to a large Blue Whale. It can be expressed as: Heart Weight = 0.006Mb1.0, where Mb is the body mass of the individual. Lung volume is also directly related to body mass in mammals (slope = 1.02). The lung has a volume of 63 ml for every kg of body mass. In addition, the tidal volume at rest in an individual is 1/10 the lung volume. Also respiration costs with respect to oxygen consumption is scaled in the order of Mb.75. This shows that mammals, regardless of size, have the same size respiratory and cardiovascular systems and it turn have the same amount of blood: About 5.5% of body mass. This means that for a similarly designed marine mammals, the larger the individual the more efficiently they can travel compared to a smaller individual. It takes the same effort to move one body length whether the individual is one meter or ten meters. This can explain why large whales can migrate far distance in the oceans and not stop for rest. It is metabolically less expensive to be larger in body size. This goes for terrestrial and flying animals as well. In fact, for an organism to move any distance, regardless of type from elephants to centipedes, smaller animals consume more oxygen per unit body mass than larger ones. This metabolic advantage that larger animals have makes it possible for larger marine mammals to dive for longer durations of time than their smaller counterparts. That the heart rate is lower means that larger animals can carry more blood, which carries more oxygen. Then in conjuncture with the fact that mammals reparation costs scales in the order of Mb.75 shows how an advantage can be had in having a larger body mass. More simply, a larger whale can hold more oxygen and at the same time demand less metabolically than a smaller whale.", "situation": "Shawn is curious as to how body mass affects animals of different sizes in regards to metabolism, oxygen consumption, and heart rate. To do this, he is studying two different animals of very different sizes. Animal A is extremely large, and Animal B is extremely small.", "qas": [{"question": "Which animal will be able to travel a longer distance without resting, Animal A or Animal B?", "id": "3205963946", "answers": [{"text": "Animal A"}]}]}, {"background": "Mammals have a heart that is about 0.6% of the total body mass across the board from a small mouse to a large Blue Whale. It can be expressed as: Heart Weight = 0.006Mb1.0, where Mb is the body mass of the individual. Lung volume is also directly related to body mass in mammals (slope = 1.02). The lung has a volume of 63 ml for every kg of body mass. In addition, the tidal volume at rest in an individual is 1/10 the lung volume. Also respiration costs with respect to oxygen consumption is scaled in the order of Mb.75. This shows that mammals, regardless of size, have the same size respiratory and cardiovascular systems and it turn have the same amount of blood: About 5.5% of body mass. This means that for a similarly designed marine mammals, the larger the individual the more efficiently they can travel compared to a smaller individual. It takes the same effort to move one body length whether the individual is one meter or ten meters. This can explain why large whales can migrate far distance in the oceans and not stop for rest. It is metabolically less expensive to be larger in body size. This goes for terrestrial and flying animals as well. In fact, for an organism to move any distance, regardless of type from elephants to centipedes, smaller animals consume more oxygen per unit body mass than larger ones. This metabolic advantage that larger animals have makes it possible for larger marine mammals to dive for longer durations of time than their smaller counterparts. That the heart rate is lower means that larger animals can carry more blood, which carries more oxygen. Then in conjuncture with the fact that mammals reparation costs scales in the order of Mb.75 shows how an advantage can be had in having a larger body mass. More simply, a larger whale can hold more oxygen and at the same time demand less metabolically than a smaller whale.", "situation": "Shawn is curious as to how body mass affects animals of different sizes in regards to metabolism, oxygen consumption, and heart rate. To do this, he is studying two different animals of very different sizes. Animal A is extremely large, and Animal B is extremely small.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Animal A or Animal B be able to travel a longer distance without stopping for rest?", "id": "4248313718", "answers": [{"text": "Animal A"}]}]}, {"background": "Mammals have a heart that is about 0.6% of the total body mass across the board from a small mouse to a large Blue Whale. It can be expressed as: Heart Weight = 0.006Mb1.0, where Mb is the body mass of the individual. Lung volume is also directly related to body mass in mammals (slope = 1.02). The lung has a volume of 63 ml for every kg of body mass. In addition, the tidal volume at rest in an individual is 1/10 the lung volume. Also respiration costs with respect to oxygen consumption is scaled in the order of Mb.75. This shows that mammals, regardless of size, have the same size respiratory and cardiovascular systems and it turn have the same amount of blood: About 5.5% of body mass. This means that for a similarly designed marine mammals, the larger the individual the more efficiently they can travel compared to a smaller individual. It takes the same effort to move one body length whether the individual is one meter or ten meters. This can explain why large whales can migrate far distance in the oceans and not stop for rest. It is metabolically less expensive to be larger in body size. This goes for terrestrial and flying animals as well. In fact, for an organism to move any distance, regardless of type from elephants to centipedes, smaller animals consume more oxygen per unit body mass than larger ones. This metabolic advantage that larger animals have makes it possible for larger marine mammals to dive for longer durations of time than their smaller counterparts. That the heart rate is lower means that larger animals can carry more blood, which carries more oxygen. Then in conjuncture with the fact that mammals reparation costs scales in the order of Mb.75 shows how an advantage can be had in having a larger body mass. More simply, a larger whale can hold more oxygen and at the same time demand less metabolically than a smaller whale.", "situation": "Shawn is curious as to how body mass affects animals of different sizes in regards to metabolism, oxygen consumption, and heart rate. To do this, he is studying two different animals of very different sizes. Animal A is extremely large, and Animal B is extremely small.", "qas": [{"question": "Which animal will travel a shorter distance before needing to stop for rest, Animal A or Animal B?", "id": "2868781815", "answers": [{"text": "Animal B"}]}]}, {"background": "Mammals have a heart that is about 0.6% of the total body mass across the board from a small mouse to a large Blue Whale. It can be expressed as: Heart Weight = 0.006Mb1.0, where Mb is the body mass of the individual. Lung volume is also directly related to body mass in mammals (slope = 1.02). The lung has a volume of 63 ml for every kg of body mass. In addition, the tidal volume at rest in an individual is 1/10 the lung volume. Also respiration costs with respect to oxygen consumption is scaled in the order of Mb.75. This shows that mammals, regardless of size, have the same size respiratory and cardiovascular systems and it turn have the same amount of blood: About 5.5% of body mass. This means that for a similarly designed marine mammals, the larger the individual the more efficiently they can travel compared to a smaller individual. It takes the same effort to move one body length whether the individual is one meter or ten meters. This can explain why large whales can migrate far distance in the oceans and not stop for rest. It is metabolically less expensive to be larger in body size. This goes for terrestrial and flying animals as well. In fact, for an organism to move any distance, regardless of type from elephants to centipedes, smaller animals consume more oxygen per unit body mass than larger ones. This metabolic advantage that larger animals have makes it possible for larger marine mammals to dive for longer durations of time than their smaller counterparts. That the heart rate is lower means that larger animals can carry more blood, which carries more oxygen. Then in conjuncture with the fact that mammals reparation costs scales in the order of Mb.75 shows how an advantage can be had in having a larger body mass. More simply, a larger whale can hold more oxygen and at the same time demand less metabolically than a smaller whale.", "situation": "Shawn is curious as to how body mass affects animals of different sizes in regards to metabolism, oxygen consumption, and heart rate. To do this, he is studying two different animals of very different sizes. Animal A is extremely large, and Animal B is extremely small.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Animal A be able to travel a longer or shorter distance before needing to rest than Animal B?", "id": "1727734473", "answers": [{"text": "longer"}]}]}, {"background": "Mammals have a heart that is about 0.6% of the total body mass across the board from a small mouse to a large Blue Whale. It can be expressed as: Heart Weight = 0.006Mb1.0, where Mb is the body mass of the individual. Lung volume is also directly related to body mass in mammals (slope = 1.02). The lung has a volume of 63 ml for every kg of body mass. In addition, the tidal volume at rest in an individual is 1/10 the lung volume. Also respiration costs with respect to oxygen consumption is scaled in the order of Mb.75. This shows that mammals, regardless of size, have the same size respiratory and cardiovascular systems and it turn have the same amount of blood: About 5.5% of body mass. This means that for a similarly designed marine mammals, the larger the individual the more efficiently they can travel compared to a smaller individual. It takes the same effort to move one body length whether the individual is one meter or ten meters. This can explain why large whales can migrate far distance in the oceans and not stop for rest. It is metabolically less expensive to be larger in body size. This goes for terrestrial and flying animals as well. In fact, for an organism to move any distance, regardless of type from elephants to centipedes, smaller animals consume more oxygen per unit body mass than larger ones. This metabolic advantage that larger animals have makes it possible for larger marine mammals to dive for longer durations of time than their smaller counterparts. That the heart rate is lower means that larger animals can carry more blood, which carries more oxygen. Then in conjuncture with the fact that mammals reparation costs scales in the order of Mb.75 shows how an advantage can be had in having a larger body mass. More simply, a larger whale can hold more oxygen and at the same time demand less metabolically than a smaller whale.", "situation": "Shawn is curious as to how body mass affects animals of different sizes in regards to metabolism, oxygen consumption, and heart rate. To do this, he is studying two different animals of very different sizes. Animal A is extremely large, and Animal B is extremely small.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Animal B be able to travel a longer or shorter distance before needing to rest than Animal A?", "id": "1733239497", "answers": [{"text": "shorter"}]}]}, {"background": "Mammals have a heart that is about 0.6% of the total body mass across the board from a small mouse to a large Blue Whale. It can be expressed as: Heart Weight = 0.006Mb1.0, where Mb is the body mass of the individual. Lung volume is also directly related to body mass in mammals (slope = 1.02). The lung has a volume of 63 ml for every kg of body mass. In addition, the tidal volume at rest in an individual is 1/10 the lung volume. Also respiration costs with respect to oxygen consumption is scaled in the order of Mb.75. This shows that mammals, regardless of size, have the same size respiratory and cardiovascular systems and it turn have the same amount of blood: About 5.5% of body mass. This means that for a similarly designed marine mammals, the larger the individual the more efficiently they can travel compared to a smaller individual. It takes the same effort to move one body length whether the individual is one meter or ten meters. This can explain why large whales can migrate far distance in the oceans and not stop for rest. It is metabolically less expensive to be larger in body size. This goes for terrestrial and flying animals as well. In fact, for an organism to move any distance, regardless of type from elephants to centipedes, smaller animals consume more oxygen per unit body mass than larger ones. This metabolic advantage that larger animals have makes it possible for larger marine mammals to dive for longer durations of time than their smaller counterparts. That the heart rate is lower means that larger animals can carry more blood, which carries more oxygen. Then in conjuncture with the fact that mammals reparation costs scales in the order of Mb.75 shows how an advantage can be had in having a larger body mass. More simply, a larger whale can hold more oxygen and at the same time demand less metabolically than a smaller whale.", "situation": "Shawn is curious as to how body mass affects animals of different sizes in regards to metabolism, oxygen consumption, and heart rate. To do this, he is studying two different animals of very different sizes. Animal A is extremely large, and Animal B is extremely small.", "qas": [{"question": "Which animal consumes more oxygen, Animal A or Animal B?", "id": "4267905981", "answers": [{"text": "Animal B"}]}]}, {"background": "Mammals have a heart that is about 0.6% of the total body mass across the board from a small mouse to a large Blue Whale. It can be expressed as: Heart Weight = 0.006Mb1.0, where Mb is the body mass of the individual. Lung volume is also directly related to body mass in mammals (slope = 1.02). The lung has a volume of 63 ml for every kg of body mass. In addition, the tidal volume at rest in an individual is 1/10 the lung volume. Also respiration costs with respect to oxygen consumption is scaled in the order of Mb.75. This shows that mammals, regardless of size, have the same size respiratory and cardiovascular systems and it turn have the same amount of blood: About 5.5% of body mass. This means that for a similarly designed marine mammals, the larger the individual the more efficiently they can travel compared to a smaller individual. It takes the same effort to move one body length whether the individual is one meter or ten meters. This can explain why large whales can migrate far distance in the oceans and not stop for rest. It is metabolically less expensive to be larger in body size. This goes for terrestrial and flying animals as well. In fact, for an organism to move any distance, regardless of type from elephants to centipedes, smaller animals consume more oxygen per unit body mass than larger ones. This metabolic advantage that larger animals have makes it possible for larger marine mammals to dive for longer durations of time than their smaller counterparts. That the heart rate is lower means that larger animals can carry more blood, which carries more oxygen. Then in conjuncture with the fact that mammals reparation costs scales in the order of Mb.75 shows how an advantage can be had in having a larger body mass. More simply, a larger whale can hold more oxygen and at the same time demand less metabolically than a smaller whale.", "situation": "Shawn is curious as to how body mass affects animals of different sizes in regards to metabolism, oxygen consumption, and heart rate. To do this, he is studying two different animals of very different sizes. Animal A is extremely large, and Animal B is extremely small.", "qas": [{"question": "Which animal consumes less oxygen, Animal A or Animal B?", "id": "4274590657", "answers": [{"text": "Animal A"}]}]}, {"background": "Mammals have a heart that is about 0.6% of the total body mass across the board from a small mouse to a large Blue Whale. It can be expressed as: Heart Weight = 0.006Mb1.0, where Mb is the body mass of the individual. Lung volume is also directly related to body mass in mammals (slope = 1.02). The lung has a volume of 63 ml for every kg of body mass. In addition, the tidal volume at rest in an individual is 1/10 the lung volume. Also respiration costs with respect to oxygen consumption is scaled in the order of Mb.75. This shows that mammals, regardless of size, have the same size respiratory and cardiovascular systems and it turn have the same amount of blood: About 5.5% of body mass. This means that for a similarly designed marine mammals, the larger the individual the more efficiently they can travel compared to a smaller individual. It takes the same effort to move one body length whether the individual is one meter or ten meters. This can explain why large whales can migrate far distance in the oceans and not stop for rest. It is metabolically less expensive to be larger in body size. This goes for terrestrial and flying animals as well. In fact, for an organism to move any distance, regardless of type from elephants to centipedes, smaller animals consume more oxygen per unit body mass than larger ones. This metabolic advantage that larger animals have makes it possible for larger marine mammals to dive for longer durations of time than their smaller counterparts. That the heart rate is lower means that larger animals can carry more blood, which carries more oxygen. Then in conjuncture with the fact that mammals reparation costs scales in the order of Mb.75 shows how an advantage can be had in having a larger body mass. More simply, a larger whale can hold more oxygen and at the same time demand less metabolically than a smaller whale.", "situation": "Shawn is curious as to how body mass affects animals of different sizes in regards to metabolism, oxygen consumption, and heart rate. To do this, he is studying two different animals of very different sizes. Animal A is extremely large, and Animal B is extremely small.", "qas": [{"question": "Does Animal A consume more or less oxygen than Animal B?", "id": "3949990854", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Mammals have a heart that is about 0.6% of the total body mass across the board from a small mouse to a large Blue Whale. It can be expressed as: Heart Weight = 0.006Mb1.0, where Mb is the body mass of the individual. Lung volume is also directly related to body mass in mammals (slope = 1.02). The lung has a volume of 63 ml for every kg of body mass. In addition, the tidal volume at rest in an individual is 1/10 the lung volume. Also respiration costs with respect to oxygen consumption is scaled in the order of Mb.75. This shows that mammals, regardless of size, have the same size respiratory and cardiovascular systems and it turn have the same amount of blood: About 5.5% of body mass. This means that for a similarly designed marine mammals, the larger the individual the more efficiently they can travel compared to a smaller individual. It takes the same effort to move one body length whether the individual is one meter or ten meters. This can explain why large whales can migrate far distance in the oceans and not stop for rest. It is metabolically less expensive to be larger in body size. This goes for terrestrial and flying animals as well. In fact, for an organism to move any distance, regardless of type from elephants to centipedes, smaller animals consume more oxygen per unit body mass than larger ones. This metabolic advantage that larger animals have makes it possible for larger marine mammals to dive for longer durations of time than their smaller counterparts. That the heart rate is lower means that larger animals can carry more blood, which carries more oxygen. Then in conjuncture with the fact that mammals reparation costs scales in the order of Mb.75 shows how an advantage can be had in having a larger body mass. More simply, a larger whale can hold more oxygen and at the same time demand less metabolically than a smaller whale.", "situation": "Shawn is curious as to how body mass affects animals of different sizes in regards to metabolism, oxygen consumption, and heart rate. To do this, he is studying two different animals of very different sizes. Animal A is extremely large, and Animal B is extremely small.", "qas": [{"question": "Does Animal B consume more or less oxygen than Animal A?", "id": "3952743366", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Mammals have a heart that is about 0.6% of the total body mass across the board from a small mouse to a large Blue Whale. It can be expressed as: Heart Weight = 0.006Mb1.0, where Mb is the body mass of the individual. Lung volume is also directly related to body mass in mammals (slope = 1.02). The lung has a volume of 63 ml for every kg of body mass. In addition, the tidal volume at rest in an individual is 1/10 the lung volume. Also respiration costs with respect to oxygen consumption is scaled in the order of Mb.75. This shows that mammals, regardless of size, have the same size respiratory and cardiovascular systems and it turn have the same amount of blood: About 5.5% of body mass. This means that for a similarly designed marine mammals, the larger the individual the more efficiently they can travel compared to a smaller individual. It takes the same effort to move one body length whether the individual is one meter or ten meters. This can explain why large whales can migrate far distance in the oceans and not stop for rest. It is metabolically less expensive to be larger in body size. This goes for terrestrial and flying animals as well. In fact, for an organism to move any distance, regardless of type from elephants to centipedes, smaller animals consume more oxygen per unit body mass than larger ones. This metabolic advantage that larger animals have makes it possible for larger marine mammals to dive for longer durations of time than their smaller counterparts. That the heart rate is lower means that larger animals can carry more blood, which carries more oxygen. Then in conjuncture with the fact that mammals reparation costs scales in the order of Mb.75 shows how an advantage can be had in having a larger body mass. More simply, a larger whale can hold more oxygen and at the same time demand less metabolically than a smaller whale.", "situation": "Shawn is curious as to how body mass affects animals of different sizes in regards to metabolism, oxygen consumption, and heart rate. To do this, he is studying two different animals of very different sizes. Animal A is extremely large, and Animal B is extremely small.", "qas": [{"question": "Which animal has a lower heart rate, Animal A or Animal B?", "id": "248386505", "answers": [{"text": "Animal A"}]}]}, {"background": "Mammals have a heart that is about 0.6% of the total body mass across the board from a small mouse to a large Blue Whale. It can be expressed as: Heart Weight = 0.006Mb1.0, where Mb is the body mass of the individual. Lung volume is also directly related to body mass in mammals (slope = 1.02). The lung has a volume of 63 ml for every kg of body mass. In addition, the tidal volume at rest in an individual is 1/10 the lung volume. Also respiration costs with respect to oxygen consumption is scaled in the order of Mb.75. This shows that mammals, regardless of size, have the same size respiratory and cardiovascular systems and it turn have the same amount of blood: About 5.5% of body mass. This means that for a similarly designed marine mammals, the larger the individual the more efficiently they can travel compared to a smaller individual. It takes the same effort to move one body length whether the individual is one meter or ten meters. This can explain why large whales can migrate far distance in the oceans and not stop for rest. It is metabolically less expensive to be larger in body size. This goes for terrestrial and flying animals as well. In fact, for an organism to move any distance, regardless of type from elephants to centipedes, smaller animals consume more oxygen per unit body mass than larger ones. This metabolic advantage that larger animals have makes it possible for larger marine mammals to dive for longer durations of time than their smaller counterparts. That the heart rate is lower means that larger animals can carry more blood, which carries more oxygen. Then in conjuncture with the fact that mammals reparation costs scales in the order of Mb.75 shows how an advantage can be had in having a larger body mass. More simply, a larger whale can hold more oxygen and at the same time demand less metabolically than a smaller whale.", "situation": "Shawn is curious as to how body mass affects animals of different sizes in regards to metabolism, oxygen consumption, and heart rate. To do this, he is studying two different animals of very different sizes. Animal A is extremely large, and Animal B is extremely small.", "qas": [{"question": "Which animal has a higher heart rate, Animal A or Animal B?", "id": "566957079", "answers": [{"text": "Animal B"}]}]}, {"background": "On Earth, the solar radiation varies with the angle of the Sun above the horizon, with longer sunlight duration at high latitudes during summer, varying to no sunlight at all in winter near the pertinent pole. When the direct radiation is not blocked by clouds, it is experienced as sunshine. The warming of the ground (and other objects) depends on the absorption of the electromagnetic radiation in the form of heat.", "situation": "William was traveling in a boat on the Pacific Ocean in the Northern Hemisphere during the summer and got lost at sea when his boat malfunctioned. None of his navigational equipment works and William isn't quite sure where he is or in what direction he is heading. William is trying to determine whether he is moving north or south based on the length of sunlight duration. On Day 1, William recorded 13 hours of sunlight and on Day 45, William recorded 9 hours of sunlight.", "qas": [{"question": "Is it more or less likely that William is moving north?", "id": "3175700129", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "On Earth, the solar radiation varies with the angle of the Sun above the horizon, with longer sunlight duration at high latitudes during summer, varying to no sunlight at all in winter near the pertinent pole. When the direct radiation is not blocked by clouds, it is experienced as sunshine. The warming of the ground (and other objects) depends on the absorption of the electromagnetic radiation in the form of heat.", "situation": "William was traveling in a boat on the Pacific Ocean in the Northern Hemisphere during the summer and got lost at sea when his boat malfunctioned. None of his navigational equipment works and William isn't quite sure where he is or in what direction he is heading. William is trying to determine whether he is moving north or south based on the length of sunlight duration. On Day 1, William recorded 13 hours of sunlight and on Day 45, William recorded 9 hours of sunlight.", "qas": [{"question": "Is it more or less likely that William is moving south?", "id": "3178452649", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "On Earth, the solar radiation varies with the angle of the Sun above the horizon, with longer sunlight duration at high latitudes during summer, varying to no sunlight at all in winter near the pertinent pole. When the direct radiation is not blocked by clouds, it is experienced as sunshine. The warming of the ground (and other objects) depends on the absorption of the electromagnetic radiation in the form of heat.", "situation": "William was traveling in a boat on the Pacific Ocean in the Northern Hemisphere during the summer and got lost at sea when his boat malfunctioned. None of his navigational equipment works and William isn't quite sure where he is or in what direction he is heading. William is trying to determine whether he is moving north or south based on the length of sunlight duration. On Day 1, William recorded 13 hours of sunlight and on Day 45, William recorded 9 hours of sunlight.", "qas": [{"question": "If William continues to move in the same direction, will he recorded more or less sunlight on Day 60?", "id": "3688588958", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "On Earth, the solar radiation varies with the angle of the Sun above the horizon, with longer sunlight duration at high latitudes during summer, varying to no sunlight at all in winter near the pertinent pole. When the direct radiation is not blocked by clouds, it is experienced as sunshine. The warming of the ground (and other objects) depends on the absorption of the electromagnetic radiation in the form of heat.", "situation": "William was traveling in a boat on the Pacific Ocean in the Northern Hemisphere during the summer and got lost at sea when his boat malfunctioned. None of his navigational equipment works and William isn't quite sure where he is or in what direction he is heading. William is trying to determine whether he is moving north or south based on the length of sunlight duration. On Day 1, William recorded 13 hours of sunlight and on Day 45, William recorded 9 hours of sunlight.", "qas": [{"question": "Is it more likely that William is moving north or south?", "id": "429479709", "answers": [{"text": "south"}]}]}, {"background": "On Earth, the solar radiation varies with the angle of the Sun above the horizon, with longer sunlight duration at high latitudes during summer, varying to no sunlight at all in winter near the pertinent pole. When the direct radiation is not blocked by clouds, it is experienced as sunshine. The warming of the ground (and other objects) depends on the absorption of the electromagnetic radiation in the form of heat.", "situation": "William was traveling in a boat on the Pacific Ocean in the Northern Hemisphere during the summer and got lost at sea when his boat malfunctioned. None of his navigational equipment works and William isn't quite sure where he is or in what direction he is heading. William is trying to determine whether he is moving north or south based on the length of sunlight duration. On Day 1, William recorded 13 hours of sunlight and on Day 45, William recorded 9 hours of sunlight.", "qas": [{"question": "Is it least likely that William is moving north or south?", "id": "1917212547", "answers": [{"text": "North"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, there is an increase in biodiversity from the poles to the tropics. Thus localities at lower latitudes have more species than localities at higher latitudes. This is often referred to as the latitudinal gradient in species diversity. Several ecological factors may contribute to the gradient, but the ultimate factor behind many of them is the greater mean temperature at the equator compared to that of the poles.Even though terrestrial biodiversity declines from the equator to the poles, some studies claim that this characteristic is unverified in aquatic ecosystems, especially in marine ecosystems. The latitudinal distribution of parasites does not appear to follow this rule.In 2016, an alternative hypothesis (\"the fractal biodiversity\") was proposed to explain the biodiversity latitudinal gradient. In this study, the species pool size and the fractal nature of ecosystems were combined to clarify some general patterns of this gradient. This hypothesis considers temperature, moisture, and net primary production (NPP) as the main variables of an ecosystem niche and as the axis of the ecological hypervolume. In this way, it is possible to build fractal hypervolumes, whose fractal dimension rises up to three moving towards the equator.", "situation": "Sasha is studying the biodiversity of two ecosystems located in different regions of the world. Ecosystem A is located in North America, and Ecosystem B is located in South America.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Ecosystem A be more or less diverse than Ecosystem B?", "id": "509290873", "answers": [{"text": "less"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, there is an increase in biodiversity from the poles to the tropics. Thus localities at lower latitudes have more species than localities at higher latitudes. This is often referred to as the latitudinal gradient in species diversity. Several ecological factors may contribute to the gradient, but the ultimate factor behind many of them is the greater mean temperature at the equator compared to that of the poles.Even though terrestrial biodiversity declines from the equator to the poles, some studies claim that this characteristic is unverified in aquatic ecosystems, especially in marine ecosystems. The latitudinal distribution of parasites does not appear to follow this rule.In 2016, an alternative hypothesis (\"the fractal biodiversity\") was proposed to explain the biodiversity latitudinal gradient. In this study, the species pool size and the fractal nature of ecosystems were combined to clarify some general patterns of this gradient. This hypothesis considers temperature, moisture, and net primary production (NPP) as the main variables of an ecosystem niche and as the axis of the ecological hypervolume. In this way, it is possible to build fractal hypervolumes, whose fractal dimension rises up to three moving towards the equator.", "situation": "Sasha is studying the biodiversity of two ecosystems located in different regions of the world. Ecosystem A is located in North America, and Ecosystem B is located in South America.", "qas": [{"question": "Will Ecosystem B be more or less diverse than Ecosystem A?", "id": "511977849", "answers": [{"text": "more"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, there is an increase in biodiversity from the poles to the tropics. Thus localities at lower latitudes have more species than localities at higher latitudes. This is often referred to as the latitudinal gradient in species diversity. Several ecological factors may contribute to the gradient, but the ultimate factor behind many of them is the greater mean temperature at the equator compared to that of the poles.Even though terrestrial biodiversity declines from the equator to the poles, some studies claim that this characteristic is unverified in aquatic ecosystems, especially in marine ecosystems. The latitudinal distribution of parasites does not appear to follow this rule.In 2016, an alternative hypothesis (\"the fractal biodiversity\") was proposed to explain the biodiversity latitudinal gradient. In this study, the species pool size and the fractal nature of ecosystems were combined to clarify some general patterns of this gradient. This hypothesis considers temperature, moisture, and net primary production (NPP) as the main variables of an ecosystem niche and as the axis of the ecological hypervolume. In this way, it is possible to build fractal hypervolumes, whose fractal dimension rises up to three moving towards the equator.", "situation": "Sasha is studying the biodiversity of two ecosystems located in different regions of the world. Ecosystem A is located in North America, and Ecosystem B is located in South America.", "qas": [{"question": "Which ecosystem will be more diverse, Ecosystem A or Ecosystem B?", "id": "1637166130", "answers": [{"text": "Ecosystem B"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, there is an increase in biodiversity from the poles to the tropics. Thus localities at lower latitudes have more species than localities at higher latitudes. This is often referred to as the latitudinal gradient in species diversity. Several ecological factors may contribute to the gradient, but the ultimate factor behind many of them is the greater mean temperature at the equator compared to that of the poles.Even though terrestrial biodiversity declines from the equator to the poles, some studies claim that this characteristic is unverified in aquatic ecosystems, especially in marine ecosystems. The latitudinal distribution of parasites does not appear to follow this rule.In 2016, an alternative hypothesis (\"the fractal biodiversity\") was proposed to explain the biodiversity latitudinal gradient. In this study, the species pool size and the fractal nature of ecosystems were combined to clarify some general patterns of this gradient. This hypothesis considers temperature, moisture, and net primary production (NPP) as the main variables of an ecosystem niche and as the axis of the ecological hypervolume. In this way, it is possible to build fractal hypervolumes, whose fractal dimension rises up to three moving towards the equator.", "situation": "Sasha is studying the biodiversity of two ecosystems located in different regions of the world. Ecosystem A is located in North America, and Ecosystem B is located in South America.", "qas": [{"question": "Which ecosystem will be less diverse, Ecosystem A or Ecosystem B?", "id": "1645685814", "answers": [{"text": "Ecosystem A"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, there is an increase in biodiversity from the poles to the tropics. Thus localities at lower latitudes have more species than localities at higher latitudes. This is often referred to as the latitudinal gradient in species diversity. Several ecological factors may contribute to the gradient, but the ultimate factor behind many of them is the greater mean temperature at the equator compared to that of the poles.Even though terrestrial biodiversity declines from the equator to the poles, some studies claim that this characteristic is unverified in aquatic ecosystems, especially in marine ecosystems. The latitudinal distribution of parasites does not appear to follow this rule.In 2016, an alternative hypothesis (\"the fractal biodiversity\") was proposed to explain the biodiversity latitudinal gradient. In this study, the species pool size and the fractal nature of ecosystems were combined to clarify some general patterns of this gradient. This hypothesis considers temperature, moisture, and net primary production (NPP) as the main variables of an ecosystem niche and as the axis of the ecological hypervolume. In this way, it is possible to build fractal hypervolumes, whose fractal dimension rises up to three moving towards the equator.", "situation": "Sasha is studying the biodiversity of two ecosystems located in different regions of the world. Ecosystem A is located in North America, and Ecosystem B is located in South America.", "qas": [{"question": "Which ecosystem will contain more species, Ecosystem A or Ecosystem B?", "id": "1420766801", "answers": [{"text": "Ecosystem B"}]}]}, {"background": "Generally, there is an increase in biodiversity from the poles to the tropics. Thus localities at lower latitudes have more species than localities at higher latitudes. This is often referred to as the latitudinal gradient in species diversity. Several ecological factors may contribute to the gradient, but the ultimate factor behind many of them is the greater mean temperature at the equator compared to that of the poles.Even though terrestrial biodiversity declines from the equator to the poles, some studies claim that this characteristic is unverified in aquatic ecosystems, especially in marine ecosystems. The latitudinal distribution of parasites does not appear to follow this rule.In 2016, an alternative hypothesis (\"the fractal biodiversity\") was proposed to explain the biodiversity latitudinal gradient. In this study, the species pool size and the fractal nature of ecosystems were combined to clarify some general patterns of this gradient. This hypothesis considers temperature, moisture, and net primary production (NPP) as the main variables of an ecosystem niche and as the axis of the ecological hypervolume. In this way, it is possible to build fractal hypervolumes, whose fractal dimension rises up to three moving towards the equator.", "situation": "Sasha is studying the biodiversity of two ecosystems located in different regions of the world. Ecosystem A is located in North America, and Ecosystem B is located in South America.", "qas": [{"question": "Which ecosystem will contain fewer species, Ecosystem A or Ecosystem B?", "id": "2231447223", "answers": [{"text": "Ecosystem A"}]}]}]}]}